Easy easy banzai Easy easy banzai
Easy easy banzai Human
Wanna get them mad? Get them mad?
Get them mad? People
What's up? Full of causes for concern
Crime won't disappear Forever
(play a trick on resentment Who's down?)
What's up? Full of causes for concern
Crime won't disappear Forever
Hey Hey! A hymn to humanity
Love has gone People, are you worried?
Hey Hey! Subservient People! !
WHAT'S UP, PEOPLE?! !
Are you worried?
L, I want to meet you.
Daikoku Wharf...
An abandoned warehouse
nicknamed the Yellow Box.
On the 28th. How about 1 PM?
That's fine.
Take off everything you're wearing
and put it in there.
I'll give you a blanket.
Miss Takada, are you all right?!
Light, I did as you said...
I made survival my first priority. ..
and did it.
Come quickly. . .help me...
Kiyomi Takada.
January 26, 2013, 2:32 PM.
Burns to death by setting fire
to everything around her
including the things she wrote on.
We are sad to announce...
The Special Police has confirmed
in their autopsy report...
that one of the bodies recovered at
the crime scene
was that of anchor, Kiyomi Takada.
A two-ton truck and a motorcycle
were found in the burnt-down church.
Officials suspect a gasoline fire.
I'm wondering who's going to be
Kira's next spokesman?
Kira's voice should continue to
be broadcast to the world.
It is very unfortunate that
Anchon/voman Takada passed away, but...
I cannot help but sa y that
with that kind of carelessness- . .
she lacked a full appreciation for
her position as Kira's representative.
A woman is not suited
for this role.
Kira, make me your representative.
KIRA'S KINGDOM
This is horrible...
Yeah...
As soon as they announced
that Takada was found dead...
every station has been debating over
who should be Kira's next spokesman...
The killings last night
were carried out.
This means that Takada and
Mikami had cell phone contact...
Nothing to worry about.
It's Near!
- L...
- Yes?
Sorry to interrupt, but...
we 're still going to meet...
On the 28th at 1 PM.
Is that still all right?
Yes.
There's no change...
just as I thought.
There's no mistake...
So, the day after tomorrow,
on the 28th...
Yes...
The day after tomorrow, huh?
Isn't it getting exciting?
Yeah... I don't know what Near
wants to show us, but...
Matsuda. .. Ide. ..
We might all die. . .on that day.
Do you understand?
- Gevanni.
- Yes.
Will you make it in time?
Yes. It's not a problem.
Commander Rester. ..
Lidner. .. Gevanni...
Let's do our best.
JANUARY 28, 2013
Good morning, everyone.
G-Good morning...
First off...
We've released Amane.
Call her for confirmation.
I don't know why, but I'm in
a deluxe suite at the Teito Hotel...
Probably as some sort
of compensation...
It feels great!
I see. All right.
Please stay there for a little longer.
Okay!
Near, please get me Mogi.
In order to bring the notebook
we have here,
We need PIN numbers
from each of us...
All right. I'll connect you to him.
This is Mogi.
The number is 62-324.
All that's left is my number...
The Killer Notebook...
How to use it...
The human whose name is
written in this notebook shall die.
This note will not take effect
unless the writer has the person's face
in their mind when writing his/her name.
Therefore, people sharing
the same name will not be affected.
If the cause of death is written...
within 40 seconds of writing
the person's name, it will happen.
If the cause of death
is not specified,
the person will simply die
of a heart attack.
After writing the cause of death,
details of the death should be written
in the next 6 minutes and 40 seconds...
Near. I've got our notebook here.
I'll be bringing it with me.
Is it all right if Mr. Aizawa
carries it, L?
Near. My only concern is whether
you think that Aizawa
is the best one for this task.
Thank you very much.
We'll see you at the meeting place.
It's all going to end...
no, today is just the beginning.
The perfect world of Kira...
Everyone who knows about
the existence of the notebook...
...Will die!
Near is inside.
There's no mistake.
Well then, let's go.
Near... You're far inferior to L...
You have no right to
wear a mask of L.
L... Those four are the SPK...
Near is the one wearing the mask.
Wait, I have a problem with this.
I don't care who he accuses
of being Kira...
but that mask proves that
he's only trying to protect himsel
This is just for insurance.
There is a chance that everyone's face,
except mine, has been seen by Kira.
Kira might have written down
their names already.
So, for an hour...no, half an hour,
I want to see if anyone
falls under Kira's control or dies.
W-What?
He's waiting to see if we die?
He's right...
It's not impossible if Light is Kira.
Especially now,
since we 're expendable...
This is just a front...
to buy some time. . .Near...
I never thought it would be so hard
to keep myself from laughing.
Near's probably waiting
for him t0 come.
I've already predicted that.
Near! It's been over thirty minutes.
Nothing's happened.
Of course.
It's because Kira isn't here.
Fine. Everyone seems safe.
I'll remove my mask.
What's wrong, Near?
Are you still waiting for something?
Waiting... That's right.
I am waiting. . .for the one who
will solve everything, to arrive.
"The one who will
solve everything?"
He'll come soon.
So we must wait.
This building is completely sealed.
You can't see inside without
opening that door.
He'll come through that door...
or at least peek through it...
Who's going to come?
X-Kira. He's the one who is
currently killing in Kira's place...
He'll come with the notebook.
And he'll see me and write my name.
No, he'll probably try
to kill everyone here
who knows about
the notebook's existence.
Th-This makes no sense.
What are you talking about?!
Are you saying that
some third party...
is just going to come strolling by
with the notebook and kill us?!
And are you saying that we should
just let this happen?!
That's right...
Please listen.
If someone comes through that door,
just let him in...
If the door opens slightly,
act as if you don't notice.
Th-That's crazy. That's. . .!
He's already here.
LIGHT YAGAMI
God!
Delete.
Delete. Delete. Delete. Delete.
Delete!
Delete. Delete. Delete.
Delete.
Please do not move.
It's all right. You won't die.
- How can you be so sure, Near?!
- Delete. Delete. Delete. Delete.
I've tampered with the notebook.
We took possession of the notebook
and replaced its pages.
The person behind the door...
who is killing for Kira...
has been using exactly
one page every day.
So I replaced the pages for today and
all subsequent days so no one will die.
Delete. Delete. Delete.
Delete. Delete...
Delete. Delete!
Delete!
X-Kira, who's beyond that door...
will eventually look inside...
to see if we're dead.
We can catch him when he does.
The one whose name isn't written
in the notebook is Kira.
Y-You're right. . .The one whose name
isn't written down would be Kira...
But...
Exactly as planned!
Tampering with the notebook...
I knew it all along.
Near... You've been completely defeated!
The notebook you tampered with
was the fake that I had Mikami prepare!
And now, the one Mikami is
writing names in...
is the real notebook
that's been hidden!
I had Mikami make a fake notebook
and send Takada clippings
from the real one.
In other words, Takada was the one
who was really doing the killings...
I had Mikami write names in public,
numerous times in the fake notebook...
so he would be noticed if
he was being followed.
But even then, Takada was the one
who was doing the killings...
That is how I made them believe
that the Notebook that Mikami
had was the real one...
Mikami's daily behavior can
be called morbidly methodical.
He fills the notebook
with names one page a day...
Near. You noticed that and thought
of tampering with it.
In other words, you arranged it so that
on the day of our meeting,
the page would be on the right side.
You just had to change
the pages for that day on.
If you did,
no one would die from having
their names written in the notebook...
That was your plan!
That's why the meeting date
was not changed.
But I knew you were going to
tamper with the notebook, so...
I had Mikami
MATS U M OTO
check the notebook every day...
I've confirmed it.
This match was decided
at that point...
The notebook that Mikami brought today
is the real one I had him hide!
Bu! Near, you had a chance.
You 're sofi'...
You're nowhere as good as L...
I would have noticed
there was a possibility that the notebook
was fake and would have tested it.
You had the opportunity...
I'm completely disappointed in you.
This is no fun...
You tried to win too beautifully...
Well, that's fine. Because of you. ..
E veryone's going to die.
And I, Kira will have
my perfect victory...
To the person outside...
Did you write the names down
in the notebook?
God!
Yes, I've written them.
No, n01' yet.
Don '1' laugh yet. . - hold if in- . .
They're all going to die 40 seconds
after he's written eve!y0ne's names...
35 seconds...
I'll claim my victory after 35 seconds...
That's strange...
Why would he answer you
so earnestly
when you asked him if he had
written our names?
Who knows?
Maybe he's honest? No, he's confident?
Could it be that he's seen
through your plan?
Huh? Then that means
we're in big trouble...
Teru Mikami.
Come in if you'd like.
I know that you are doing
the killings for Kira.
There shouldn't be anything to be
afraid of if you've written our names.
Come right in.
Teru Mikami?
That's right.
Don't hide. Come in.
God!
Well done, Mikami!
How many seconds has it been since
you wrote down the first name?
30...
31...32...
33...34...
35...36...
37...
38!
39!
I win, Near!
40!
TO BE CONTINUED
This single page Forever depressing
A fleeting tactic in the eyes
Without petition evil against the law
chain it in prison
Poison the notebook fear the lust
Delusion of being deceived
perpetually drooling
Judgement is "crime control"
they drive/ed
Who has the Rx for that?
A decriminalized world
A sanctioned word
Taking in heat
Just like "Pirates of Death"
Atone with the game of laws
Billy in despair
Now, it's time for ethics
Now, the unstoppable Eraser Rain
Billy in despair
Now, it's time for ethics
Now, the unstoppable Eraser Rain
The unstoppable Eraser Rain
PREVIEW
That's right. I'm Kira.
NEXT EPISODE: NEW WORLD