[theme music plays]
I can't believe my son
is looking at those magazines.
Hey, Light.
Come on!
Dinner's ready!
[Light laughing]
I'll solve equations with my right hand...
SUSPECT: TAYOSHI MURAO
...and write names with my left.
I'll take a potato chip
and eat it.
And the witness to my alibi
is L himself.
ENCOUNTER
Are you sure about this? Ryuk?
Yeah. I'm sure
nobody's following you, okay?
[Ryuk] Now, hurry up already, will ya?
The symptoms are getting worse.
[Light] I really hope you're not saying
what you think I'd want to hear
just to get some apples.
[Ryuk] Whoa. Hold it right there.
I just flew out and checked
a one-hundred-meter radius around you
and there was no one there.
So, yeah, for the last time, I'm sure.
Okay?
All right, but on the news
they said they were dispatching
1,500 investigators to Japan.
They're bluffing.
You said so yourself.
If it were really happening,
they wouldn't announce their arrival.
Instead, they'd come
and investigate secretly.
[Ryuk chuckles nervously]
I suppose you're right.
Well then, I'll buy you some apples.
Nice!
[Ryuk chuckles]
Here you are. Please, come again.
Light, come on! Hurry up!
[chomping loudly]
You know, you're really haven't been
that nice to me.
[chomping]
[swallows]
You have me looking all over for cameras,
telling me that I can't even eat apples
in the house anymore.
It's not right.
-[chains jangle]
-[bones crackle]
Make sure you eat the core as well.
[Ryuk chomping]
You know, I might actually write your name
in my Death Note and kill you.
Just like that.
[Light chuckles]
I wouldn't laugh, if I were you.
[Light] Right. That reminds me
I've got one finishing touch left to add.
Hmm. Hey, Ryuzaki.
[Ryuzaki] Yes?
I've been thinking
about purse-snatcher and embezzler's
heart attacks two days ago.
It seems my family couldn't have had
any knowledge of them before they died.
Shouldn't that resolve
any doubts you have?
You may be right.
Even though Kira can control
the time of death,
I don't think that there's any way
he could've arranged their deaths
without having seen
the broadcast first. Huh?
Your son has come home.
Hmm.
Heh, so you're gonna keep quiet
and pretend to study again, huh?
I have a good grasp
of where all the cameras are placed.
But I only managed to kill
a purse-snatcher and an embezzler...
MURAO TA...
...using that trick with potato chips.
Both of them were guilty
of much lesser crimes
than my previous victims.
[male newscaster] Next in...
You're watching TV?
I made sure to kill criminals
whose names and faces were broadcasted
when I didn't have access
to TV or the Internet.
But there is a chance
I'll look even more suspicious
of only these lesser criminals
end up dying
when I'm not receiving information.
In other words,
if I kill other petty criminals
whose names and faces
are broadcast as I watch TV,
I won't draw
unnecessary attention to myself.
For this to work
all I really have to do is remember
the identities of the criminals
I either see on TV or while I'm online,
regardless of the severity
of their crimes.
That way, whenever I go out...
MAINICHI ASAJ...
...I can use that piece of the Death Note
I keep in my wallet
to kill them at random times.
Just like that.
It's the perfect way
to deal with these hidden cameras.
[Ryuzaki] In the past few days,
I have listened
to all of our audio recordings
and reviewed the video footage
we captured.
I've gone over them many times.
And I've come to a conclusion.
Our surveillance
of the Kitamura and Yagami households,
has revealed...
nothing.
-[Ryuzaki] Hm...
-[sighs]
[Ryuzaki] We will remove
the cameras and wiretaps.
[sighs]
All that and we still
don't have any suspects.
It's okay, Matsuda.
We'll have to pursue other leads
but we'll get them.
[Ryuzaki] Please,
don't get the wrong idea.
I only said that we were unable
to reveal anything suspicious
based on our surveillance.
What?
[Ryuzaki] Even if Kira was among them,
I'm sure he wouldn't make it obvious.
No, in fact, it could mean
he was able to continue killing
without doing anything
outwardly suspicious.
Well, then you believe that Kira
is among one of those families?
As I've said,
there's a five percent chance.
Kira never stopped killing people,
even while the surveillance cameras
were in place.
I still have no idea how he's been able
to commit these murders, but...
let's say he could kill someone
simply by wishing death upon them.
You'd think that any human being
would have shown at least some emotion,
some sign that they were knowingly
committing an act of murder.
So, the obvious conclusion is...
that Kira couldn't be one of them.
However,
what if he is one of these people
we've been watching?
If he is, we have to assume
that his psyche has reached
god-like proportions.
Punishing evil-doers without
the slightest change of expression.
It almost makes me want to believe
that Kira does not exist,
that this is just
the wrath of a vengeful god.
But that idea is completely absurd,
to think that god would need a person's
face and name to kill them?
No.
These aren't acts of god.
But someone very childish and immature
who wants to pretend they're god.
That's what's going on here.
The mass murderer who calls himself Kira
exists somewhere.
I'm sure of it and I will catch him.
But I can't count on Kira
making any mistakes.
It doesn't matter how long we watch him,
he's not gonna expose himself to us.
So, what should I do?
Ideally, I'd get to know him well enough
that he'd admit to me that he was Kira
and show me how he kills.
Would that even be possible?
[birds cawing]
Hmm.
Hey, Light. I've just checked
and all the cameras have been removed!
All of them, every single one.
Hello, are you listening to me?
Hey, Light.
Oh, good point.
We still don't know if they've
removed all the wiretaps from the house.
I suppose this means
I'm no longer a suspect.
Everything is going as planned.
But I'm sure L won't give up that easily.
If he's still working
with the Japanese police,
chances are my father is working with him.
Or under him, anyway.
If that's the case,
I will have to use my father
to find out L's true identity
and I'll eliminate him.
Once I get rid of L,
Kira will be one step closer
to becoming the god of the new world.
[birds chirping]
[Sachiko] Light, hurry up.
You don't wanna be late.
Do your best.
I know you don't need it, but good luck!
[chuckles]
I really don't see why you two
are making such a big deal out of this.
I'm relieved. We don't have to
deal with wiretaps in the house anymore.
[Light] Well, it's nice to know
that one cause of stress
was resolved before my exam.
2007 TEST CENTER
FOR UNIVERSITY ADMISSIONS
Once I get into university, I will have
a lot more room to act as Kira.
Then I can focus on finding out
who L really is.
You there! The exam will be starting
in ten minutes!
So, you better hurry up!
It's fine. I planned to get here
three minutes before the test.
I hate waiting.
I'm here too early.
Well, well, confident.
CIVICS EXAM PAPER
-[bell tolls]
-And... begin.
Hm?
[professor] You there, student number 162.
Sit properly in your chair.
Hm?
[Zellogi yawns]
[Zellogi] It seems like a lot of Shinigami
are observing the human world lately.
What's with that, anyway?
It turns out that Ryuk
is being kept by a human.
What's he thinking? Seriously.
He's a disgrace to the pride of Shinigami.
[Zellogi] No, I'm talking about the human
who's keeping Ryuk.
Who would want him as a pet?
Aren't pets supposed to be cute?
[cackling]
When you're right, you're right.
So, what's the story
on this human, anyway?
Is it a male or a female?
Who knows?
In that case, I think I better go
and take a closer look.
Oh boy!
[chattering]
2007 TO-OH UNIVERSITY
ENTRANCE CEREMONY
You're a college student now.
That's kind of exciting.
I'm filled with joy.
Now for the freshman address,
freshman representative,
Light Yagami.
[Light] Yes.
Oh, wow.
[man] And freshman representative,
Hideki Ryuga.
[Ryuga] Oh, that's up here.
Is that Hideki Ryuga, the pop idol?
That guy?
There's no way he's got the brains
to get into a school like To-oh.
Yeah, you're right.
He doesn't look anything
like the real Hideki Ryuga.
I knew I'd be giving the address
with one other student.
But I never expected this.
I remember him from the exam center.
He got into trouble
for sitting oddly in his desk.
It seemed like he was off
in his own world.
As all of us embark
on this new chapter of our lives...
[student 1] The student who've
scored highest on the test
is supposed to give the speech, right?
[student 2] I guess both of them
must've had the high score this year.
[student 1] I heard they both had
the perfect scores in all subjects.
[student 2] Seriously?
[student 1] It's hard to believe
there are people like that.
I think I like the little one
on the right.
What? You're so weird, Kyoko.
Look at how he is dressed.
[Kyoko] Mhmm.
[student 1] Man, these two
are total opposites.
[student 2] Yeah.
[student 1] This one looks
like a sheltered genius
who has been groomed for success
his whole life.
But the other one...
As we embark
on this new chapter in our lives...
[student 1] There's something
not right about him.
He's just freaking weird.
[student 2] This guy must be
what they call a mad genius.
[student 1] Coming to the To-oh
entrance ceremony dressed like that?
Unbelievable!
Either he's crazy,
or he's just toying with us.
[Ryuga]
...freshman representative, Hideki Ryuga.
Light?
Light Yagami?
Your father is Chief Soichiro Yagami
of the NPA.
Your respect for your father is matched
only by your strong sense of justice.
Who the hell is this guy?
You're planning to join the police agency
when you graduate.
And you have already got experience,
seeing as you've helped the police
solve a number of cases in the past.
Now, you're showing an interest
in the Kira case.
I'm impressed by your abilities
and your sense of justice.
If you promise
not to tell anyone about this,
I have important information
concerning the Kira investigation
that I'd like to share with you.
Where’s this coming from?
And who is he?
Is it safe to just ignore him?
But... I wonder what this information
actually is.
I won't tell anyone. What is it?
I want to tell you I'm L.
[Light] What? [gasps]
There's no way.
What's he talking about?
If he really was L,
he would never admit to it.
I thought this guy
was a bit strange but...
This is pretty extreme.
[groans] Stop.
[puffs] This isn't good.
Don't act surprised.
On the off chance that he really is L,
I have to act how Soichiro Yagami's son,
Light Yagami, would act in this situation.
There'd be no reason for him to be afraid.
If you are who you say you are,
then you have nothing
but my respect and admiration.
Thank you.
The reason I chose to reveal
my identity to you
is because I think
you could be of some help to us
on the Kira investigation.
Light Yagami.
The likelihood that you are Kira
is just under five percent.
Even so,
something tells me
I'm not wrong to suspect you.
But you're just too perfect.
If you're Kira, I can't think of anything
that would put more pressure on you
than this little scenario.
[Ryuk chuckles]
If this guy's really L, like he says,
then consider me impressed.
[Light] Indeed.
If this guy really is L...
No, even if he is not L, I...
I-- I can't do anything to him.
[Light breathing nervously]
If what he's saying is true,
it probably means he's already
shown his face to my father.
What now?
If he were to die
right after telling me who he was,
it would only confirm their suspicions.
Although it's obvious Hideki Ryuga
is nothing more than an absurd alias,
it still complicates things.
Even if I get lucky and it isn't an alias,
if I try to kill him by simply
writing his name in the Death Note,
I might accidentally picture the face
of Ryuga, the pop star,
and end up killing him instead.
If this guy doesn't die,
he will know for a fact that I'm Kira.
Is he really L?
Does he already suspect that I'm Kira?
It' hard to say how much he knows, but...
I must be under suspicion.
What other reason could he have
for telling Soichiro Yagami's son
that he is L?
Does this mean
that he's still suspicious of the people
that Raye Penber was investigating
before he died?
Even so,
I still don't see why he would
reveal himself to me directly?
I can't let him see any signs of distress.
It's better if I just...
clear my mind.
[chuckles] I didn't think the ceremony
would be so interesting.
[students chatter]
[Ryuga] Hey, Light?
You hear that?
I think it's your new friend.
-Uh... nice meeting you.
-No.
The pleasure was mine.
-What an amazing car.
-A limousine?
Well, I'm sure I'll see you on campus.
[Light] Yeah. Take care.
[student 1] That kid must come from
some serious money.
[student 2] Plus, he is at the top
of the class. Where is the justice?
[music playing on TV]
Hey, welcome home, Mister To-oh!
[Ryuk] Huh? [chains jangling]
[puffing]
Damn it! He got me!
Uh? What do you mean?
Damn, L.
I've never been so humiliated in my life!
Ugh. Hey, why don't you just do
the Shinigami eye deal?
Then you should have no problem
killing him, right?
What good would Shinigami eyes do me
if this is just a trap?
If I kill him
and it turns out he's not really L,
then would be like announcing
to the real L that I'm Kira!
Uh... Sorry.
Don't think that Shinigami killing people
and humans killing people
are the same thing because they're not.
I want nothing more than to kill him,
but if I do it,
it's like asking to get caught.
Unfortunately, the Death Note can only
kill a person whose name is written in it.
So, it's not like I can
arrange for someone else to kill him.
It's inconvenient!
That's the flaw with the Death Note.
Light is usually so calm,
but he snapped.
This must be getting to him.
At first, I thought
once I found out his name,
I'll have him die in an accident
or kill himself.
However, none of that will do me any good,
unless I know with 100 percent certainty
that this guy is L.
No. It's already too late
to do anything about it,
since he's approached me
and introduced himself as L.
It doesn't matter how sure I am.
Regardless of the cause of death,
if L dies now,
the police are going to suspect me.
I underestimated him.
I've never even considered the possibility
that he would
reveal his identity to me on purpose.
He could be telling all the suspects
the same thing.
In fact, it doesn't even have to be him.
He could have sent a double instead.
For L, this strategy
acts as a solid defense
and it allows him
to confront Kira directly.
He can defend and attack.
He got me.
It was a good move.
I'm sure I haven't seen the last of Ryuga.
He will keep trying to move in on me,
playing the absent-minded genius
and will pretend like nothing is going on.
[chuckles]
[laughing manically]
Huh?
This is perfect.
There's no reason for me to be worried.
After all, this is proof
that they don't have anything on me yet.
So, this whole thing is nothing more
than a contest between L and me.
A match of wits!
On the surface we will be
two friendly classmates.
But in reality,
we will be investigating each other.
This is interesting, Ryuga.
If it's my friendship you want,
I'll gladly accept it.
In time I'll earn your trust.
And once you've told me
what I want to know,
there'll be no point keeping you alive.
Then I will kill you...
with my hands, if I have to.
TO BE CONTINUED
[theme music plays]