[theme song playing]
DOUBT
[tennis ball thwacking]
[Light] I have to admit,
I was surprised, Ryuga.
I never thought
you'd ask me to play tennis
as a way to get to know each other.
Is it a problem for you?
[Light] Not at all.
But when you first invited me to play,
did you know how good I was?
Yes. I'll be fine, though.
It's been a while
but at one time I was actually
the British Junior Champion.
[Light] If I ask him if he's British,
would he think I'm trying
to find out more about him
because I'm Kira?
Well, can't hurt to try.
Ryuga, were you raised in the UK?
I lived in England for about five years
when I was younger.
But save your breath.
Nothing in that story
would reveal L's true identity,
I promise you.
Oh, is that so?
[L] Well, since it's our first match,
why don't we just play a single set?
-First one to six?
-[Light] That's fine by me.
This is just a friendly game of tennis.
Nothing more.
In and of itself it won't determine
if Light is Kira.
But I know Kira hates to lose.
[grunts]
[yelps]
[L] Fifteen, love.
Wow, Ryuga. You sure don't mess around.
He who strike first, wins.
[man] What do you mean
you're not at liberty to say?
I'm very sorry, sir.
We're under orders from L
not to discuss the case with anyone,
including you.
I'm not asking for details here,
just what you're doing and where.
I'm very sorry, sir.
[growls]
[man] You know, Yagami,
it's been more than four months since
this case came to the public's attention
and they want results.
[man] People are saying that the NPA
is incompetent.
That L is incompetent.
With all due respect, sir.
The rest of the department runs away
with their tails between their legs
and we are incompetent?
Do you have any idea
how many people are left
at task force headquarters these days?
If you're concerned with public opinion,
then you want to suppress the fact
that most of our detectives
would rather a serial killer roam free
then risk their lives.
Please, excuse me.
[man] Yagami.
[man] What about this L character?
Can he be trusted?
[Yagami] In my opinion,
he is a lot more capable than we are.
Right now, even as we speak,
he is risking his life.
[grunts]
[Light grunts]
Are these two really amateurs?
Who are they, anyway?
I think their names are
Light Yagami and Hideki Ryuga.
These are the same two guys
who scored perfect on the exam.
[L] Relax, Light.
While it's true that Kira hates losing,
it's also true that most people would
rather win than lose. It's human nature.
[Light] Is he going to think that I'm Kira
if I go for the win?
I suppose I could just lose on purpose,
but if I do, it could work against me.
Since he'd expect Kira to want to win,
he might also expect me to throw the match
to avoid suspicion.
[Light] I don't see any way that he can
profile me based on a tennis match.
So, I have to assume
he has some other goal in mind.
[grunts]
But either way,
I'm not going to let him win!
[Ryuga grunts]
[L] Look at that.
He's going for the win.
That's four games all.
Light Yagami to serve.
[chuckles] And just like that,
we've got an umpire and a line judge.
[panting] You won't believe this!
I thought I'd heard the name
Light Yagami somewhere before,
so I checked.
He was the '02/'03
Junior High Tennis Champion.
Apparently, during the third year
award ceremony
he announced that he was
hanging up his racket.
And I guess he hasn't
played competitively since.
[female student] Hey, hey!
What about my Ryuga?
Don't tell me you haven't noticed
him holding his own
against this former junior high champ.
Hm.
[L] I can see the wheels turning,
Light Yagami.
I'm already in your head.
[Light] There's no way this tennis match
will deepen our friendship.
This is a token gesture.
An elaborate act to go with
so we can say we are closer.
[L] Because I wanted
to play tennis with you,
you'll assume I'm preparing
to take a step closer,
laying the ground work
to get to know you better.
[Light] And then you're going
to try and trap me
by getting me to say something
that only Kira would know.
[L] However, I'm sure you will tell me
you need to know
if you can trust me first,
and of course,
the only way to win your trust,
will be to share what I know about Kira.
[Light] If you want me
to discuss Kira with you,
it would only make sense
that I want to ask for proof
that you are in charge
of the investigation.
And more importantly, that you are
really L, as you've say you are.
[L] So, it goes without saying
that the first thing
you're going to want from me is...
[Light] ...some kind of confirmation
from a third party that you really are L.
[Light] Which means...
[both] We'll have to go
to task force headquarters!
[Light] In all things, one cannot win
with defense alone.
To win, you must attack!
Game and set.
Won by Light Yagami.
Six games to four!
[spectators applauding]
[birds chirping]
[L] Just as I expected, you beat me.
[Light] It's been a while
since I had to play that hard.
I'm feeling kind of thirsty.
Plus, there's something
that I wanted to ask you about.
Do you want to go somewhere
for a drink?
You humored me with the tennis match.
The least I can do,
is answer some of your questions.
But before this conversation
goes any further,
there's something I must tell you.
What's that?
I suspect that you, Light Yagami,
are in fact Kira.
Now, if you still wanna ask me something,
than please, go ahead.
[chuckles] You think I'm Kira?
Well, when I say I suspect you,
it's only a one percent possibility.
That aside, I don't mind telling you
that once I'm sure you aren't Kira
and I can verify
that your deductive skills
are as strong as I think they are,
I'd like nothing more than to have you
work with me on this investigation.
One percent, huh?
That was well worded.
Because no matter how little he says
he suspects me,
it means he has grounds to prevent me
from meeting anyone on the task force.
[Light] It was quite a pre-emptive move
on his part.
He got me.
This coffee shop is one of my favorites
in the area.
And if we sit here, there's no chance
of anyone overhearing us.
[L] Thanks for showing me this place.
I can see why you like it.
Not to mention,
we're so out of the way here,
no one is gonna give you a hard time
about the way you sit.
I don't sit like this because I want to.
I have to sit like this.
You see, if I were to sit normally,
my deductive skills would immediately
be reduced by roughly 40 percent.
So, what was it you wanted to ask me?
[Light] Right.
I'm sure that can wait
until you're convinced that I'm not Kira.
So, please, let's talk
about whatever you want to.
You're under no obligation
to do this, but...
would you mind submitting yourself
to a test of your
deductive reasoning skills?
Sure, why not.
Sounds like fun.
All right then.
We can begin by taking a look at these.
Photographs of three notes
written by prison inmates
while under Kira's control,
just prior to their deaths.
None of this information
has been made public.
You can take as long as you want
to look them over.
Please, let me know what you think.
Very interesting.
[Light] Come on, this is child's play.
There's a print number
on the back of each of these photographs.
If I ignore this fact,
and was still able
to come up with the phrase:
"L, do you know, gods of death
love apples",
what would that mean?
Clearly, if I read it the way Kira
intended on my first attempt,
I'd only look more suspicious.
But the fact I'm able
to solve this silly code,
isn't enough on its own
to prove that I'm Kira.
It would be quite amazing to learn
that not only could Kira kill others,
but could also control
his victims actions.
I think Kira wrote these,
and it seems he's encoded
a message for you as well.
Almost as if he's mocking you.
If you line these notes up
side by side,
and take a look
at the first letter of every line,
it reveals a message.
Rearranging it like this...
gives you...
"L, do you know
Gods of Death love apples?"
But there're obvious print numbers
on the back of all these photographs.
Arrange it in that order, we get:
"L, do you know
Love apples, Gods of Death "
[chuckles] That doesn't sound right.
And based on that,
it's hard to believe that Kira
would've wanted you to read it this way.
[L] That's incorrect.
Huh?
The thing is
there were actually four photographs.
When we add this one, it reads...
"L, do you know?
Gods of Death
who love apples have red hands."
[Light] It's a fake.
I never made any criminal
write the letter in this fourth picture.
Is he stupid?
But seeing as I only had
three photographs to work with,
my deduction was perfect.
[L] No, it wasn't.
The truth is, there were four of them.
If you'd figured that out,
it would have been perfect.
Even though you knew
the message was incomplete,
you decided that
there were only three notes.
You never even considered
that there might be a fourth.
What to make of that?
Damn him.
This wasn't just about gauging
my deductive reasoning skills.
He wanted to see
what my reaction would be.
If I keep falling for his tricks,
I'll be playing right into his hands.
Hmm.
Well, you got me there.
I didn't think of that.
In any case,
the likelihood this message
will lead you to Kira is not very great.
Besides, we all know
Gods of Death don't exist.
If you were me,
faced with someone who might be Kira,
how would you go about establishing
this person's innocence or guilt?
You need to be absolutely sure.
I would probably try
to get him to say something
that was never made public in any way
Something that only Kira could know.
Kinda like what you were doing just now.
[L] Truly amazing.
What's incredible
is that I've asked countless detectives
that same question
and it took most of them minutes
to even come up with an answer.
But you...
you immediately thought of a scenario
in which Kira is speaking
directly to the investigator.
I'm impressed.
You'll make a fine detective, Light.
[chuckles]
But it's a bit of double-edged sword.
The more impressive my answers,
the more of a suspect I become.
[L] Yes, it's about three percent now.
However, it's made me
that much more determined
to work with you on this investigation.
You see, I'm in a position
where even if you are Kira,
it would still be to my benefit
to have you working alongside us.
Do you know why I'd say that?
If I cooperate with you,
there's a chance I can
help the investigation to move forward.
And if I'm Kira, I might reveal myself.
In other words, whether I am Kira or not,
you stand to gain either way.
It’s a very smart move on your part.
But I think you might be
getting the wrong idea.
It's true that I do have
an interest in the Kira case,
and yes, detective work
is a hobby of mine.
But I know that I'm not Kira,
and I certainly
don't want to be killed by him.
Besides, what proof
have you been able to give me
that you yourself aren't Kira?
I mean, it hardly seems fair
for just one of to be investigated,
wouldn't you say?
At this point, neither of us
can prove that we're not Kira.
However, if you are in fact L,
I don't imagine it would be that hard
for you to prove it to me.
I think I'd be convinced
if, say, my father or someone else
from the task force headquarters
was able to confirm your identity.
If you can't do that, then I'm afraid
I just won't be able to help you.
You sure talk a lot, don't you, Light?
Typical for someone who hates losing.
I think that's seven percent...
Could it really be him?
I don't remember saying you couldn't meet
anyone from task force headquarters.
to verify my identity.
Huh?
I'm currently working
alongside your father,
as well as several other
senior detectives from the NPA.
Now, if I understand you correctly
and I take you
to task force headquarters,
you'll help us with the investigation.
Am I safe in making this assumption?
[Light] Does this guy have a death wish?
I don't understand. What's he thinking?
[phone ringing]
Excuse me.
-[phone buzzing]
-Oh, there goes mine.
Yes?
[man] Ryuzaki, I have some bad news.
[Sachiko] Light, your father has--
Light, it's your--
My father...
He had a heart attack!
[ambulance siren wailing]
[Sachiko] Okay, see you tomorrow.
Have them call home
if you need me to bring anything.
-Light, you take care of him, okay?
-[Light] Sure.
So, the doctors think
stress was the only cause?
Yeah.
To be honest, I thought it was Kira,
when I first collapsed,
but I'll be all right.
It seems I've been pushing myself
a bit too hard lately.
Indeed.
It must have added to your stress
knowing that Light
is a suspect in this investigation.
You actually told my father that?
Yes, in fact, I've told him everything.
It's true he even knows that I'm L.
That's correct.
This man is L.
To protect his identity,
we on the task force
refer to him as Ryuzaki.
But make no mistake, it's him.
This guy is the real L.
My father wouldn't lie.
The very same man who has been
controlling the police up to this point.
If I get rid of him
and the rest of the investigative team...
No...
No, let's face it.
It wouldn't be that simple.
There's no need to rush.
I have time to sit back and watch.
But for now,
I'm the Light Yagami
who's worried for his father.
So, Ryuzaki,
now that you've had the chance
to talk to my son,
is he cleared as a suspect?
When I say I suspect him,
you should know it's very minor.
We’ve gone over this
but I'll explain it again.
Not long ago, Kira killed 12 FBI agents
who'd come to Japan to assist us.
They were instructed to follow people
connected to the Japanese police.
One of these agents, Raye Penber,
exhibited unusual behavior
before he died.
I understand.
And I was one of the people
Raye Penber was investigating
before he died.
It only make sense I'd be a suspect.
No, to be more precise,
there's no one else you could suspect.
I find Light's deductive powers
quite impressive.
He's always quick and to the point.
Ryuga, I'd like to help
with the investigation.
My father has erased any doubts
I might have had
regarding your true identity.
Also, I'd like nothing more
than to catch Kira
so I can prove once and for all
that I'm not him.
No, Light.
This is a time in your life
when you should be studying
to become a police officer.
It won't be too late to join us
once you're done.
Come on, Dad. What are you talking about?
Who knows how many years that'll take.
Besides, don't you remember my promise?
That if something ever happened to you,
I'd find Kira and make sure
he gets executed.
I refuse to believe that my son
could turn out to be Kira.
[L] This doesn't seem
like an act to me.
Or if it is, it's too cheesy.
[Yagami] Light, listen to me.
Kira is pure evil.
We can all agree on that.
But recently,
I've been thinking of this whole situation
in a different way.
What is truly evil
is the power to kill people.
And any person who has come
to possess this kind of power,
is cursed.
No matter how you use it,
no true happiness
can be obtained like that.
Not by killing other people.
[L] I think you're absolutely right.
If Kira is just a normal person,
who somehow obtained this awful power,
I would say that he's cursed.
Ryuzaki, I'm sorry for all this trouble.
But I'll be back at work
as soon as the doctors let me out of here.
[nurse] Excuse me.
Visiting hours were over ten minutes ago.
[Light] Ryuga.
What would it take to get you
to believe that I'm not Kira?
Please, isn't there something?
If you aren't Kira, it won't be necessary.
Let things run their course
and the truth will be revealed.
I can't take this anymore!
Put yourself in my position.
How do you think it feels
to be accused of being Kira?
It was one of the worst feelings ever.
What if you were to lock me up for a month
in a place with no TV or any other kind
of access to the outside world
and keep a constant watch over me?
Would any normal person be willing
to go to such extreme measures
to clear their name?
That's no good.
I can't do anything that would
deprive you of basic human rights.
And furthermore,
it's a complete nonsense
for the investigator
to take suggestions from his suspect.
I understand.
[L] Don't worry so much.
Be patient. It will become apparent to us
if you're not Kira.
And listening to that conversation
between you and your father,
I was almost convinced
you might not be him.
Light, please,
take good care of Mr. Yagami.
Oh, one more thing.
I know agreed
to help with the investigation,
but I don't think I'll be able to do much
until my father is healthy again.
Yes, of course.
Well then...
Hideki Ryuga.
Ryuzaki.
He's the L I've been fighting
this whole time.
[Light] What is his real name?
Light Yagami,
are you not Kira?
Ryuk.
Huh?
I never once felt cursed
since I picked up the Death Note.
In fact, the thought
never even crossed my mind.
I'm happier than I've ever been.
All thanks to this power.
[Light] I'm going to create
a perfect world.
[Ryuk] Honestly, I couldn't care less
whether you feel cursed or happy
to have the notebook.
I leave that sentimental crap
to you humans.
But...
normally, humans who come
into contact with the Shinigami
have nothing but misfortune.
[Light] That's interesting.
But I have no intentions
of repeating that pattern.
[Ryuk chuckles] Well, I hope
you're right about that.
[man] What is this crap?
Don't tell me
this is your ideal of a proposal?
Listen, you people must think
that just mentioning Kira's name
is enough to get us
the ratings we need, huh?
Well, you're wrong.
Our program gets the ratings
because we cover stories
that the other stations won't touch!
If it bleeds, it leads!
What I need
is a good fricking story.
Not this crap!
Now, get out there and find me a story!
But the police won't talk, sir.
It's been impossible to get details
from them lately.
Idiots! I don't pay you to complain.
And if they won't give you anything,
then get creative!
[knocking on door]
Huh?
Mr. Demegawa, sir, this is for you.
[Demegawa] What is this?
So, who is this from?
Huh?
[laughs]
[Demegawa] Now, this is more like it.
This is what I call a story.
It's almost too good to be true.
"A message to the world from Kira.
If you do not broadcast these tapes,
I'll kill your company's
board of directors one by one."
Who wouldn't air these?
If this is for real, our ratings
are gonna go through the roof!
[Demegawa] Holy crap!
I'm so excited I feel like
I'm having a heart attack here!
TO BE CONTINUED