Easy easy banzai Easy easy banzai
Easy easy banzai Human
Wanna get them mad? Get them mad?
Get them mad? People
What's up? Full of causes for concern
Crime won't disappear Forever
(play a trick on resentment Who's down?)
What's up? Full of causes for concern
Crime won't disappear Forever
Hey Hey! A hymn to humanity
Love has gone People, are you worried?
Hey Hey! Subservient People! !
WHAT'S UP, PEOPLE?! !
Are you worried?
The Second L, and the one
who I think is Kira, is Light Yagami.
Good evening.
I am Kiyomi Takada.
KIYOMI TAKADA CHOSEN AS
KIRA'S SPOKESPERSON
About our investigation...
I think we should incorporate
Kiyomi Takada from now on.
Sorry.
Kira...
KIRA VVANTS TC) HAVE THE ROOM CHECKED FOR SURVEILLANCE
DEVICES. I'M REMOVING EVERYTHING BEFORE HE SEES THEM.
It can't be helped...
Listen Kiyomi...
I'm Kira.
Yagami is. . .Kira?
SCORN
All the pieces are set.
Now that things have
gone this far,
It's my turn to head to Japan...
Commander Rester.
Yes.
Can you return to New York now?
NOW?
I've decided to go to Japan.
Does that mean that I'll be standing by
in New York while you're gone?
No...
Then why do I have to
return to New York?
I've never been on
an airplane by myself.
I want you to come back now,
and come with me to Japan...
All right.
As we expected,
Yoshida Productions and
NHN jumped at the chance.
MISA AMANE TO MAKE A COMEBACK AT NHN EAST VVEST POP SONG FESTIVAL "MISA-MISA'S
FIRST TIME ON SHOVV: I'M GONNA DO MY BEST!" TO BE HOSTED BY ANCHOR KIYOMl TAKADA
It's difficult to enter
NHN right now,
but this will allow us to do it
without looking suspicious.
Yes. Mogi can go as her manager.
We definitely want someone
who can freely enter NHN.
I'll also investigate through Takada.
This is Near. Get me L.
This is L... What do you want?
I'm going to arrest Kira and
I'm here in Japan.
In Japan?
Why is he taking the time
to tell me that?
L. . . You've contacted
Takada the anchor
and are investigating Kira,
aren't you?
Yes... I'm investigating her myself.
I thought so.
Right now, it's a given
that we must investigate
NHN's Kiyomi Takada if
we want to find Kira...
So please tell Takada that...
SPK members have entered Japan
in order to arrest Kira.
Why?
In order to lure Kira out.
I also want you to add this:
There are only four members
of the SPK, including myself.
Kira won't run away.
He'll definitely try to kill us.
We're...
going to use that to beat him
at his own game.
"Beat him at his own game," huh?
Fine. . .Near. ..
I'll accept your challenge!
I'm in Japan.
I'm also in Japan.
Then we may meet
face-to-face soon.
You're right.
I'll look forward to that time.
Yes.
We'll bring this business with Kira
to an end once and for all...
Definitely...
Come to think of it,
ever since the beginning...
this has been a one-on-one
battle against L...
Only now, it's shifted to someone
who's influenced by L.
Fine, Near.
I'll come out if you're coming out.
When we meet,
we'll see who's more prepared
and who can surpass the other.
When that happens,
the battle will end.
That's when I'll begin
my reign at the top!
First, we have to figure out
our current situation.
I is Light Yagami.
And Kira...
Let's assume that there
is an L-Kira.
And there's another.
X-Kira. He holds the notebook
and is using it.
Judging by X-Kira's killings,
he definitely has the Shinigami eyes.
L-Kira and X-Kira plan to
communicate through Takada.
So, I believe there are approximately
two ways to win against Kira.
Our first option...
is to kill L-Kira and X-Kira
and take the notebook.
But we will never resort
to this method.
Why not?
That is not how we do things.
"We?"
That's right.
Killing people and getting
ex post-facto justification
just by the fact that
the killings have stopped...
That's not the way that
I and I do things.
I wouldn't be able to rest...
There would be no meaning to entrusting
this case to his successor...
Takada, I heard on the news that
you receive an enormous amount
of fan mail every day.
Yes. I've heard it's about
an average of 200 letters a day.
200 letters. . .
I'm kind of jealous...
- I don't even have f/hve f0 read them.
- With just audio and no video...
it's quite boring.
I think you should look through
them even if they're fan letters.
You're right.
Keep calm when you
read this note.
Make sure not to let the people
listening to this conversation
detect your surprise.
The SPK has started to move.
For your safety, you should
not only accept messages...
but make demands to Kira as well.
Light has moved on to the main topic.
You shouldn't remain
just a spokesperson.
Why don't you reach out to Kira?
There is a cflfierenz' job
that Tmusz' do.
In order to create
the perfect world for Kira...
I WANT YOU TO PUNISH AS KIRA
It's all right. You'll do it well...
If you do, you can give
information to Kira
that you don't want the SPK to know.
All right. I'll do it.
We did it.
As I expected of Light. He's good.
Delete... Delete...
Delete...
Kiyomi Takada...
Yes?
Here's your message.
Send me a fan letter that I can
tell is from you.
Place within it...
Five blank notebook pages.
Continue killing as usual
until I receive them.
What about after you receive them?
Continue killing using
a fake notebook.
A fake?
Yes.
Make a notebook that looks
as close to the original as possible...
and act as if you're killing
using the fake...
I understand.
God, what are you doing?
No, there's no need to question.
God is absolute...
My job is to do as God wishes.
What is this show?
It's the program that
took over Kira (9 Kingdom.
They're as unscrupulous as always.
Today, Miss Takada will introduce...
her four female bodyguards who have
passed a rigorous screening process.
The 22nd Karate Title Champion,
Tatsumi Ooyama.
Former CIA agent Hal Lidner.
If there's an SPK member
among these people,
it would have to be Hal Lidner...
Near is also trying to
investigate Takada...
A random murderer
has stabbed six people...
- Who would I choose...
- in Shinjuku's busy quarters.
- to be X-Kira?
- There has been another killing.
Children should be educated about
Kira's existence and teachings.
- Takada was chosen because...
- I think that there is nothing...
- she worships Kira.
- more important.
X-Mra A9 someone who knows
that Takada A9 a MTa-Worshwer.
Someone who has a close,
intimate relationship with Takada...
Kira will not forgive any small crime.
From now on...
assume that any living person
is punishable.
I'd like to hear Kira's voice...
his thoughts once more.
I think that following Kira's teachings
exactly as ordered
is the quickest path to world peace.
21 ST CENTURY DISCUSSION THINKING
ABOUT THE RECONSTRUCTION OF JAPAN
If there are no orders or
words from Kira,
we need to believe that
it's all part of Kira's plan.
And make our own decisions
and take action.
- L-Kira is Light Yagami.
- Kira's orders. Kira's Kingdom.
- It was Teru Mikami's own decision...
- Spokesperson. Close since college.
- to contact Kiyomi Takada. ..
- Coincidental past. Secret meetings.
- In order to stop Demegawa's rampage.
- Had notebook before our surveillance.
Everything seems to fit...
I've been saying...
Why aren't I the headlining performer?
You said that I was the highlight of
this year's East West Pop Festival.
No, the highlight is the highlight.
But the headlining act
is usually a big name...
So we should take precautions...
Kiyomi Takada...
She sure is stupid.
She doesn't know that Light is just
using her for his investigation.
Don't say that.
You'll be killed if you do.
I know. That's why I whispered it.
She snickered at me!
I'm going to kick her!
Don't!
What were you trying to do?
What was I doing?
Looks who's talking, lady?
Lidner, she's a good friend of mine.
Please don't be rough with her.
Yes, Miss Takada.
I'm very sorry.
M-Misa-Misa!
Are you all right?
That was s0 frustrating!
L. If Mr. Aizawa is there...
May I talk to him?
Near, this is Aizawa.
What is it?
Do you videotape and wiretap L
and Takada's meetings?
No. We only have wiretaps now.
I see. Only wiretaps now.
Thank you very much.
If it's only wiretaps...
then we can assume that L-Kira
and X-Kira
are contacting each other
through Takada.
If that's the case,
then Lidner is in increasing danger.
I know.
What's important is for L to turn
his attention to Lidner and Takada.
We'll investigate Mikami
while his attention is on them.
How are things, Gevanni?
About Mikami. ..
Tailing him is strangely easy...
He doesn't try to hide and
has been living normally in
the same place for the past four years.
He's prosecuting people
actively at his job.
I don't think that he can be X-Kira...
No. There is a high possibility
that Mikami is X-Kira.
Please be careful...
Don't enter his room yet,
just keep watch over him...
Yes.
Jeez. How many meetings
do I have to have with NHN?
And how many times have only I been told,
"Be careful about what you say"?
What's with that?
Yes. I'll ask her.
Misa-Misa. Takada is asking if
you would like to have dinner together.
Huh?
Damn Kiyomi. .. What does she want?
That's fine.
The Pop Song Festival emcee
and the main headliner
should have dinner together
at least once...
Tell her, "Okay."
Hello?
Miss Takada, she agreed.
Well, I'm looking forward to it.
Lidner, book a nice private room.
Also. . .l would like you
to attend as well.
Yes...
Miss Amane, I'm sorry
this is so late at night.
It just had to be after
News 9 finished.
Not a problem. I don't mind.
I'm a night owl anyway.
So, what do you want?
It's hard for me to say if
you ask, but...
Your boyfriend seems busy.
Do you still see him?
Why that... She knows that
she can see him, but I can't...
What a-!
I do. He's a lot more
affectionate than he seems.
He keeps clinging onto me
every night when he comes home.
I see... You're doing well.
Thank goodness.
Also, since you're the emcee,
I wanted to tell you this
in advance, but...
I'm going to announce my engagement
to him at the Pop Music Festival.
Does he. . .know about this?
Of course. It's an engagement.
I can't do it by myself.
He promised me more
than a month ago.
Don't you think it would make
things more exciting if
I made the announcement at
the Pop Music Festival, Miss Emcee?
You're right.
It would be great if you can.
What do you mean, "if I can"?!
You're not going to let me do it?
Or are you...
Going to have me killed by Kira?
Of course not.
Only Kira decides who to punish.
I'm not involved.
I think of you as a friend.
Don't say such depressing things.
I don't have any intention
of killing anyone,
no matter how horrible they may be.
Well, whatever.
I used to like Kira as well, but...
Light's going to catch Kira soon.
When he's caught,
you're not going to get away either...
You'll probably get...
executed.
M-Miss Takada!
Are you all right?
Listen, Kiyomi... I'm Kira.
With me... You're...
going to become the goddess
of the new world...
Miss Amane.
Yes?
That was very unpleasant.
Well. . .the same to you!
I should have waited
to invite you to dinner
until after you had become
more mature
and learned some manners.
Oh my...
I'm older than you are, Little Kiyomi.
Besides, doesn't leaving the table
for something like this
make you the more childish one?
Mochi...
Thanks for waiting. ..
How are you?
A-Are you all right?
Of course. I won.
Won?
Yeah. It was a cinch!
About tonight's conversation between
Takada and Amane...
I could only assume that
they were fighting over...
who was Light Yagami's girlfriend.
Near...
All that I can deduce from this is...
Light Yagami is popular
with the ladies.
Takada and Amane adore
Light Yagami.
Near, be serious!
It's a problem if
they seriously like him.
They won't easily betray him.
Yes, he can make them do
whatever he wants them to do...
Please stop!
What's up with that, lady?
You're wearing such
a short skirt even though it's winter...
You were tempting me, weren't you?
S-Someone-!
A cell phone?
Mikami has taken out a notebook.
Delete...
He's writing in it.
Could that be it...?
Mikami's getting off.
TO BE CONTINUED
This single page Forever depressing
A fleeting tactic in the eyes
Without petition evil against the law
chain it in prison
Poison the notebook fear the lust
Delusion of being deceived
perpetually drooling
Judgement is "crime control"
they drive/ed
Who has the Rx for that?
A decriminalized world
A sanctioned word
Taking in heat
Just like "Pirates of Death"
Atone with the game of laws
Billy in despair
Now, it's time for ethics
Now, the unstoppable Eraser Rain
Billy in despair
Now, it's time for ethics
Now, the unstoppable Eraser Rain
The unstoppable Eraser Rain
PREVIEW
Mikami is talking to himself!
He seems to have reacted to
the scrap of paper at his feet.
He's entered the gym.
I'm sneaking into the locker room.
I've opened his bag lock!
I'm going to touch the notebook!
NEXT EPISODE: VIGILANCE