[theme music playing]
MALICE
[cheeping]
[inaudible]
COMING OF AGE CEREMONY
NHN NEWS 9
[Gevanni] Near, it's all taken care of.
I did exactly as you asked.
[Near] Good…
[chains rattling]
[pen scratching on paper]
MATSUMOTO
"T." That is all I have to tell you today.
We'll talk soon.
[Mikami] Very well. I understand.
I also have a message for you.
[Takada] Yes. What is it?
I've confirmed it.
[gasps softly]
[phone hangs up]
[phone ringing]
[Matsuda] You got a text?
I WANT TO SEE YOU
Ooh, it says she wants to see you!
Man, I'm so jealous. [sighs]
[Light] I've done it. That's the sign
of confirmation from Mikami.
Now, all I have to do is wait for Near
to request a meeting face to face.
Game over, Near! I win.
I knew what your move would be
from the very beginning.
-[monitor beeps]
-Sir, this is Gevanni.
I've been checking the notebook regularly
as you ordered.
For the past three days, he's continued
filling out one page every night
after midnight as he usually does.
The victims still match up.
And there's been no change
in Mikami's behavior otherwise.
[Near] I understand.
Well, then let's begin.
[clock ticking slowly]
[monitor beeping]
It's Near!
-[Light] He called!
-[Near] L?
Yes, this is L. What is it, Near?
[Near] I want to meet you.
What?
[Near] There is something I must show you
pertaining to the Kira case.
[Light] But... don't you suspect me
of being Kira?
Do you really think it's wise
to reveal your face to me?
[Near] That's true. I cannot show you
unless I reveal my face.
Furthermore, the very act
of showing my face will prove something.
And that will bring this case to a close.
[all gasp]
All right, fine.
As far as I'm concerned, the sooner you
realize you're wrong about me, the better.
[Aizawa] The time has finally come
for Near to prove that Light is Kira.
But on the other hand, if that's true,
this will be a chance
for Light to kill Near.
It all comes down to this.
[Near] I'd like to lay out
some ground rules for the meeting.
[Light] We're willing to go along
with whatever you want.
First, I wanna have all the investigators
from both teams be present.
In other words, everyone who is chasing
after Kira should be gathered together
to take part in the meeting.
[Light] I understand.
That's not a problem.
[Near] As I mentioned before,
there are a total of four members
in the SPK.
That's including myself.
All of us will be there.
Besides our team, we'll also bring along
Mr. Mogi, who's currently staying with us.
As for Miss Amane, she will be released
right before we meet.
She'll not be told where we're going.
You can come and meet us once you confirm
that she has been safely released.
Is that acceptable?
-[Matsuda] What do we do?
-Hmm.
[Light] Okay, Near, I understand.
I have a team of five investigators,
including myself.
Of course, Mogi's with you
at the moment,
so aside from me,
there'll be only three people.
Very well. That's fine.
Now, as for our meeting place…
Daikoku Wharf. There's a warehouse
on the outskirts of the southeast side
that's been abandoned for some time.
It's known as the Yellow Box.
I've already taken the liberty
of purchasing it.
If this arrangement is fine with you,
then we'll use it.
How about that, Light Yagami?
With a location like this ,
you can do what you're planning to do.
One more thing.
This meeting cannot take place
unless I have your word that someone
will bring the notebook.
Huh? Wait, why the notebook?
[Near] It's quite simple.
If your entire team leaves HQ to meet me,
then there'll be no one left behind
to guard the notebook.
I can promise you this.
I will make no attempts to steal it.
In fact, I won't even try to touch it.
As long as Mr. Aizawa can confirm
that it's the genuine notebook,
I'm willing to place my faith in you
and accept his word.
Huh?
All right.
However, I do insist that someone
other than L hold onto it.
My reasons for making that request
should be fairly obvious to you.
Right, I understand. But I'll be the one
who decides who will hold onto it.
Does that sound fair?
[Near] Yes, of course. Then all that's
left to arrange is the time and date.
[Light] Right. The question is, what time?
[Near] Mikami makes his judgments
after midnight.
He most likely receives a notice
in the morning
of which people to kill next.
If we take his movements
into consideration...
Say... three days from now,
on the 28th at 1:00 p.m.?
[Light] One o'clock, huh? That's the exact
time I expected him to pick.
Near is obviously aware
of Mikami's movements.
That's fine by me.
The time doesn't really concern us.
[Near] Well, then. One o'clock.
Three days from now.
[Light] Sure.
[Light] Near.
[Near] Light Yagami.
[both] I know exactly what your plan is!
[both] And I'm going to win!
Kiyomi, I'm sorry, but I'm a little busier
than usual today.
Oh, really? Does that mean
you can't stay until morning?
Yeah, I'm sorry.
The police are gonna have
their hands full
for the next two to three days.
That's a shame.
[Light] I've already given orders to both
Mikami and Takada about what to do.
This will be the final order.
To kill Near.
JANUARY 28 1:00 PM
DAIKOKU WHARF WAREHOUSE
[camera shutter clicking]
DEAR MS. TAKADA, I LOVE YOU!
[engine revving]
[tires screeching]
Heads up, we're under attack!
[Lidner] Quick! This way.
Are you all right?
[Takada] Yes.
[bodyguard] He's getting away! After them!
[Lidner] We need to get inside NHN now.
-[tires screeching]
-[Mello] Don't do it. Take a look around.
It's not safer here. Not even inside.
Mello!
[Mello] It's best if you get her away
from here right now. Miss Takada, get on!
Now!
It's okay. You'll be safe with him.
-Please. You have to go.
-[Takada] Right.
[engine revving]
Team A and team B,
stay on that bike's tail
and don't lose sight of them.
As for the rest of you,
I need you to find that assailant.
All right! We've confirmed
Ms. Takada's safety.
Let's get her into car number seven.
[tires screeching]
-What the hell?
-No, he's taking her!
[bodyguard 1] Damn it!
[bodyguard 2] Stop, you idiot!
You can't do that.
What if it ends up hitting her?
[stammering] What are you doing?!
[reporter] One of the attackers
was heavily armed.
TAKADA KIDNAPPED
IN FRONT OF NHN?
As of this moment,
both Ms. Takada's escort team
and the police are hot on the tail
of the suspects.
[Matsuda] Oh, man. This is really bad.
[Aizawa] Is it Near again?
[Light] Near, you promised
that we'd meet in three days’ time.
What's the meaning of making a move
like this now? It doesn't make sense.
No, this isn't Near's style.
It's more like…
[monitor beeps]
[Light] It's Near!
[horns honking]
[indistinct yelling]
[tires screeching]
[Matt] So, those cars got ahead
of me, huh?
How many damn bodyguards
does one woman need anyway?
[Matt] Hey, come on! Give me a break.
Since when were the Japanese allowed
to carry around such big guns?
You got me. I'm part of this whole
kidnapping incident.
That means you'll have a lot
of questions to ask.
-You won't shoot--
-[guns firing]
What an idiot. He probably wouldn't
have told us anything anyway.
And death is the only way to pay
for crimes against Kira.
[Takada] This man…
He's the person that Light warned me
to be extra careful of. Mello.
Mihael Keehl…
[Takada whimpering]
[Mello] Take off everything you're wearing
and put it all in that box.
Hurry up.
You can use this blanket.
[Near] L, I am not the one
who kidnapped Takada.
Is that so? Then it has to be...
-Mello.
-[Near] Yes, that's right.
I have to be honest with you on this.
We had one of our members
escorting Takada and they confirmed it.
Mello was the one who abducted her.
I'm apologize for letting this happen
while one of us was guarding her.
[Light] Near... isn't there any way
for you to contact Mello?
[Near]
No, I'm afraid that would be impossible.
While I do have a method
of getting in touch with him,
there's no way he'd respond
in the current situation.
[Takada] Before I take off the rest,
could I please have the blanket
so I can wrap it around me?
Whatever you want.
NHN NEWS 7
LADY TAKADA KIDNAPPED
Our latest report is that the escort team
was forced
to shoot one of the perpetrators
They are also still making efforts
to track Ms. Takada's whereabouts.
[Ide] Were you able to get a hold of her?
[Light] Not yet.
Takada's phone has been turned off.
Mello must have confiscated it.
-[phone beeps]
-Damn it.
I need to get in touch with Takada.
With no way of getting a hold of her,
all I can do is wait.
[Mello] This is the only thing
that can be done.
If I don't do it--
[reporter] As for the suspect
who was gunned down earlier,
we're still not able to identify him.
The police are tracking the remaining...
[Mello]
Matt… I never thought you'd be killed.
I'm sorry.
[shivering]
[panting]
[phone ringing]
-Light's cell phone!
-Could it be her?
Quiet, everyone.
Hello?
[Takada sobbing] Light… I…
-Ms. Takada?
-[all gasp]
Listen to me, are you all right?
The only reason she'd be able to call me
like this without getting caught
is if she had an opportunity
to get away from Mello. Or...
[Takada] Light, Light, please save me!
[Light] It's all right. Calm down.
Answer my questions, okay?
[sobbing] Okay.
[Light] First, your location.
Do you know where you are?
[Takada] No. No, I don't know where I am.
I was put into a truck that was locked
from the outside.
But we were on the freeway
and I caught a glimpse of a sign
that said we were heading to Nagano.
Right now, I think we're parked
inside of a building somewhere.
[Light]
Miss Takada, you are Kira's spokesperson.
Do you remember the conversation
we had when I told you
that there might be people who would try
to hurt you because of that?
[Takada] Yes, I remember.
We talked about what you should do
if a situation like this ever arose.
Do you remember that?
[Takada] I remember…
I did what you told me to, Light.
I did it.
[Light] Yes!
[Takada] I didn't struggle,
even when he stripped me naked.
I did exactly as you said.
I made survival my first priority,
and-- and I did it.
Please, Light, I did everything
that you told me to…
Come quickly. Save me!
[Light] Ms. Takada…
You remember what I told you to do
after that, don't you?
[Takada] I have to do as many killings
as possible while I still can.
I... I know.
-But Light--
-Can you do it?
[whimpering]
-[Takada] I can do it.
-[phone hangs up]
[sobbing]
Aizawa, Ide, let's get going.
Matsuda, you stay here and take care
of headquarters.
You got it.
[sobbing]
KYOTO LEGAL
GOVERNMENT BUILDING
[Takada] It's me…
Send me as many names of people
to punish as you can.
Here's my email address.
Yes. Right, I understand.
If Takada is calling me like this,
it must mean that she's been able
to kill her kidnappers.
In which case, the only certainty
is that she's in a situation
where she can't move.
Nakajima, I'm going to go to the scene
of the crime for this case.
[Nakajima] Okay.
[Light] All right. I got the location
by tracing the call.
Head to Karuizawa by freeway.
[Aizawa] Karuizawa, huh? Damn. It'll take
at least 30 minutes to get there.
[Light] Well, hurry.
This is Mello we're talking about.
Who knows what he'll do?
Got it.
[Light] I don't believe this.
Aizawa and Ide are just too stupid.
They jumped the gun and got
in the front seats without even thinking.
-This is just too easy.
-[clicking]
[gasps]
-[gasps]
-[heart beating]
[gasps]
[Lidner gasps] No, no!
What the hell is this?
[Light] Kiyomi Takada, Suicide.
January 26, 2013, 2:32 PM.
Burns to death by setting fire
to everything around her…
including everything she wrote on.
TO BE CONTINUED
[theme music playing]