Easy easy banzai Easy easy banzai
Easy easy banzai Human
Wanna get them mad? Get them mad?
Get them mad? People
What's up? Full of causes for concern
Crime won't disappear Forever
(play a trick on resentment Who's down?)
What's up? Full of causes for concern
Crime won't disappear Forever
Hey Hey! A hymn to humanity
Love has gone People, are you worried?
Hey Hey! Subservient People! !
WHAT'S UP, PEOPLE?! !
Are you worried?
MAKESHIFT
Let's begin our meeting.
Only seven out of the eight are present.
That means that...
They probably killed one of them.
For the further advancement
of the Yotsuba Group...
who shall we kill?
See? It's like I said.
This is bad.
If things continue like this...
Before that, we have several topics
which we should discuss.
First, concerning Hatori's death...
That couldn't be helped.
To be honest,
I'm relieved that he's dead.
Kira has clearly shown
what'll happen
to whoever tries
to leave these meetings.
I think we all know what
Hatori's death means.
Take it to heart.
Next, Era/do Coil's report...
One of their colleagues just died.
Is that it?!
Five million dollars.
Just for this report, huh?
He hasn't found anything
important about L,
like his face and name.
Is this Coil really of any use?
Well, wait.
At the end of this report...
Coil warns us that we shouldn't
take L's existence lightly.
It says, "if you continue with
your current pace of killing. .
"For Yotsuba's benefit...
every week on Fridays and Saturdays. .
"I could possibly
connect you with Kira."
It's impressive that Coil has
figured out what we've been doing.
At any rate, we should stop killing...
every weekend.
This is amazing.
It's like they're confessing.
Yeah... As long as
we have this video,
we could probably arrest
all seven of them.
This is definitely bad...
Kira isn't very flexible either.
It would be nice if he killed
at various times during the week.
The fact that Coil noticed this,
makes it dangerous to
continue killing at our current pace.
From now on,
we should be even more careful
and make sure no one ever finds out.
Now, on to the main topic.
Who shall we kill?
We must stop E.L.F. Insurance
from expanding their business
into the Japanese market.
That will hurt not only Yotsuba,
but many other companies' customer base.
Agreed.
So, do we agree for these people
from E.L.F. to die by accidental deaths?
No objections.
What is this?
How can they do this so easily?
Another person is Santaro Zenzai,
a member of the Kugisawa Group.
He's protesting Yotsuba's plans
for the resort development.
Zenzai suffers from
high blood pressure.
So. . .it is possible t0 he ve him t0
die of a stroke at a designated time.
Is this all right?
No objections.
Kira. . .accidental death...
death by illness...
designated time of deaths.
It's as we thought.
There's no mistake.
No. Unfortunately, we can only say that
after those people they named die.
As long as we continue to monitor
what these seven say at their meetings,
their actions, and whether
the people they name die...
we'll definitely catch Kira.
Ryuzaki!
What is it?
Both of you in unison...
I can't go along with your idea!
- It's wrong!
- Yes!
Here it comes...
You seem to plan on catching Kira
by allowing these seven to continue
to murder, but I can't let them!
That's right. It's apparent that
these seven are committing murder!
Can't we prove it's them by
Matsuda's testimony and this footage?
This is problematic.
If we caught them now,
everything we've done until
now will go to waste.
So the E.L.F. will be
three weeks later.
We'll ask Kira to have Zenzai
killed this weekend.
Agreed?
No objections.
If it's this weekend,
there's not much time left!
Light, you know the cell phone numbers
of those seven, right?
Yeah.
Any one of them will do.
I'm going to call one of the seven
to try and stop the murders!
Please wait.
If we do that just three days
after Aiber's made contact with them,
we'll arouse suspicion that
our investigation is catching up to them.
It's also highly likely
that we won't be able to
determine who Kira is.
We've come this far,
and we'll have to start over again.
To catch Kira...
we need proof.
Ryuzaki, if Kira is among these seven,
isn't it fair to assume that
if we call one of them...
there's a one in seven chance that
that person is Kira?
At most, I would think there's
two of them.
So it's two out of seven...
If we're prepared to let them know
that the investigation is
catching up to them,
then let's risk it on those odds.
I'm going to borrow
the name Ryuzaki.
From the sound of the conversation...
the one who seems the least
likely to be Kira
and who carries some
weight on the board is...
- Ooi!
- Namikawa.
If you're going to make a call,
use this phone.
It can't be traced or tapped.
I really think it would
be faster if...
we killed the executives of
our rival companies one by one.
That would be going a bit far.
Let's kill them and
split their stocks.
You're Reiji Namikawa,
the V. P. of Yotsuba Group's
Sales Department One, aren't you?
Yes, I am...and?
Listen and respond as you see fit.
lam L.
I've planted cameras and wires
in that meeting room...
and I'm recording footage
of your entire meeting.
The opening topic
was Mr. Hatori's death.
Now you're deciding on who to kill.
Isn't that right?
He's been watching everything!
If you aren't Kira...
or if you aren't someone who
can directly contact Kira...
then let's make a deal.
A deal?!
Delay the death of E.L.F.'s president
and Mr. Zenzai one month.
This shouldn't be difficult for you.
- Yes, I see...
- If we want to randomize the deaths...
- Yes... Go on...
- just throw darts at a calendar.
If you do this,
and cooperate with us from now on,
your crime. . .no...
everyone other than
Kira will not be charged...
under the belief that they were
threatened by Kira
into participating in the meetings.
Ah...lsee...
My only option is join L.
No, I'll be killed if Kira finds out
that I've sided with L.
What should I do?
If you reveal this conversation,
it'll cause a panic.
There would be no advantage for you.
Everyone will be caught.
But my goal is to go
one-on-one against Kira.
Listen... If L wins against Kira,
you'll be acquitted.
If Kira wins against me,
you'll carry on with your luxurious life.
Or you can remain a spectator and
g0 along with either side.
Whoever wins, L or Kira,
it's no loss to you.
However, it would be a loss
to you if you were caught right now.
He already knows the answer
I would have given.
That's all...
Okay. On Monday...
What's wrong, Namikawa?
Who was it from?
Nothing, a subordinate of mine
messed up
and I'll have to fix it on Monday.
Sorry for interrupting.
Let's get back on topic.
Regarding on when we should kill
those E.L.F. guys and Zenzai.
How about this?
We give Coil one month
to discover L's identity.
If he doesn't, we'll be forced to
kill them at various dates.
Next, we'll give him another month
and repeat the process.
Once we've dealt with L,
we'll go back to two to
three people a week.
In other words, we should make
dealing with L our first priority.
I see...
Indeed. If we kill L,
we won't have anything in our way.
Until then, we should be careful...
Yeah... It sounds good to me.
Well, we've got to be
extremely careful.
Then we'll give Coil one month.
No objections.
L. . .that should satisfy you...
But we'll still hold these meetings
every week. That's all for now.
It went well...
Yeah...
You really are amazing, Light.
Not only did you delay the killing,
we may be able to get
information from Namikawa.
Furthermore, it looked like
something I would do...
You thought of it faster than I did.
At this rate...
If I die...
you could probably become
the successor to the "L" name...
Why are you talking about
such morbid things?
We have a month to figure out
Kira's identity
and gather evidence against him.
The challenge is just beginning.
Yes...
But you're the one who
first noticed Yotsuba.
You may be more capable than I am.
You might be able to do it.
If I die...
would you take over for me as L?
If I die, would you take over for me?
As L.
If this is all an act and he is Kira,
he's sure to say yes...
What are you talking about, Ryuzaki?
As long as we have this,
won't we die together?
I get it...
Sorry Ryuzaki...
I'm going to tell everyone
what you're thinking.
Ryuzaki thinks that if I'm Kira,
I'm eitherjust pretending I'm not him
and putting on an act...
or that Kira's power has been
passed to someone else...
...and I have no memory
that I was Kira.
One of those two possibilities.
If it's the first...
If I'm putting on an act,
these handcuffs will never come off.
No, even if it was
the other possibility,
he probably wouldn't take them off.
Ryuzaki thinks that I'm Kira.
Even if that power has been
passed to someone else...
he assumes that I would have
planned things
to have it return to me again.
In other words, he doesn't think
I was being controlled.
I passed the power on
and planned for it to come back
to me once I've been cleared.
Amazing... You figured out
exactly Wnaz' I was thinking.
Ryuzaki's line of reasoning is,
"Light will become Kira
once he steals L's position."
Correct.
To acquire the position of L...
and be able to freely control
the police,
while being Kira in secret...
would be the ultimate.
I could do that...no, I would do it.
That's what you meant, didn't you?
Yes.
But what about now?
You should know by now that
I'm probably not acting.
If you were acting and
trying to steal my position as L...
there's no way that you'd reveal
your plan in front of everyone.
Is that what you mean?
Ryuzaki...
Even if I capture the current Kira...
do you really think...
that I'd become Kira, a murderer?
Do I look like that kind of person?
That's what I think,
and that's how you look.
Not again...
Okay! Once is enough!
Let's just leave it as a draw!
Yeah...
Anyways, we have to catch the Kira
that's in front of our eyes.
As long as I have the handcuffs,
you shouldn't have any complaints.
I suppose so.
We only have a month.
- Ryuzaki. ..
- Yes?
If we can use
that meeting as evidence,
and capture the seven of them,
won't the murders of criminals stop?
Not again...
Unfortunately, no.
No?
We're not sure if Kira
is among those seven.
If they just have a connection to him,
Kira will simply kill them.
We have to be absolutely sure
that Kira is among them,
or there's no point in
catching them now.
Even if he is...
it's difficult to determine
who's Kira right now.
I think it's still too early.
But, if you can't say that
he's definitely among the seven...
there's still a chance that the murders
will stop if we arrest them.
It's like my dad says.
There is a chance.
Um, on second thought...
I think I'll go after Kira by myself.
You can use these headquarters,
as will I.
You can do things your way
and arrest them if you wish.
I shall investigate as
I wish in my own way.
We'll only get into arguments
if we don't.
Let's split up and act separately.
In other words, you just want to
figure out who Kira is, huh?
Yes. This case will never be solved
if we don't capture Kira.
I can't say that stopping
the deaths of a number of people
right before our eyes, is meaningless...
But if we don't find the truth,
Kira will appear again and
the victims will increase in the end.
That's why...
I think it's more important
to figure out who Kira is.
I'm opposed to arresting
the seven men,
if you want to do that,
then you take responsibility for it.
I will pursue Kira by myself.
We only have one month.
I wonder who will be faster?
Ryuzaki. .. Where are you going?
Amane's room.
Sorry, Light, I know
you're on your father's side, but...
I can't remove these handcuffs,
so you're going to have to come with me.
Light! Did we have a date today?
Along with Mr. Ryuzaki...
Misa...
Do you love Light?
Yes. . .very much.
But you also worship Kira.
Yes...
So who would you pick,
Light or Kira?
Light, of course.
What? I'm grateful to Kira
and want to meet him,
but that's not love.
Definitely Light.
Light wants to catch Kira.
Isn't that right, Light?
Yeah. Of course.
It seems he wants to catch him.
Now what'll you do?
If Light wants to catch him,
then I want Light to catch him.
So would you want to help
Light by working with him...
on the investigation?
Ryuzaki!
Yeah! I'll do anything for Light!
Wait a second.
What are you thinking?!
Aiber will pose as Eraldo Coil
and tell those seven men that...
he learned that Misa Amane might
be able to identify L.
And that L brought her in
for questioning
because he suspected that
she was the Second Kira.
Well, that £9 true.
If they know that Misa Amane
might know L...
they'll have her appear in
their commercials
and try to ask her about
various things.
Since Mr. Matsuda's screw up...
there were talks about using her
in their commercials.
Yeah. Yeah.
- That's no good.
- Why?
Because it would subject
you to danger.
Huh?! You're worried about me?
Yay!
But this is nothing if it's for you.
Listen, Misa, if they know that
you might know who L is...
we don't know what means they'll use
to get that information out of you.
It's all right. I won't say anything
under any kind of torture.
Yes. That is true...
Besides, Kira can control
his victims' actions before death.
There is a good chance that
he might try to get her
to talk and kill her.
No, if he kills L, then he won't have
any use for her and
Kira would kill Misa
to keep her silent.
I wouldn't like that...
Light.
If we win, Misa won't die.
Also...
as long as we're handcuffed,
we'll share the same fate.
If I die, you'll die too.
In that case, Misa is the one
who would grieve the most.
It's either we both die,
or we catch Kira.
Now which will you choose?
Catch Kira!
I can't live in a world without Light.
Yes, that's correct.
Hey, Ryuzaki, that's messed up.
We have no time.
I'm desperate.
Besides, Misa Amane's. ..
bravery and love for you...
are the greatest in the world.
Ryuzaki...
I think I've been wrong
about you all this time.
I called you a pervert and all...
You really do understand me!
Yes. Misa is the perfect,
most worthy woman for Light.
Yay!
Thank you, Ryuzaki.
I could fall in love with you,
you know.
Uh... That's a little...
How about being friends, Ryuzaki?
Yes. I've made another friend.
Yeah. All of Light's friends
are my friends.
Let's all be friends!
Ya y!
And I'll never betray
any of my friends.
With our powers combined,
let's arrest Kira!
No, but...
Yagami is taking a different
investigative approach from us
and will be working with
his father and the others.
You and I will be together, Misa.
Huh? What's up with that?
That was dirty, Ryuzaki.
Now my only choice is to
join your investigation...
No, that's quite all right.
What are you talking about?
Light will be joining us!
No, it's not like that...
I'm opposed to this investigation.
It's too dangerous for you.
Light...
Thank you for thinking about me.
But let me do this.
I want to be of use to you.
I want to be of use to you and
I want you to love me even more.
Plus, I...
would gladly die for you.
Right now, it will be difficult
to arrest the seven of them...
Mogi, Matsuda,
do you have any good ideas?
TO BE CONTINUED
This single page Forever depressing
A fleeting tactic in the eyes
Without petition evil against the law
chain it in prison
Poison the notebook fear the lust
Delusion of being deceived
perpetually drooling
Judgement is "crime control"
they drive/ed
Who has the Rx for that?
A decriminalized world
A sanctioned word
Taking in heat
Just like "Pirates of Death"
Atone with the game of laws
Billy in despair
Now, it's time for ethics
Now, the unstoppable Eraser Rain
Billy in despair
Now, it's time for ethics
Now, the unstoppable Eraser Rain
The unstoppable Eraser Rain
PREVIEW
Well, I am an actress.
Director Nishinaka,
Light and the others...
And now even the Shinigami's
asking me to act!
This is a lot of work.
It looks like I might be in
a big commercial. I am so popular!
NEXT EPISODE: PERFORMANCE