[theme music plays]
Quiet, Matsuda! This is not the time
to be fooling around. Knock it off.
Yes, sir.
This is the Kira investigation!
Stop messing around!
Sorry, Aizawa.
-[yelps]
-[L] Matsuda!
-I mean, please don't.
-Matsuda?
After all, the last thing I want
is to be dead weight.
Ryuzaki!
Is there anything I can do to help
with the investigation?
Besides the manager thing.
[L] Could you get me
another cup of coffee?
[gasps]
[snickering]
[Matsuda] I... I wanna help too!
I wanna contribute to the case!
MATSUDA
[romantic piano music playing]
I love you.
So please, don't tell me
you're going home now.
Instead, say you'll stay by my side.
Uh, Mr. Director? I can't do this.
I have a boyfriend.
-Can we cut the love scenes, please?
-[indistinct chatter from crew]
Wait! Where'd this come from
all of a sudden?
Can't we just fake kiss or something?
[director] What? You're kidding.
You can't expect us to make a movie
like that.
[Misa] If I say no, then it's no! Okay?
-[Matsuda sighs]
-[director] Hey, come on!
[indistinct chatter]
[Matsuda] The Yotsuba Group's
main Tokyo office...
And today is Friday.
All the deaths that are beneficial
for Yotsuba
are concentrated around the weekends.
[Matsuda] Hmm...
The last thing I want to be
is dead weight.
Mogi's been incredibly efficient
from the start.
Quiet, Matsuda! This is not the time
to be fooling around!
Would you cut it out?
Matsuda's special.
[L] Then, could you get me
another cup of coffee?
Matsuda!
[gasps]
[Matusda grunts]
NISHINAKA GROUP
Matsu! Hello? Matsu, get over here.
I guess he had to run off somewhere.
[Misa groans]
BADGE
RETURN SLOT
[sighs]
Alright, for the time being, I want you
to start going over this list, here.
Yes, sir. Right away.
[Light] Would I punish evil doers
and criminals if I could kill
by just seeing a name and face?
Is that what I'd do
if I had that sort of power?
I mean, it's true that there are lots
of people around
that the world could frankly do without,
but I don't think I'd become a murderer
-just to change the world.
-Huh?
Surely I wouldn't do that.
No, I'm thinking too hard about this.
There's no way anyone
could murder so many people
-and not have any memory of it.
-[L] What's wrong?
You've been staring at me
for the last two minutes.
Wait, let me guess. You must be annoyed
because I'm the only one eating cake
-at the moment, am I right?
-Uh, no, that's not it...
-Here.
-Really, don't worry about it.
-[monitor beeping]
-[Watari] Ryuzaki.
[L] Yes, what is it?
[Watari] Detective Eraldo Coil
has just received a private request
to investigate and reveal
the identity of L.
Isn't Eraldo Coil supposed to be
the second greatest detective in the world
after L himself?
Who on earth would send such a request?
[Watari] The man who sought out
Coil's services is Masahiko Kida,
the head of the Rights
and Planning Department
of the Yotsuba Group's headquarters
in Tokyo.
So it is Yotsuba!
We know that Yotsuba
must be linked to Kira.
If they're trying to find out
L's identity,
it's probably because they wanna kill him
and need that information to do it.
[Yagami] This isn't good.
We're already shorthanded enough as it is,
-and now we have to worry about Coil, too?
-[L] Mm...
It's quite all right.
The detective known as Eraldo Coil is me.
-[Yagami] Oh?
-[L] It's quite simple, really.
Three of the greatest detectives
in the world, L, Coil and Deneuve...
They're all actually me.
It's been my experience that people
who try to find me usually fall for this.
I'll give you this strawberry
if you keep it a secret, okay?
I'm impressed as always, Ryuzaki.
[elevator dings]
[Matsuda] Maybe I should leave
while I still have a chance.
No, then there would've been
no point in coming here.
Should I wait until everyone's gone
and search their offices?
I can't. I'd probably get caught
doing that, and then...
Maybe I should get out of here.
[sighs]
[Takahashi] Not this again!
I'm too tired.
Look on the bright side,
at least it falls on the weekend.
Might never know how long these
confidential meetings will go on for.
Can you imagine if we did this on Mondays?
That would be the worst start to the week.
[Matsuda] Confidential meetings?
All right!
[gasps]
[Matsuda] The nineteenth floor!
[grunting and panting]
I've made it this far!
I'm gonna see it through!
All right. I just have to get close
to him, right?
Leave it to me.
And you want me to make sure
that we're able to breach the security?
And override the surveillance cameras
in the Yotsuba Group's head office?
Is that all?
Yes. At this point, it's safe to assume
that Kira and the Yotsuba Group
are connected in some way.
We're going to investigate Yotsuba
to determine who holds Kira's power,
and if there is more than one person
who possesses this ability.
We need a clear understanding, quickly.
We cannot let anyone from Yotsuba
figure out that we are investigating them.
Please realize that if they do notice,
it means we won't be able to catch Kira.
[Matsuda] Damn it.
I can't hear them clearly.
If I could only hear just one thing.
Something important...
[muffled voices]
[man] Let's kill him!
[Matsuda] I just heard someone say "kill"!
[muffled voices]
[man] I'm sure Kira would agree...
[Matsuda] Kira! There it is!
Kira, they said it! What's that?
"Let's have Kira get rid of him"?
I heard it! They really are
working with him.
I did it! This is huge!
[grunting]
[man] Who the hell are you?
[L] Please be sure not to act impulsively
out of panic or haste.
And don't take matters
into your own hands.
-[monitor beeping]
-[Watari] Ryuzaki.
[L] Yes, what is it?
[Watari] I have just received
an emergency signal from Matsuda's belt.
Uh, where is he?
It seems that it's coming from within
the head office of the Yotsuba Group.
Sorry to barge in like this!
Uh, my name is Taro Matsui.
I'm an agent with Yoshida Productions!
I just dropped by to ask if your company
would be interested
in using our top multi-talented star,
Misa Amane, as your new spokesperson?
[laughs nervously]
[all] Hmm...
[L] Disregard everything I just said.
We'll need to rethink our strategy.
[sighs] Matsuda, you idiot!
Yoshida Productions. Taro Matsui.
He doesn't have anything
suspicious on him.
I suppose that means
he isn't a corporate spy.
[laughs] Right, um, so please,
take Misa-Misa into consideration.
These two are only acting as guards.
The rest of them must be discussing
how they'll get rid of me.
Oh, there's no way out of this.
I'm gonna be killed for sure.
I wonder if the emergency signal
got through.
Never mind that. Even if it did,
will Ryuzaki come and save me?
Oh, no. What's gonna happen?
[phone ringing]
[Shimura] Go ahead. You can answer it.
Don't say that you're here, though.
And hold it away from your ear.
Make sure we can listen in
on the conversation.
Okay.
Hello?
[L] Yo, Matsui!
[Matsuda] Ryuzaki! [gasps]
[L] It's me, Asahi.
It's been a while, buddy!
[Matsuda] Asahi!
Yeah, it's been a long time.
[chuckling] Doesn't sound
like you're out right now.
Don't tell me you're home already?
[Matsuda] Yeah...
So, you by yourself?
Yeah. I'm by myself. What's up?
He's not with Misa Amane right now.
Matsuda must be on his alone.
[all] Mm-hm.
So, do you wanna, like,
go out drinking tonight?
[Matsuda] Huh? Right now?
Oh, sorry. I'll have to pass tonight.
Oh, what's the matter?
Don't tell me your wallet
is in trouble again?
[Matsuda] In trouble!
Yeah, that's right.
Big troubles with money.
You know me way too well.
[laughs nervously]
Matsuda's saying he's in big trouble.
Oh, that's too bad. Guess I'll drag
you out some other time, all right?
See ya, buddy. [hangs up]
Uh...
Anyway, what do you think
about contracting Misa-Misa?
I think she'd be a great spokesperson
for your company.
[both] Hmm...
If you're gonna promote
one of your clients,
shouldn't you at least
bring them with you?
Do you expect us to believe
you're this girl's manager?
Well, to be honest, at the moment
she's filming a movie nearby.
Once she's finished,
I'll call her and get her over here.
Then you can see why she'd make
a great spokesperson!
I have to keep stalling them somehow!
Misa's cellphone is on voicemail
right now.
I left her a message and told her
to get back to me as soon as she can.
What are you planning to do, Ryuzaki?
[L] Well…
We have to consider that if Matsuda dies,
our suspicions about the Yotsuba Group
would be confirmed.
[all] Hmm...
Let's just watch the situation
for the time being.
What should we do?
The main question is whether
he heard anything.
[Higuchi] If it's a possibility,
no matter how small,
we'll have to kill him.
I'm wondering if he really did
come here just to promote his client?
He could be an undercover cop.
No, that can't be it.
The Japanese police have completely
withdrawn support from the Kira case.
Look, it doesn't really matter who he is.
We have no choice but to kill him.
Hmm...
You know, now that I think about it,
it might be good to have her
-as the face of our company.
-Huh?
[gasps]
Exactly. Her shoot should be done soon,
so please wait. She'll convince you.
[yawning] I'm beat.
[sighs]
[gasps] I got a call from Light!
He really does worry about me
when I'm late. [chuckles]
[phone ringing]
Misa?
[Misa] Light! I'm sorry I've been
working so much.
I'll be finished soon, 'kay?
Misa, you're not with Matsuda
at the moment, are you?
Him? He's a total jerk!
He just ran off and left me here...
-[phone ringing]
-Oh!
Hang on, I'm getting a call
on my work phone.
Oh hey, it's from Matsu.
Misa's just received a call from Matsuda.
Tell her to hold her phone
so that we can listen in as well.
[Matsuda] Misa-Misa,
when you're finished filming,
come over
to the Yotsuba Group head office.
It's still tentative,
but there's a chance
you may be able to appear
in Yotsuba's commercials!
We're working it out now.
What? For real? You're amazing, Matsu!
So that's what you've been up to
all this time?
Don't worry, we're wrapping up soon.
[Matsuda]
Great, it's just a short trip by taxi.
Huh?
Listen to me, Light. There is a chance
that we may be able to save Matsuda.
But we won't be able to do it
without Misa's help.
She'll listen to you and do anything
you say, won't she?
[both gasp]
I'm Misa-Misa!
My only rule is I don't do nudes,
but swimsuits and lingerie
are totally okay!
It's really nice to meet you.
[laughs nervously]
Hmm. I gotta admit,
she is really cute in person.
That's not exactly the main issue now,
wouldn't you agree?
By the way, Matsu,
since Yotsuba's a big catch,
I got the okay from our office
to have a special reception.
-Hmm? Reception?
-[chuckles]
[all] Good evening!
We're very pleased to meet you!
Tonight, I'll be entertaining you
as our special guests,
along with the girls from the agency.
Hey. Is it just me,
or is this getting weird?
Hmm, well, it can't be helped.
-[Matsuda laughs nervously]
-Right now, we can't afford to leave
Misa's manager alone for a second.
Let's just go with it.
I'm gonna enjoy myself.
-[all mumbling]
-[man] Right. Hard to go wrong with this.
[laughs nervously]
[Matusda] Ryuzaki and the others
will be able to watch us from here.
This is my way out.
-[can opening]
-[chatter and laughter]
[Misa] Here you are! Drink right up.
[chuckles]
[man] Man, we gotta do this more often.
Hmm. Well, well.
Misa's pretty good at this sort of thing.
[chatter continues]
[laughs nervously]
[Matsuda] Excuse me, guys.
I gotta go to the bathroom.
Ryuzaki, are you watching this?
-Yes.
-Look, I'm really sorry that--
That's not important right now.
Okay. Listen, the eight men who came here
were having a meeting to determine
who they'd get Kira to kill for them.
[all gasp]
I heard them say it clearly.
There's no doubt they're behind this.
Yes, that is probably true.
But if you did overhear them
and they caught you,
then they'll almost certainly be trying
to kill you now.
[sighs] I know.
Do you think there's anything I can do
to save myself?
[L] Well, luckily, you're still alive,
so we may be able to save you.
But for that to happen...
you will have to die
before they can kill you.
What?
[L] I want you to listen
to me very carefully.
[Matsuda groans]
No way...
But that's... that's crazy!
[indistinct chatter]
And you know, our company is expanding.
[everyone gasping]
What the hell?
Wow! I am so drunk!
[Matsuda groaning]
Oh... hi, everyone! Everyone having fun?
Good. That's great.
Now, everyone, the moment
you've all been waiting for!
The Taro Matsui show! [laughing]
[man] Hey, what are you doing?
Yay! You can do it! Go, Matsu!
All right! Here we go.
Hey, you're drunk!
That's way too dangerous.
Don't worry. I'm just fine.
I do this all the time. [grunting]
[everyone gasping]
-[Kida] The hell is he doing?
-[Takahashi] Get in here, come on!
-[Hatori] Are you crazy, you idiot?
-[Matsuda] It's all right! No prob...
[screaming]
[Yagami grunts]
[thudding]
[gasping and screaming]
He fell!
[Mido] This can't be good.
[screams] No!
I heard a thud, so I came out.
This is just horrible!
-Someone call an ambulance!
-[Aiber] Geez. This sure is a crappy role.
Look, everyone.
I think you should all just leave this
for us to take care of and go home.
-What? But--
-Don't worry. We'll handle it.
Just don't forget about me
for your next campaign, okay?
Let's go. If the press sees us,
we're in trouble.
[man] Yeah.
[sirens wailing]
[woman] What's going on?
Did someone jump?
Well, we're lucky that he ended up dying
right in front of us, at any rate.
-Hey.
-[ambulance door slams]
[chuckles]
While I'm aware of the fact
that we're shorthanded,
I'm not very pleased about having
to do this sort of thing myself.
Matsuda, you idiot.
[sighs]
"Misa Amane's manager dies in fall."
Hmm...
[phone ringing]
UNKNOWN NUMBER
[Kida] Yes?
[man] You're Masahiko Kida,
VP of the Rights and Planning Department
at Yotsuba's Tokyo office, correct?
[Kida] Yes, that's right,
and who am I speaking to?
I go by the name Eraldo Coil.
I'm calling to discuss my terms with you.
[Kida gasps]
[Ooi]
What? A two-million-dollar advance
and eight million upon completion?
Is he out of his mind?
That's not all.
Even if we don't commission him,
we have to pay him two million
just to keep him silent.
So, he wants hush money, huh?
If he's saying something like that,
we should assume Coil knows
quite a bit already.
This is getting ridiculous. I've had it!
I want out of these meetings right now!
I don't know who Kira is
and I don't care.
I just don't wanna get wrapped up
in this and end up in jail!
-[Higuchi] No.
-Huh?
[Higuchi] Hatori...
I think you're going to end up
dead tomorrow.
No, wait! I was only joking!
It's not like that!
I'm in. I'll see this to the end.
So what are we going to do?
Coil is still willing to accept the job
despite what he already knows.
Isn't is obvious? He'll become partners
with us as long as we pay him.
His demands are exorbitant,
but we need to have someone
as skilled as Coil on our side.
Good point. Pay him.
It doesn't matter how much.
Exactly, we'll just have to pay him.
[Ooi] All right, we'll contract Coil.
Anyone have any objections?
[all] No objections.
[Wedy] L, are you listening?
[sighs] I'm so disappointed.
I thought this would be a challenge.
Security level here is a joke.
They've left it all
to a single contractor.
There weren't even any
wiretap detectors.
It's been about a week since I first
snuck into the place.
It looks like things have been moving
pretty smoothly since then, huh?
We've almost got them.
So, one of these people...
is Kira.
[Ooi] Well, then,
now that everyone's here,
let's commence our regular meeting.
[Yagami] But if they're supposed
to be eight, why are there only seven?
TO BE CONTINUED
[theme music plays]