[theme music plays]
OVERCAST
[Light] Regardless of how she came
to the conclusion,
the fact remains
this woman knows the truth.
If she gives this information
to the police,
it won't take them very long
to figure out that Kira is actually me.
I have no choice but to eliminate her.
[Naomi] Something wrong?
[Light] Oh, it's nothing.
But the more I think about it,
the more your theory makes sense to me.
We can't waste any time.
We need to start investigating it
right away.
What? Really? Do you mean that?
Yes.
So, have you told anyone else about this?
No, you're the first person I've told.
[Ryuk chuckles]
You're lucky.
But how will you get rid of her?
It's not like you can do it here.
[Light] Well, you have a gift
for stating the obvious, Ryuk.
Oh, aren't you bold?
Let's get started.
Could you please tell me the date and time
of the bus-jacking incident?
It was December 20th,
in front of Asagao Hill.
At 11:02 a.m., bound for Space Land.
December 20th, and they were
on their way to Space Land.
[Naomi] Yes.
SHOKO MAKI
SUICIDE JANUARY 1, 2007
Commits suicide in such a way
that nobody will be inconvenienced,
and her body will not be discovered.
Dies by implementing this plan
within 48 hours.
[Light] This way,
no one will find her body.
And even if they do, they'll just assume
that the death of her fiancé
drove her to commit suicide.
[Ryuk chuckling]
[Light] What's so funny, Ryuk?
[Ryuk laughs maniacally]
[L] I apologize for questioning
all of you like that,
but I'm afraid I had no other choice.
I've determined that Kira is not among us.
[all sighing in relief]
Ryuzaki, how can you be certain
that we're all innocent?
Well, to be honest, from the beginning,
I set a number of traps
that would reveal if any of you was Kira.
But after speaking with you one on one,
I don't feel the need.
[all sighing]
[phone ringing]
Excuse me.
Unbelievable. He tells us
to turn off our cellphones...
Understood.
I'm just about finished here anyway.
You've got the key, so let yourself in.
Watari is on his way.
[all gasping]
So, that's everything.
I'd like to report this incident
to my father.
If it's okay with you, that is.
Well, if it's all the same,
I think I'd like to report it myself.
And after talking to you,
I've decided that it would be best
to do it as soon as possible.
[Light] Uh, that makes sense.
Just ten seconds until 1:15…
I have to admit,
I'd really love to see how she dies.
But I can't be caught
following her around.
Go on, hurry to your death!
[ticking]
[clock ticking]
[Naomi] Kira will definitely be caught.
Don't you think?
Huh?
[ticking]
What's going on?
It should have happened already.
This doesn't make sense.
I don't understand why she's not leaving.
SUICIDE
I've had no problems making people
kill themselves in the past.
All I had to do is
write the word "suicide."
The criminals I tested it on
all hung themselves
exactly when I specified.
My experiments indicate
that in a situation like this,
I should be able to control
a person's actions.
So, what's wrong?
[Ryuk laughing]
[Light] Ryuk…
He laughed just like that
when I was writing in the Death Note.
[Light] And that's not all.
I remember thinking it was bizarre
how he laughed when I asked for her name.
In fact, he's reacted the same way
every time her name comes up.
An alias!
[all gasping]
Gentlemen,
it's an honor to meet all of you.
This person is Watari?
Hm. What about your usual outfit?
If I dressed like that, I'd be announcing
to the world that I am Watari.
That's all it takes to give away
the location of our headquarters
and Ryuzaki.
Oh, I see.
Ordinarily, I would never show my face
to any of you.
The fact that I'm here is proof
that you've won Ryuzaki's trust.
Now that you mention it,
I do feel honored.
[nervous laughter]
Well then, I've brought those items
you requested.
It's all here.
Could you please pass them out
to everyone?
[Watari] Yes.
[Watari] Gentlemen,
these are your new police IDs.
-[all] Huh?
-But what for?
[Light] She used an alias,
that has to be it!
But Ryuk knew all along.
He could see her real name with his eyes.
That's why he wouldn't stop laughing.
I should've known.
She's been overly cautious
from the beginning.
I see. It makes a lot of sense.
She believes that Raye died
because he showed his ID to Kira.
So, of course she'd be careful
not to reveal her own identity.
Oh, this isn't good.
It's gonna be almost impossible
to ask for her real name
knowing she gave me an alias
the first time.
If I'm too persistent,
she'll get suspicious.
What am I saying?
It looks suspicious that I even knew
she was using an alias.
-I should probably be getting back soon.
-Hmm?
Someone from the Task Force
might be back there by now.
[Light] Oh, yeah, you could be right.
Let's cross our fingers
and hope someone's there.
Yeah.
Damn it! I'm running out of options here.
I have to stop this before it's too late.
Oh, no. What if my father calls back now?
I already promised her
that I'd let her talk to him if he did.
If this phone rings, it's all over for me.
What am I gonna do?
This is crazy. All I have to do
is turn my cellphone off.
-[phone beeps]
-[Light] Problem solved.
Now, calm down.
You know what needs to be done.
Just find out her real name.
Her purse, her pockets...
She's got to have a driver's license
or some sort of personal identification
on her somewhere.
She's a woman, after all.
I suppose if I had to, I could use force.
No, no, the last thing I want to do
is make a scene in public.
I've got to get her somewhere isolated.
But where?
And what explanation could I give her?
It would never work. She's too careful.
I need a better approach.
I can do this.
I'm going to convince her
to give me her real name.
[Ryuk laughs]
Hey, Light, you know,
that deal I mentioned is still open.
It's just like putting on contact lenses.
Completely painless.
Would I be willing to give up half my life
just so I can learn
this woman's real name?
No, I wouldn't.
In fact, it's not even worth considering.
Now quit wasting my time.
Just shut your mouth, Shinigami.
-Excuse me.
-Yes?
Uh, do you still have business
at the police station then?
I'd like to go there by myself,
if you don't mind.
Yeah, no problem.
[Soichiro] Our names and ranks are false.
[Matsuda] Why did you give us fake IDs?
As you know, Kira requires
a name and a face to kill.
[L slurps, gulps]
We will confront him
with that premise in mind.
And I think it should be obvious why.
Yes, but of all people,
the police shouldn't use fake IDs.
Enough. What choice do we really have,
given the capabilities of our enemy?
As long as you're working on this case,
I think we're going to need
all the protection one can get.
It would be foolish not to use them.
-Yeah. You've got a good point.
-Uh-huh.
Remember, any time you're in a situation
where you have to give out your name
to a stranger,
make sure to use the name
from your fake ID. Understood?
-Hmm.
-Right.
And be careful not to take them out while
in the presence of other police officers.
I'm sure I don't need to tell you.
That could cause problems for us.
-I understand.
-[men grunting in approval]
[Watari] Very well, then.
I'd like to request
that you wear these at all times.
Uh, belts?
Each one has a transmitter
hidden in the buckle.
This will allow Ryuzaki
to monitor your whereabouts.
And when you press the buckle
twice like this...
[phone ringing]
...my cellphone will ring,
displaying your name.
And I'll call you back immediately,
but you won't see my number displayed.
In the morning, all of you will go
to the police station as usual.
Then, later on in the day,
we'll use this method to confirm the name
of Ryuzaki's hotel and his room number.
Please use this for emergencies as well.
No way! This is totally cool.
I feel like some kind of secret agent
going after Kira!
Quiet, Matsuda!
This is not the time to be fooling around.
-Knock it off!
-Yes, sir.
Thank you so much
for everything you've done, Light.
After talking to you, I feel
much more confident about my theory.
Not at all.
Considering that Ryuk mentioned
that eye deal again,
there's no doubt in my mind
that she used an alias.
At this rate, once she goes to the police
with her theory about Kira
being on that bus,
and they look at all the people
Raye Penber was investigating,
it won't take them long to zero in on me.
[Ryuk chuckles]
Hey, she's leaving. So now what?
I've got about five minutes
before that woman
gets to police headquarters.
Think!
I need her real name,
and I don't have much time to spare.
[Light] If this woman makes it
to the police station
and someone from the Task Force
has returned by then,
it'll all be over for me.
I've got to find out her real name
and eliminate her quickly.
Only three minutes left
until she reaches the station.
All right.
Oh? Whatcha doing?
-Excuse me.
-Yes?
There's something
that I should probably tell you.
Okay.
The thing is, it'll be impossible for you
to contact anyone
from the Task Force directly.
Huh?
[Light] That's right.
Keep the conversation going.
I just need to find something
that she can latch onto and I've got her.
Once she's comfortable,
then I can get her real name.
I can do this.
I can't contact anyone? But why not?
Didn't you think it odd that there
was no one at Task Force headquarters?
Uh, yeah.
I did find it a bit strange,
but I didn't...
Let me explain.
The Task Force has been organized
so that its members can't be identified
if nobody on the outside knows
who's in charge.
Hmm.
If the members' names
were ever made public
or the structure of the Task Force
was revealed,
we'd likely see another tragedy
along the lines of the one
that claimed your fiancé's life.
I see.
[Light] That's why you were told earlier
that no one was
at Task Force headquarters.
What I'm trying to say is,
you'll never be able to talk to someone
directly from the Task Force
because the police simply won't allow it.
[Ryuk chuckles]
That's pretty clever. I'm impressed.
If this is supposed to be a secret,
then how do you know so much?
Guess I spoke too soon. She's sharp.
Very well. You leave me no choice.
It's because I'm actually a member
of the Task Force.
[Ryuk] Huh?
I'm sorry, you're telling me
that you're an agent?
Yes. L is currently in charge
of the Task Force,
and he's leading our investigation.
Yes. To be honest,
I already suspected that.
He was concerned that the Task Force
had become too small.
Many detectives had quit,
fearing for their lives. And so...
despite the fact
that I'm a high school student,
he brought me on board
to help out with the investigation.
After all, I've helped them solve cases
in the past.
So, L trusts you then?
I can go to Task Force headquarters
whenever it suits me
and I'm allowed to investigate freely
as I see fit.
You see, these days, the Task Force
is made up of a chosen few,
an elite group of people
handpicked for the job by L.
All are highly skilled, well respected,
and above all, trustworthy.
[gasps]
[Ryuk laughs]
Thanks for explaining.
But just to be safe,
I'd like to try and visit
the Task Force headquarters again.
-Huh?
-Goodbye.
Please, wait a second!
It's like I just told you.
They won't let you talk to anyone.
[Naomi] I know, but I was hoping
I could speak with L directly.
Oh, and come to think of it,
who's at the police station right now?
Actually, no one's there at the moment.
That's not good news.
We need someone there at all times.
Work in shifts if you have to.
I understand. Aizawa,
I'll put you in charge of that for today.
Yes, sir. I'm on my way.
Won't take me long.
Ms. Maki, please wait a second.
It's literally impossible to meet L.
This is pointless.
You may be right.
But I think there's a chance
that he'll meet with me.
[Naomi] Although the only contact
I've had with him
was following orders through a computer.
He might remember who I am.
You see, I worked under him
in a case in the US about two years ago.
Are you serious? You worked under L?
Yes, I didn't tell you this, but...
up until three months ago,
I worked as an FBI agent.
This is it. Finally something I can use.
Guess I shouldn't be surprised.
In fact, I noticed early on
that your investigative skills
were far beyond those of an amateur.
You're very cautious
and you seem to have a gift
for getting to the heart of the matter.
If I could, I'd like to learn from you.
[Ryuk laughs]
One lie after another.
You make it look easy.
From the beginning, I knew I had
to do things outside the regular channels
because from my perspective,
both the police and the members
of the Task Force were suspects.
But I'm certain that I can trust L.
Maybe it's unrealistic,
but I think that if I go to headquarters
and I give them my name,
there's a chance that they'll let me
speak with him directly.
I see…
But if the only person you could trust
with this info was L, then why me?
I suppose I was upset
that they wouldn't allow me
to see anyone from the Task Force.
And then you came along,
claiming to be the son
of the lead detective and...
No, that's not it.
[Naomi] I'll be honest with you.
It's because you remind me of L.
There's something about you
that's just like him.
Hmm.
-Will you investigate this case with me?
-Huh?
I want you to come work with us
as part of the Task Force.
We could use your help.
[Light] As I'm sure you know,
not just anyone can do it.
Please, I know this is sudden
but the team needs people like you.
I'm serious.
You could be doing so much more
than gathering information on your own.
You have all the experience
as an FBI agent.
You're more talented
than most of the detectives
currently on the Task Force.
And L obviously trusted you in the past.
It wouldn't be that difficult
for you to join.
All you'd need
is some valid identification,
a recommendation
from a current Task Force member,
and, of course,
you'd need to get L's permission.
You want me to join the Task Force?
I can't help but think
that it must be fate that I met you today.
I'd like to be the one to recommend you.
Oh, I'm sorry about that.
-I guess I got a little bit too excited.
-It's okay.
I mean, even if you acted
as a consultant on this investigation,
it would be a great help.
I'm sure you have personal obligations
to attend to.
Not to mention the fact
that you live in the United States.
It's true. Before all this happened,
I thought I'd continue living in America
with my fiancé.
We'd planned on getting married
in the spring.
But now he's gone,
so I'm not sure what to do anymore.
All right. I've come this far.
All she needs is a little encouragement.
But you're young and beautiful,
and you've got your life ahead of you.
Why put it all in danger for this?
No! Now that Raye's gone,
I've got nothing to lose anymore.
I want to catch Kira!
I don't care about anything else.
It's all I want to do.
Please let me investigate this case
with you.
Huh?
[Ryuk laughs maniacally]
Yes, of course.
I just need to see some form
of identification before we proceed.
-Oh, um...
-Yes?
You see, the name
I gave you earlier, well...
it wasn't actually my real name.
I'm so sorry.
Don't worry, it's all right.
To be honest, I'm impressed
by how incredibly thorough you've been.
You've stayed one step ahead of me.
But I suppose that's just further proof
of your capabilities.
So will a Japanese driver's license
do the trick then?
Sure.
[Light] I made it in time.
NAOMI MISORA
DATE OF BIRTH: 2/11/1979
SUICIDE 1/1/2007
Uh, so, if you don't mind my asking,
why do you keep checking your watch?
Oh, well...
I guess it's because…
Because I'm Kira.
[gasps]
[ticking]
What's the matter?
[Naomi] There's something I have to do.
Hmm.
My father's cellphone
might be available now.
Do you wanna see
if you can talk to him?
[Naomi] No, thank you.
I have nothing to say to him.
Then, goodbye, Naomi Misora.
TO BE CONTINUED
[theme music plays]