Easy easy banzai Easy easy banzai
Easy easy banzai Human
Wanna get them mad? Get them mad?
Get them mad? People
What's up? Full of causes for concern
Crime won't disappear Forever
(play a trick on resentment Who's down?)
What's up? Full of causes for concern
Crime won't disappear Forever
Hey Hey! A hymn to humanity
Love has gone People, are you worried?
Hey Hey! Subservient People! !
WHAT'S UP, PEOPLE?! !
Are you worried?
It's been a while.
Thank you for taking care
of my father.
S-Sayu. . .You've grown up...
This is Yagami.
Mr. Deputy Director?
About the trade of the director
for the notebook...
- lfis canceled
- What?!
We'll now trade the notebook...
for Sayu Yagami.
At any rate, bring the notebook
to Los Angeles,
by yourself in two days.
Nice to meet you, L Number Two.
I am the center of SPK...
Let's see, call me...N
N? Is he joking?
But what is this. . .strange feeling?
IMPATIENCE
N... He's similar...
This feeling. . .is like L...
I said we will
no longer rely on L...
That means,
my orders to the CIA and FBI
will be given priority over L's.
However, the murder of
the Director of the NPA
is an unforgivable crime...
I think there is a possibility
that this case could lead
to the arrest of Kira...
So I will lend you my full support.
"Lead to the arrest of Kira?"
Who does he think he is?
This confidence...
What's wrong, L?
N-Nothing.
Actually, after the director
was murdered...
Deputy Director Yagami's daughter
was kidnapped by someone...
who we believe to be the same person
who killed the director.
They contacted us to make
a deal in Los Angeles.
A deal? In exchange for
the notebook, right?
That's right.
I understand.
I'll gather as many investigators as I can
in Los Angeles
without telling them the details...
And use a satellite to
monitor the L.A. area.
No...
I'll let you have
total authority on this, L.
Thank goodness.
We make the decisions.
But what was that about the Americans
not trusting L anymore?
Near, are you sure about leaving
this to a fake L
who hasn't succeeded
in catching Kira?
So much the better.
It means that there's a chance
we can take advantage of him.
Of course, peoples' lives
are our first priority.
But as the SPK, our goal is...simply...
to get the notebook and capture Kira.
Light...
I don't care if it costs me my life.
Please. . .just save Sayu...
Don't say things like that!
You may be satisfied with that...
but do you know how painful it would be
for everyone you'd leave behind?!
You cannot die in front of Sayu.
You may lose contact with me.
So if you ever come across
a situation where you have to
make a decision by yourself...
do whatever you need to do to
make sure that both you and Sayu live.
Promise me that.
Light...
What? No way!
I can really go with you?!
Yeah. I may need your eyes
this time.
All right!
Thank you!
I've got to start packing immediately!
I can't decide...
Hey, Light...
Which one do you like?
If things get bad,
I'll have to kill Sayu...
Dad, I'll go on ahead to Los Angeles
and make preparations.
Mr. lde and the rest of you,
please come after us.
We'll take different planes.
So just in case, Mr. Aizawa...
will follow my father and ride
the same plane as him.
All right.
As a disguise,
I'll cut my hair.
Okay everyone, I'm counting on you.
Mr. Yagami.
What is it?
Are you one of the kidnappers?
You will take flight SE333.
I have your ticket.
Hurry. It's Gate 18.
All right.
A man has intercepted him at Narita!
Should I arrest him?
Mr. Aizawa, calm down.
It won't do us any good
if you arrest him right now.
Just don't lose sight of him.
Oh, no.
The Deputy Director just got on
a different flight with that man
than the one
he was supposed to catch...
This is an emergency.
- I'm going to get on as a police officer...
- Calm down, Mr. A/zawa/
If you do that and they find out
it will blow everything.
Do you know where it's going?
Umm... Oh...
It's going to Los Angeles too.
Impossible, they even have a plane?
This is bad...
Flight SE333, Flight SE333,
can you hear me?!
You are veering off course!
This is Flight SE333,
I hear you loud and clear.
We are not off course.
I changed course.
W-What are you talking about?
What's wrong? Are you joking?
This is not a hijacking.
We're just going to take a little detour
to drop off a passenger.
Feel free to track me by radar.
But if you do anything
to interfere...
I will not hesitate to crash this plane
and take all the passengers with me.
Light... I mean, L.
The plane that
the Deputy Director is on
has veered off course
from Los Angeles.
Someone's going to be
dropped off somewhere...
It's probably the Deputy Director...
Damn it! What's going on?!
I checked the flight crew
ahead of time.
There wasn't anyone suspicious.
The pilot is a veteran of
over fifteen years.
There's no problem with
the co-pilot, either.
So the enemy is powerful enough to
control ordinary people like them.
Damn it. I've got no choice...
Director, this is L. Get me N...
Yes.
N, I think you know the situation.
Can you notify the airlines, police
and military not to make a move yet?
What is L doing? How unreliable...
All right...L.
We'll figure out where he'll land...
and keep surveillance over
the area by satellite.
If there's anything else we can do,
please let me know.
Take this PDA...
Place the wireless earphone
in your ear.
Yagami, only you can hear my voice.
Listen closely.
I'm the one who kidnapped
your daughter.
I have no interest in the lives
of you or your daughter.
Right now,
the only thing I want is...
just the notebook.
If you do as I say,
I won't kill either of you.
I've even arranged
an exchange procedure
that you'll be satisfied with.
Do not fight me.
I am trading the killer notebook
for my daughter's life
with an unknown person...
When the time comes,
what do I do?
As a police of fiber. ..
as a human being. . .as a parent...
L, we have pinpointed
where they have landed
with our satellites.
I'll send you footage
of what we're seeing.
Dad!
What's going on?
How is he supposed to make
the exchange there?
You see it, don't you, Yagami?
Enter there.
Underground, huh?
This is interesting...
Damn it. Underground, huh?
That means he predicted that
there 'd be satellite surveillance...
Now I can't watch him...
It's bulletproof glass. You understand.
A certain syndicate used this place
up until a few years ago...
to make shady deals.
We've made some modifications.
Slide the notebook through here.
When you slide it in,
I'll release this handle.
We'll step back and
spin the glass door.
The notebook will
be passed this way
and your daughter, to you.
If you don't go through with the trade,
I'll shoot your daughter from here...
L, do you have a plan?
Or do you really think it's all right
to let the notebook fall into the
hands of someone you don't know?
Y462, begin.
Now open the notebook
and slide it into...
the slot in the glass door
to the left.
Damn it.
I'm being set back even further...
I've just arrived in L.A.
and I'm not in any situation
to be giving orders to the police
agencies around the world as L...
At this rate. . .the notebook will...
Light, what's wrong?
Are you all right? You're pale...
Misa, shut up and just do as I say!
I want you to take more care than usual
in killing the criminals in Japan.
He's investigating Kira.
You know something bad
will happen
if the punishing gets delayed,
don't you?
Okay... But who's "he"?
Just do as I say!
You're just taking out
your anger on her.
I-I can still make it...
At this rate,
is my only option to kill Sayu?
All right, I'm going to
test the out notebook.
"Test out?!"
Are you going to kill someone?!
- That's...
- Hey, hey...
We can't trade
without testing it out.
Do you want
your daughter to die?
This is not good!
Only the police
know about this case.
I can't blame
Sayu's death on Kira...
What's wrong?!
Are you all right, Miller?!
That's what you get when you steal and
sell our drugs behind my back.
He was worthless,
but this is the first time
he's been useful.
Y462, the target is dead.
It seems the notebook is real.
Now let go.
We'll exchange it for your daughter.
Sayu. .. Dad...
Oh, they've been saved.
The perpetrator is headed
for a helicopter.
We can assume that
that's his means of escape.
This means that the notebook
was definitely exchanged.
We still don't know
what may happen next.
Follow their helicopter the best
you can until it lands.
Don't let it out of
your satellite's view...
You sure give difficult orders easily.
All right. I'll try my best...
We can't. We've been tricked, L.
A missile?!
That's a type that
can't be tracked by radar.
The notebook is on a missile?
The missile's been launched!
The helicopter or the missile?
Which one is the notebook on?
Boss, I'm sure you were watching.
I did everything as
you told me perfectly.
Yeah, good job.
So now my past mistakes
will be wiped clean, right?
Yeah, I'll wipe them clean...
Do it!
Near, the helicopter has...
I thought so...
This means that the notebook
was definitely on the missile!
The missile can't be tracked!
I've completely lost sight
of the target...
It won't be difficult
to retrieve the missile
if it falls in
an unpopulated area.
He should be getting his hands on
the notebook right about now...
When he does, I have a good idea
of Whaz' he 'll do flfsz'.
L.
Yes?
They got us.
"Got" You?
Yes.
Most of the members of the SPK
have been killed.
L... You helplessly handed over
the notebook.
N... Are you saying that if
you were in command
that you wouldn't have
handed it over?
No, with that kind of preparation,
it would have been taken either way.
There's no point in us quarreling.
Let's help each other and
tell each other what we know.
I have some idea of who
the culprit may be.
I think a person who goes by
the name Mello is behind this.
The name... Mello...?
I don't have his photograph and
I don't know his real name.
I only know that until four years ago
he was at an orphanage...
called Wammy's House
in Winchester, England...
Wammy's House?
That was the institution
Watari established...
I think that Mello is playing
a game with me.
To see who can catch the last boss,
Kira, the fastest...
Armo Justin...
It's Armonia Justin.
I went to the old man, the king,
to report that I lost my notebook,
but when I described
what it looked like...
he said that Ryuk said it was his and
that he dropped it, and took it...
What should I do in this case?
In this case, you've got to
get it back from Ryuk.
I thought so...
So I have to...
go the Human world, huh?
Yeah, seems like you have to go...
I see...
TO BE CONTINUED
This single page Forever depressing
A fleeting tactic in the eyes
Without petition evil against the law
chain it in prison
Poison the notebook fear the lust
Delusion of being deceived
perpetually drooling
Judgement is "crime control"
they drive/ed
Who has the Rx for that?
A decriminalized world
A sanctioned word
Taking in heat
Just like "Pirates of Death"
Atone with the game of laws
Billy in despair
Now, it's time for ethics
Now, the unstoppable Eraser Rain
Billy in despair
Now, it's time for ethics
Now, the unstoppable Eraser Rain
The unstoppable Eraser Rain
PREVIEW
Please calm down and listen.
On November 10, 23:59,
all of the Mafia will die.
This moment is your best chance
to get back the notebook.
NEXT EPISODE: FATHER