[theme music plays]
[kids playing and shouting]
[child crying]
-[child crying loudly]
-[rattling]
-[child continues crying]
-[rattling continues]
[child screams]
[bell tolls]
[rattling and crackling]
Ryuzaki, is something the matter?
What is it?
Hmm?
What's wrong?
SILENCE
Hmm... Interesting.
A corner of a page of this notebook
has been torn off.
Can you kill someone
just by writing their name on a piece?
Can't say.
I've never tried using it like that,
and I don't know of anyone who has.
Then let me ask you,
do Gods of Death love apples?
Not necessarily.
You see, our internal organs
have already degraded.
We've evolved
to a point where we
do not require sustenance.
[smacks] Say, Light.
You're finally free to leave headquarters
on your own,
but it seems like you never go out.
Even when Misa comes to visit,
you only chat with her
for a few minutes outside.
You do realize you're free
to have a relationship with her now?
That can wait
until we've managed to solve this case.
I'm not in the mood
for love or anything else right now.
Anyway, are you suggesting
that I'll be a nuisance for staying here?
[L] No.
[suspenseful choral music playing]
[Light] Right now, I'm in no position
to continue punishing criminals.
That's why I need you
to punish them for me.
Misa...
let's create a new world together.
[kids playing outside]
[chiming]
WANTED - SHINJUKU, TOKYO
SHINTAROMARU MARUYAMADA (43)
[singing] Careful what you do…
'cause God is watching your every move
Hold my hand in the dark street
For if you do, I know that I'll be safe
Even if I'm far away and alone
I can be sure that you'll find me there
This I know
You draw me close for a while, so quiet
You tell me everything
If I forget what you say
Then you'd come to me and tell me again
Yes, you'd tell me once again
But what happens when I know it all?
Then what should I do after that?
What then?
[Yagami] What's going on?
I heard criminals are being killed again!
[Aizawa] There were 16 death
just yesterday.
All of them were broadcast
after Higuchi's death.
Immediately after, huh?
Do you think this could mean
that Higuchi wasn't necessarily Kira
after all?
No. It's safe to say that Higuchi
was the one killing criminals
until we apprehended him.
Then this means we're dealing
with yet another Kira.
Aww, man! Not again!
Damn. Damn you, Kira!
Another Kira's appeared.
What's going on here?
[Rem] I can't believe this!
It has to be Misa.
These killings began
as soon as Misa was freed, didn't they?
Ryuzaki, are you still going on
about that?
She has nothing to do with this!
Think about it.
This started as soon as Higuchi died.
Hmm, I suppose you're right.
Oh, well... If there is another notebook
floating around out there
and someone is now using it
to kill criminals,
I'll just have to bring that person
to justice.
[smacks]
The Shinigami insisted
that it didn't know,
but if someone were able to kill
simply by writing a name
on a torn piece of the notebook…
It's not impossible,
but there is that rule,
"Whoever writes a name in this notebook
has to write another name within 13 days,
otherwise they die."
Light Yagami and Misa Amane
are both still alive.
Thirteen days.
That's the only problem.
[Light] Ryuzaki, I've been thinking.
Even if we do manage to catch the person
who’s been writing names in the notebook,
will we really be able to legally
convict and punish them for mass homicide?
What? Of course, we can convict them!
This guy’s intentionally
writing names in the notebook
knowing that these people
are going to die.
Even if we don't plan
on publicly acknowledging the notebook,
the least we can do is execute the killer!
[Aizawa] It's not a very humane way
to do things,
but the higher-ups would
probably wanna take measures like that.
If they admit
to killing with the notebook,
they'd receive the death penalty.
Or a life in prison at least.
[muffled] That’s the best
that they could hope for.
What are you thinking, Light Yagami?
Making Misa kill again!
She'll be caught and once that happens,
you'll also be--
[gasps]
So that's what your plan is!
You're truly disgusting.
Light Yagami is certain
that I will do anything
to help Misa and save her life.
And at this point,
the only way for me to save Misa
is to write Ryuzaki's real name
in my notebook!
And if I kill Ryuzaki...
It would mean that I deliberately
lengthened Misa's life,
and I will die as well.
Light Yagami has planned everything,
so that it will work out in his favor!
What are you gonna do, Rem?
You may be a Shinigami,
but you can't hide the fact
that you care for Misa.
There's no way
you would turn your back on her now,
after she's already
halved her lifespan twice.
Come on. Think about Misa's happiness…
[eerie ambient noise]
What are you doing standing out there
by yourself?
What are you doing, Ryuzaki?
Oh, I'm not doing anything in particular.
It's just...
I hear the bell.
The bell?
Yes.
The sound of the bell's
been unusually loud today.
Hm.
I don't hear anything.
[L] Really? You can't hear it?
It's been ringing non-stop all day.
I find it... very distracting.
I wonder if it's a church...
maybe a wedding, or perhaps a...
What are you getting at, Ryuzaki?
Come on, cut it out.
Let's get back inside.
I'm sorry.
Nothing I say makes any sense anyway.
[sighs] If I were you,
I wouldn't believe any of it…
You know, you're totally right.
Honestly, most of the things you say
sound like complete nonsense.
There'd be no end to my troubles
if I actually took you seriously
all the time.
I probably know that better than anyone.
[L] Yes.
I would say that's a fair assessment.
But... I could say the same about you.
Hmm?
What's that supposed to mean?
Tell me, Light,
from the moment you were born,
has there ever been a point
when you've actually told the truth?
Where is this coming from, Ryuzaki?
I do admit, I stretch the truth
here and there.
However, find me one person in this world
who's never had to tell a lie.
It wouldn't be easy.
Human beings just aren't made
to be perfect like that.
Everybody lies from time to time.
Even so,
I've always made a conscious effort
to be careful
not to tell a lie
that could hurt others.
That's my answer.
I had a feeling you'd say
something like that.
Let's go back inside.
We're both drenched.
[Light] Yeah.
[water dripping]
[L] Well, that was certainly
an unpleasant outing.
It's your own fault.
I mean, what did you expect?
[L] You're right.
Sorry.
[gasps] What are you doing?
I thought I might help you out.
You were busy wiping yourself off anyway.
[Light] Look, it's fine.
You don't have to do that.
I can give you a massage as well.
It's the least I can do
to atone for my sins.
I'm actually pretty good at this.
Fine. Do what you want.
[L] All right.
[grunts]
[Light] Hey...
[L] You'll get used to it.
Here. You're still soaked.
I'm sorry.
-[L] It'll be lonely, won't it?
-[Light] Huh?
You and I will be parting ways soon.
Huh?
[phone ringing]
Yes?
I understand. I'm on my way.
Come on. Let's go, Light.
It seems like it's all worked out.
[Matsuda] Ryuzaki,
what's the meaning of all this?
You've somehow
got an approval from another country
to use the notebook for an execution!
Watari, excellent work. Thank you.
[Watari] Not at all.
[L] First things first.
Please, make arrangements
to transport the notebook immediately.
[Watari] Right.
Ryuzaki, what are you trying to do?
[L] I'm gonna try out the notebook
for real.
[all gasp]
We can't do that!
And there's no point
in testing it now
when we already know
the notebook's power is real.
[Matsuda] And besides,
who's gonna write the name?
If someone starts writing in the notebook,
they will have to obey the 13-day rule
and keep writing names forever!
[L] It's already been worked out.
The person who will write in the notebook
is a criminal scheduled to be executed
in just over 13 days.
If he's still alive
13 days after writing the name,
-he will be pardoned from execution.
-[gasps]
-But still, to sacrifice a life--
-[L] We're very close.
If we work this out,
the entire case will be solved.
-[alarm blaring]
-[Matsuda] What is this?
A blackout?
[Watari groaning]
[Watari gasping]
Watari?
Watari!
[Aizawa] Data deletion?
What the hell is going on?
I told Watari to make sure
that he should erase all information
in the event that something
were to happen to him.
If something were to happen?
Could it be...?
Where's the Shinigami?
Good question. I don't see it.
It disappeared.
What's going on?
Everyone, the Shiniga--
[loud heartbeat]
-Ryuzaki! What's wrong?
-[bell tolls]
[bell tolls]
[bell continues tolling]
[Light] Hey! Ryuzaki!
Come on! Snap out of it!
-What happened?
-What's going on?
[screaming]
Calm down, Light!
We're gonna die!
Watari, Ryuzaki...
It will be us next!
[Aizawa grunts]
[whimpers]
[Light] Damn you!
Where are you, Shinigami? Come out!
Wait, Light!
You know something about this, don't you?
Come on out!
[Yagami] We better go and look too.
Right.
Mogi, take over for me.
Okay.
There is something here!
What the hell is this stuff?
[Matsuda] Sand?
What does this mean?
[Light] Whatever it might mean,
whatever happens next...
I swear, I will avenge Ryuzaki's death.
I'm going to solve this case
in honor of him...
and for Watari...
and all the other victims.
Light.
Let's do this. For them.
Yeah, but...
aren't we all gonna get killed?
Isn't that what all of this really means?
Matsuda, if you're afraid of dying,
then leave the investigation.
We put our lives on the line
when we chose to be here.
Yeah, that's true.
But... It-- It's weird
hearing you say that.
You sound like Ryuzaki.
[door closes]
I've gotten rid of everything in my way.
[dramatic music playing]
[lightning crashes]
I am the god of the new world.
TO BE CONTINUED
[theme song plays]