Within the spreading darkness
I pledged a vow to the revolution
I can't let anybody interrupt it
I'm going to change
The future that
the forbidden fruit foretells...
I'm going to change
The dream info real/Ty
The ending
That everybody wants
Within the spreading darkness
I pledged our vow to the revolution
I can't let anybody interrupt it
Someday I'll show you
A bright and ideal
World.
The human whose name is written
in this note shall die.
Please...
- Stop!
- Now lefis see...
TAKUO SHIBUIMARU
ACCIDENTAL DEATH
What will happen!
The Death Note is real!
Don't think for a moment,
that any human who's used
the Death Note can go to Heaven or Hell.
I want the world to know...
of my existence!
And that there's someone who is
passing judgment onto them!
And I will become...
the god of this new world!
CONFRONTATION
I had no idea what he was thinking,
so I'm done with him.
Really? Then how was it
with that other older guy?
Mr. Yagami.
Please translate the sentence
into Japanese.
Yes.
"When finally, he fully succeeded
in making his dream a reality,
he was immersed in beatitude."
Very good.
As usual, a perfect answer.
Well then, class is dismissed.
- It's finally over.
- Where do you want to go after?
- School sure is boring.
- Hmm, where should we go?
Hey, Light!
Light, are you listening to me?
Don't talk to me.
Others can hear my voice
when I talk, unlike yours.
You're so boring.
Hey, Light! We're going to go...
Sorry, I have something to do.
You don't have anything to do.
Aren't you just going home
like you usually do?
What are you talking about?
I have something to do.
Something very important.
Yamada is suspected of stabbing
a fellow employee in the abdomen
at a restaurant in Kabukicho,
Shinjuku, yesterday.
The knife was from the restaurant
and was roughly twelve inches long.
- Hey!
- The suspect said...
- Hey, Ughfl
- "he was being rude, so I just lost it. "
What is it?
You're really working very hard.
I can't waste any time.
I only have a limited amount of time
to write names in the notebook...
The only time I have is when I get
home from school and until I go to bed.
I also need to maintain my grades.
I can't sleep during class.
I need to do all of my homework
for school and my prep classes.
Lack of sleep is dangerous.
It will affect my health
and concentration.
After all, I'm trying to change
this world into a utopia without evil.
There's never enough time.
Why did you lock the door, Light?
It's Sayu.
What is it?
Help me with my homework.
Okay, sure.
It's on quadratic equations!
I'm sorry if you were studying.
But it just doesn't make
any sense.
Please help me.
All right.
Light, be careful.
Any human who touches
the notebook in your drawer...
will be able to see me.
He waits to tell me that
crucial detail now? Damn Shinigami!
What's wrong, Light?
It's nothing.
Well, what exactly
don't you understand?
Well, umm...
I think everything.
From what we know,
there have been 52 deaths
just this past week.
All from heart attacks.
They're all criminals who were wanted
or being held in prison.
There are probably other criminals
whose deaths are still unaccounted for.
Does that mean the death toll
could easily be over a hundred?
Chief. . .we've already started!
I know.
I had a call from headquarters.
At any rate...
they were all criminals who
probably would have been executed.
Perhaps we shouldn't
concern ourselves...
Are you stupid?!
It doesn't matter if
they're criminals or on death row.
Killing them is still murder.
We aren't even sure that
they were murdered.
How can over 100 people
have heart attacks at the same time?!
It has got to be murder.
Is it even possible to kill
that many people at the same time?
We believe that a large organization
carefully orchestrated these killings.
If you say a large organization
is involved,
I can't help but think that
the FBI or CIA is involved.
I dare you to say that again!
Now, now.
Let's stop joking around.
We have to first clarify if these
are murders,
or strange coincidences.
But don't all the autopsy reports
say that
the deaths were caused
by inexplicable heart attacks?
I don't see what else can be learned
from just the way they died.
That's right!
It would be worth looking into
if they were stabbed with knives!
If that's the case,
we'll just have to have L solve this!
What do you think?
Chief, what is "L"?
This is your first time at
this conference, isn't it?
No one knows L's name, location
or what he looks like.
But he's managed to solve
every case he's taken,
no matter how difficult it is.
He's cracked many of
the world's unsolved cases.
He's our trump card,
our secret weapon.
Our last hope.
Something like that.
But isn't L so arrogant that he
only takes cases that interest him?
That's right.
We can't even contact him.
I is already involved.
I is already investigating this case.
Huh? Watari?
Watari?
He's the only man who can contact L.
Furthermore, Watari's identity
is also unknown...
Please be silent.
I will now speak.
Members of the ICPO...
lam L.
What are we doing sneaking around
such a desolate place, Light?
People who touch the Death Note
can see you, can't they?
I can't walk around with
something this dangerous.
Up until now, I thought that if
my family saw the notebook...
I could pass it off as
a record of cases
which I'm using to study
to become a detective.
But I'm walking a fine line
right now.
If I'm not careful,
I might end up killing...
my own family.
This case is unprecedented
in scope and difficulty.
It involves more people than
any other case preceding it.
It is also an unforgivable case
of serial murder.
In order to solve this case,
I need the ICPO...
no, various worldwide organizations,
to cooperate fully.
I want you to decide whether
you'll support me at this conference.
Also. . .I strongly desire to work
with the Japanese Police.
W-Why Japan?
Regardless of how many
suspects there are,
there's a strong possibility
that they are Japanese.
Even if they aren't Japanese,
they are hiding in Japan.
What grounds do you
have for your claims?
Why Japan?
I think I can show you very soon
by directly confronting the perpetrator.
A direct confrontation?
At any rate, I would like set up
headquarters in Japan.
That was pretty easy to make...
Hmm? Does that mean you
were able to hide the notebook?
Yeah, in this drawer.
Does that count as a hiding place?
You left the key in the lock.
That's fine.
It's better that I intentionally
left the key in a noticeable place.
That's just a regular diary!
Most people will probably be satisfied
with the secrets of this drawer...
after reading this diary.
But...
The real key...is this.
There's nothing suspicious
about having one of these on my desk.
It's just a regular ballpoint pen.
I'll use the ink cartridge.
That's the key?
Yeah. On the back of the drawer...
there's a small hole that's hard
to notice if you don't look closely.
You put this in the hole.
I see.
It's got a false bottom.
Well, you also have the fake diary,
so I doubt anyone will find it.
That's not all.
Even if they discovered
it has a false bottom,
there would be no way that
they could take the notebook.
You see...
This ink cartridge is an insulator
so it doesn't channel electricity,
and stops the flow of electricity
in the circuit.
When the bottom of
this drawer is closed,
this piece of rubber also
stops the flow of electricity.
However, if someone were to
force open the bottom,
gasoline in thin plastic bags
will ignite at that moment and...
the notebook will instantly
be set aflame.
All evidence will be
completely destroyed.
That's how it's set up.
I can just say the reason
I set it up to burn was that,
"I didn't want anyone to
see my real diary."
It's a believable excuse.
It/ls a notebook, after all.
I've heard when a human
gets a Death Note,
the biggest problem they have is
finding a good place to hide it.
But Light, you're probably
the first to go this far.
But that setup is really dangerous.
If you make
the slightest mistake,
you could be badly burned.
Dangerous?
You're talking nonsense again, Ryuk.
I've been putting myself
in danger from the very beginning.
Ever since I first got a hold
of the Death Note.
Compared to that,
this is hardly dangerous.
In fact, quite the opposite.
It protects me.
Which is better?
A small fire in the house,
or being executed?
Last night, within
the Tokyo West Penitentiary,
Naoki Kurotsukayama, aged thirty-two,
who was being detained for armed robbery...
is reported to have
died of a heart attack.
In response to the endless,
bizarre deaths of prisoners...
That's amazing...
Bad guys just keep dying.
It's a little scary,
but it does feel great.
But we really can't
do anything bad now.
I wonder if the police are behind it.
The police don't have
that kind of power.
Don't you know about him?
Huh? About who?
It's Kira... Kira!
I wonder who's going
to be killed next...
KIRA, KILL EVERYONE
SEND MESSAGE?
SEND
NAME: ROCOCO KIRA, KILL
EVERYONE NAME: MISERY
Hmm?
Someone's already created a website.
"The legend of Kira the savior."
That's pretty cool.
Is this about you?
Yeah. "Kira" seems to come from
the English word "killer."
I don't like it too much, but...
I've become "Kira" to the world.
Just searching the word "Kira," and
countless sites like this one appear.
Television and newspapers have
only publicized
"the successive, mysterious deaths
of vicious criminals."
But the people of the world
can already feel it.
The existence of someone
passing judgment.
Oh?
Ryuk, humans are like that.
For example, there's no way that
anyone would bring up the topic of
killing bad people in homeroom at school.
But if someone were to bring it up,
everyone would act pious.
"That's wrong!"
That's what they're bound to say.
Of course, it's the right thing to say.
Humans must put up a front
like that in public.
But their true feelings are there.
They may be afraid or won't acknowledge
my existence on the surface,
but on the internet,
where everyone can be anonymous...
Kira is already thriving.
They don't talk about it,
but they all understand.
Someone is making
the bad guys disappear.
Those who have a clean conscience
are cheering for Kira in their hearts...
And those who have done wrong
fear that heaven's judgment
will strike down upon them.
It's perfect.
Everything is going exactly as planned.
The Scheduled Program will be
interrupted for a Special Broadcast.
We interrupt this program to
bring you
a special, worldwide broadcast from
the ICPO, Interpol.
Hmm? What's this?
Interpol?
We'll begin now.
lam Lind L. Tailor
the only person able to
mobilize the entire world's police.
Also known as L.
W-Who is this?
It's finally started.
He's never shown his face, right?
So why now?
It means L is serious.
All right, L...
We're doing exactly
what you told us to do.
Now, let's see you prove what
you said at the ICPO conference.
There has been a string of serial killings
targeting criminals.
This is the most atrocious act of murder
in history and it will not go unpunished.
I will definitely catch
the one behind the murders,
commonly known as "Kira."
He said he'll definitely catch you.
The fool.
There's no way he can catch me.
This is the Death Note!
If you don't have this,
there's no evidence.
There's no way you can catch me.
I knew that the police would
start investigating
and that someone like him
would turn up.
Kira, I have a pretty good idea behind
your motive and why you're doing this.
But what you're doing is...
Evil!
I'm evil?
I am justice!
I'm saving the meek, who fear evil.
I'm the man who will become...
the god of the ideal, new world!
All those who oppose that god...
are evil!
L, you're stupid.
This could've been more interesting
if you'd been a bit smarter...
The entire world is watching
to see what happens if
anyone defies me. . .L.
Just five more seconds...
Four... Three...
Two... One...
What's wrong?
Why don't you say something?
This is u-unbelievable.
I had to check to be sure.
Who would have thought
you could have done this?
Kira, it seems you can kill people
without direct contact.
I couldn't believe it before
seeing it with my own eyes.
Listen to me, Kira.
If you just killed
the man on-screen, Lind L. Tailor,
you just killed a man who was
scheduled I0 be executed Ioda y.
That wasn't me.
What?!
This criminal is someone who
the police caught secretly.
His capture wasn't broadcast
on television or the internet.
It seems that even you
couldn't get information on him.
He got you.
But I, L. . .do exist!
So come on!
Try and kill me!
Why that. . .!
- L/I/hafis Wrong .7 Do if quickly!
- What's going on?! This is unreal!
- C '/770/7./ /(I'll me!
- Are you trying to die, L?!
- What's going on?
- It's Kira versus L!
It's a live murder!
- Come on, Mia!
- This is scary!
Try and kill me!
What's the matter? You can't do it?!
It seems that you can't kill me.
So, there are some people
that you can't kill.
You've given me a good clue.
I'll tell you something good in return.
I told you that this is
a live broadcast worldwide, but...
This is only being broadcast
in the Kanto region of Japan.
I was planning on broadcasting this
in different areas at different times,
but it seems that I no longer need to.
I now know that you are based
in the Kanto region.
This L guy is pretty good.
The first victim was the perpetrator
of the random murders in Shinjuku.
The police overlooked this case
because it was so minor.
Of all the criminals who
died of heart attacks,
this one's crime
was the least serious.
KUROU OTOHARADA UNEMPLOYED
RANDOM SHMJUKU MURDERS
Furthermore, his crime was
only broadcast in Japan.
I have been able
to deduce this much.
You are in Japan
and your first victim
was your guinea pig.
You're just lucky that you're in Kanto,
the most heavily populated region
in Japan.
I never thought that things
would go quite so well, but...
Kira, it probably won't be too long
before I can sentence you to death.
I certainly lives up
to his reputation...
Yes, he's proved that
Kira exists,
that the killings took place,
and that Kira's in Japan.
Kira, I'm interested how
you commit the murders.
But...
I'll find that out
when I catch you.
Until we meet again...
Kira...
He's going to...
sentence me to death?
Interesting.
I'll accept your challenge.
They both have to hunt
each other down...
but neither of them know each 0ther's
name or what they look like.
And the first one
who's discovered, dies!
Humans sure are interesting!
L...
Kira. ...!
- I will definitely find and finish you!
-lam...
- justice!
'Justice!
TO BE CONTINUED
I dreamed a dream
that no one could see,
I threw away everything
that I didn't need
I'm holding these feelings
That I can't give up in my heart
Even if my feet fall victim
to the shackles of sacrifice
In between reality and my ideal
I can't hold back
the flooding impulses
Because I have a strong desire
To accomplish
[deceit] [fear] [vanity] [melancholy]
I'm not weak enough to believe
Any of these negative perceptions
I'm a trickster
who doesn't know solitude
PREVIEW
I'm not the one who's going to find L.
The police will track him down...
SERIAL MURDER
SPECIAL INVESTIGATIONS HQ
And I will eliminate him.
Looks like I may be able to provide
you with a little more entertainment, Ryuk.
NEXT EPISODE: DEALINGS