[theme music plays]
PERFORMANCE
[Higuchi] Hey, I thought we were supposed
to be meeting every other week,
not this often.
[Ooi] It can't be helped.
We just received a new report from Coil.
He says that Misa Amane might know L.
According to Coil, L once questioned
Amane as part of his Kira investigation.
But see, here's the problem.
He says, "I've been able to deduce
that Amane worships Kira.
At the moment, Yoshida Productions
is trying to promote Amane
as the new face of Yotsuba.
My recommendation is that Yotsuba use her
for the next ad campaign
and take the opportunity
to extract information about L."
Personally, I don't like the idea.
It's unacceptable, if you ask me.
Oh, really?
It seems like a perfectly good plan.
[Namikawa] I don't think that's
what Ooi was trying to say.
It's supposed to be Coil's job
to investigate L's identity.
It doesn't make sense for him to leave
all the hard work to us, in my opinion.
Exactly. We're paying him
to uncover L's identity, after all.
Why don't we contact Coil
and see what he has to say?
[Namikawa] Yes, that's a good idea.
Mr. Kida, I thought we agreed before
that you'd only call me if it was urgent.
So, is it an emergency?
Yes, I understand.
In that case, I think I have
an even better idea.
[Higuchi] Even after
those meetings are over,
I have to come home to punish criminals.
Being Kira is so time-consuming,
but things sure have become
more interesting lately.
It's pretty clear that Misa Amane
is the Second Kira,
and that L must have
caught her at some point.
The only way she could have
gotten out of that situation
is by forfeiting ownership
of her Death Note
and losing all memories
of what she did with it.
I'm not about to leave things as they are.
I'm going to make Misa Amane my wife.
Huh?
[laughs]
Everything I could ever want.
Money, power, and a beautiful wife.
That'll be enough to make anyone envious.
Once we're married, I'll just invest
a large lump sum in her life insurance.
[Rem] She would never marry
such a disgusting fool.
Rem, make sure you hide the notebook
in the usual place.
Right now, this is the only thing I can do
for Misa's sake.
[L] All right!
Let's try again, from the top.
Tell me, Misa...
Is it true you once said that you came
to Tokyo in order to meet Ki--
-What?
-[L groans]
Misa, please stop overacting.
It looks too cheesy, not to mention fake.
Huh? But I thought
that was a realistic performance.
[L] Just do it again.
Whatever you say, oh, so great director...
[L] If you don't get serious about this,
I'll kick you.
[Misa harrumphs]
Uh, Misa-Misa…
You're not smiling enough, Mochi.
And you can just call me Misa, y'know.
I'm not cut out for this,
but it's part of my job so...
[exhales dramatically]
-Misa-Misa!
-What is it, Mochi?
Today, you have an interview
with the Yotsuba Group
to see if they'll use you
in their new ad campaign.
But remember,
this is also an infiltration mission,
so stay sharp!
Don't you worry.
I already know about that.
And, of course, that means
you can't let your cover fall either.
You're gonna play the character
of the hyper-energetic manager, okay?
[Mogi] Right! Bring it on!
[cheers]
[Shimura] Sorry to keep you waiting.
Good morning!
I'm Misa-Misa's manager, Kanichi Moji,
also known as Mochi.
-Mr. Ooi, Mr. Shimura.
-Pleased to meet you.
It's so nice to see you again.
Good luck, Misa-Misa!
[Misa] Way to go, Mochi. You're a natural!
I'll be here ready to celebrate
when they decide to hire you!
I don't think I'm cut out for this.
Now then, I don't believe
you and I have met before,
have we, Misa?
My name is John Wallace.
I'm the executive adviser
for the advertising department.
-Nice to meet you.
-Thank you.
I'm very pleased to meet you too.
Well, this might seem a little bit sudden
but I'd like to be honest with you.
We've been talking about it
and we've pretty much decided
to hire you already.
But before we make it official,
we'd like to clarify a few things.
[Misa] Yes?
We've been doing
a little background check on you
and according to our sources,
a burglar killed your parents
during a robbery.
You worship Kira
because he killed the suspect.
Isn't it true that you came to Tokyo
in hope of finding and meeting Kira?
[gasps]
What? Who did you hear that from?
[Aiber] I'm afraid I can't answer that.
The information is reliable, and now,
I'd say it's confirmed.
The look on your face tells me
that these are the facts.
Huh?
[Ooi] Coil, I never thought
you investigated that far.
Also, you're still hiding something
from us, aren't you?
Something you'd prefer
the world not to know.
Okay, here's where I pause
and look nervous.
It seems you were detained
by the detective L
for a short period of time.
We'd like you to tell us the full story
of what really happened.
It would be a problem if the new face
of Yotsuba turned out to be Kira.
Yes. We would appreciate it
if you were honest with us.
All right, I understand.
I'll tell you everything.
[Misa] Yes, I was held for questioning.
I didn't think it was L,
but he did ask me lots of questions
about Kira.
But I'm not the second Kira,
and I never was.
I was released because he realized
I didn't have anything to do
with Kira after all.
Did you manage to see who it was
that was restraining you?
[Misa] No, I was blindfolded
the whole time.
But if he asked you questions,
surely you heard his voice, right?
[Misa] Only through a speaker
and voice filters, so...
Come on.
What the hell is this anyway?
A job interview or a police interrogation?
How long are we gonna keep this up?
I'm going to the bathroom.
He has a point. It seems the interview
veered a little off track.
We're very sorry.
Excuse me, but would you mind
if I went to the bathroom as well?
[water flowing]
[Misa] Oh, this is getting exhausting.
But everything's going well so far.
I just have to keep it up.
[Misa gasps]
Being touched by this scrap of paper alone
will not restore her memories
of the Death Note.
But at least now,
Misa can see me once again.
[Misa whimpers] What is this thing?
Some kind of monster?
Misa, you're in a dangerous situation
right now.
There are people within Yotsuba
who can easily have you killed.
I've come here to warn you.
Calm down and listen to me.
[Misa] Calm down? How can I?
This thing looks like it's gonna kill me.
Please, believe me, I'm your ally.
My… ally?
[Matsuda] Oh man,
I wonder if Misa-Misa's all right.
Maybe we should have wired her
or used something to track her movements.
[Light] Just as I thought.
The Kira before I was detained
and the one that surfaced afterwards,
they must be two different people.
The MO clearly doesn't match.
This Kira is killing criminals
as soon as they've had
their crime broadcast on TV,
regardless of the situation.
He's punishing people
who never intended to kill,
those who sincerely regretted
their crimes,
or people with excusable circumstances.
The original Kira would have
never punished those kinds of people.
That's the sort of distinction I'd make,
if I were him.
The way the original Kira acted
is disturbingly close to my ideals.
[sighs] What the hell am I thinking?
I'm not Kira.
Something's gotta be wrong with me
if I'm seriously comparing myself
to that murderer.
Light Yagami is Kira.
[Misa gasps]
Tell me, what is Light doing
at the moment?
[muffled speech]
[groans]
[panting]
What are you?
I mean, I can tell you're not a stalker,
but you don't look like a human at all.
No, of course not.
I am a Shinigami.
Before you were captured by L,
you and I worked closely together.
What are you talking about?
I don't understand.
You know me? And Light is Kira?
The Death Note...
It grants its owner the power
to kill someone
simply by writing
that person's name in it.
[tires screeching]
Light Yagami took it upon himself
to punish criminals using that notebook.
He soon became known to the world
as Kira.
Huh...
You also possess that same power.
In fact, your ability
was even greater than his.
You managed to find Light
by using your power to determine
that he was, in fact, Kira.
Light is Kira, and I'm the second Kira?
[Rem] That's right.
Or rather, that used to be the case.
Light arranged it so you would both
lose this power.
This was all according to his plan.
He did? Then Ryuzaki was right!
Misa, do you still love Light
enough to die for him?
[gasps]
Unbelievable.
You've gotta be telling the truth.
You already know everything about me.
I totally believe you now.
And, yes, I do love him.
To death.
Not to mention how amazing it is
that Light and I were both Kira.
Of course I'd want to believe
something like that.
I only wish I could remember it.
You haven't changed, Misa.
And it seems your feelings for Light
will never change either.
It's enough to convince me
that the only way
you can be truly happy in life,
is if you can support him in his plan.
-Thank you, Shinigami.
-It's Rem.
The current Kira is a vile
and pathetic human being.
I don't know what he's capable of.
Be careful, and beware the others
from Yotsuba.
[Rem] Trust Light. Let him do
whatever he feels necessary.
[Misa] Okay, I got it.
I guess I should just act normal
in the meantime, though, right?
[Rem] That's right.
When you go back to the interview,
you will be able to see for yourself
who the real Kira is.
Be on your guard and do not trust him.
Oh my gosh, I'm so sorry I took so long.
I was just fixing up my makeup a little.
[Rem] Listen, when you return,
I will be in the room.
The man sitting in front of me
will be Kira.
[Misa] The person in front of you is Kira.
[Misa] Higuchi is Kira?
That bastard.
[Matsuda] Misa-Misa sure is late.
[door opening]
[Matsuda] They're back!
Hey!
[sighs] I'm exhausted.
-Hey...
-How did it go?
Yotsuba agreed to hire Misa on
as their spokesperson
for their new ad campaign.
[L] I see. That's good to hear.
And I made sure to give them
my cell phone number.
Would you believe three out of seven guys
already messaged me
asking for a private date?
[Matsuda] What?
So now I accept their invitations
and investigate them, right?
Oh, it's going exactly as I planned.
[Light] No, the plan's
getting canceled right now.
Huh? But why?
Everything's been going so smoothly
up until now.
If we go any further, you'll be in danger.
You can still appear in their commercials
but from now on,
you should deny that you were suspected
of being the second Kira
and was detained by L.
Mogi will continue being your bodyguard
but you'll be working solely
as a celebrity.
[Misa sighs]
[Misa] If that's what you want, Light,
then that's what I'll do.
Hmm...
Oh well, I'm feeling pretty tired.
Tomorrow's shoot is bright and early,
so I better get some sleep.
[Misa giggles]
Thank you, Light. You're so sweet
to be worried about me,
but I've thought of the best plan ever.
I'm going to be useful to you, I promise.
[chuckles]
[Misa] Hey, Light, want to come
sleep with me tonight?
What are you talking about?
[laughs] Just kidding.
You're saving it
for after we catch Kira, right?
You don't have to be shy about it.
Yes, Light, there's no need to be shy.
I'm not being shy.
[L] No need to be so serious either.
[director] Cut!
-Okay, that's a wrap!
-Good work, everyone.
[all] Great job, everybody.
Great job, Misa-Misa!
Thanks, Mochi. Can you take me
to the restroom in that hospital?
No problem! I'll be waiting!
TO-OH WOMEN'S MEDICAL CENTER
I'll be sure not to take too long, okay?
[Nori] Yes?
Misa! You actually made it.
Nori, you look so cute
in that nurse's outfit!
[giggles] You really think so?
TO-OH WOMEN'S MEDICAL CENTER
Huh, that went well.
[Misa gasps]
What an amazing car!
If you like it,
I'll give you a ride anytime
or buy you one of your own.
By the way,
loving that nurse's outfit, Misa.
[Misa giggles] I'm glad you like it.
[Mogi] That took a while.
[giggles]
-[Mogi exclaims]
-[nervous laugh]
-Where's Misa?
-She's on a date.
You've gotta be kidding!
Kyosuke Higuchi…
The sleazy pervert who's been sending me
text messages ever since that party.
He's been even more persistent
than any of the other guys.
He's Kira?
It can't get any worse than that.
-Hey, Misa?
-Huh?
How about we grab a bite to eat?
Are you planning to take me somewhere
and do pervy things to me?
Well, even if you are, that's okay.
I'll be fine, since I can kill people.
What are you saying, Misa?
Is this part of Light Yagami's plan?
Is this what he wants you to do?
Or is this your way of telling me
that you want me to kill Higuchi
the moment he tries to do anything?
[laughing]
Come on, you're just kidding with me,
aren't you, Misa?
You can kill people?
Yup, it's true. And you know why?
Because I'm the Second Kira.
[Higuchi] That can't be.
Even if she was the second Kira before,
there's no way she still is.
She's not supposed to have
any memory of it either.
What the hell's going on?
[Higuchi laughs] Misa...
You don't have to make up stuff like that
to feel safe with me.
I'm sure you'll find
that I'm quite the gentleman.
[Misa chuckles nervously] Yeah, maybe.
Anyway, I'll only prove
that I'm the second Kira
to the real Kira.
[Higuchi]
You'll only show proof to Kira? Why?
[Misa] I'd show him because it's always
been my dream to become Kira's wife.
I know he'll need me by his side
once I tell him.
[Higuchi]
If she really is the second Kira,
then it's pretty clear
from the Sakura TV incident
that she has the Shinigami eyes.
If that's the case,
I need to make sure I keep this girl
by my side at all costs.
I've got to test her first.
[laughs]
Well, since I happen to be Kira,
does that mean you'll marry me?
Hmm?
Really?
Yeah! I mean it.
What? Then prove it to me!
Come on, let's prove it to each other!
I can't do that.
It'd be a pretty bad idea
to let someone witness how I kill people.
You think so?
I don't know.
If I thought someone was Kira,
I think I'd be willing to show them.
We'd never get anywhere if I didn't.
[chuckles]
Then why don't you kill someone?
After all, I could be the real Kira.
Oh, all right,
but I only kill bad people, okay?
That's right. A bad person, huh?
This is Ginzo Kaneboshi.
President of a major finance company.
He's infamous
for his immoral collection methods.
Sometimes, he even makes people
pay with their insurance money.
How about him?
[Misa] Would you be able
to confirm his death right away?
[Higuchi] Yeah, as soon as I call him.
[Misa] Okay then.
Could you turn around for just a sec?
[scribbling]
Misa, you want me to kill Ginzo Kaneboshi,
don't you?
Then Higuchi will believe your claim
about being the second Kira.
Very well.
GINZO KANEBOSHI
All right. He should be dead by now.
Hello, this is Higuchi from Yotsuba--
[man] Sorry, our president just collapsed
and stopped breathing! Call back later!
[man hangs up]
Told ya.
She killed him.
The same guy I chose just a minute ago.
Would've been impossible to do that
unless she had the power.
This proves it!
[Misa gasps]
[Higuchi] So, if I'm Kira,
you'll marry me, right?
Hey, why are you getting so serious
all of a sudden?
-Because I'm Kira.
-Then prove it.
I'm not gonna be able to kill
until I get home.
You understand?
Oh, well, that's no good then.
For all I know,
you're just making all this up
so you have an excuse
to take me to your place.
-Wait! I know.
-Hmm?
Why don't you stop killing the criminals
on TV? That should prove it.
If you're Kira, it should be no problem.
You can start killing again
when I tell you to.
If all the times and deaths match up,
then I'll believe you.
After all, killing criminals in that way
is something that only Kira can do.
I see what you mean.
That's a good idea.
All right, Misa.
I'm Kira, so in order
to make you trust me
and prove that I'm him,
I'll stop killing criminals
for the time being.
Then once you're fully convinced
I'm the real thing,
you and I can get married.
[all] Huh?
And so, based on what he said,
Higuchi is Kira.
Now we not only know Kira's identity,
but all those deaths that were worrying
the chief are gonna stop!
That's amazing, Misa-Misa!
TO BE CONTINUED
[theme music plays]