Easy easy banzai Easy easy banzai
Easy easy banzai Human
Wanna get them mad? Get them mad?
Get them mad? People
What's up? Full of causes for concern
Crime won't disappear Forever
(play a trick on resentment Who's down?)
What's up? Full of causes for concern
Crime won't disappear Forever
Hey Hey! A hymn to humanity
Love has gone People, are you worried?
Hey Hey! Subservient People! !
WHAT'S UP, PEOPLE?! !
Are you worried?
MALICE
COMING OF AGE CEREMONY
NHN NEWS 9
Near, it went well.
I did everything that
you told me to do.
Yes...
MATS U M OTO
"T"...
That is all I have to tell you today.
Very well.
I also have something
I want to tell you.
Yes.
I've confirmed it.
Hm? A text message?
I WANT TO SEE YOU
I'm so jealous!
I did it! That's the confirmation
from Mikami.
I just have to wait for Near
to ask to meet me.
Near... I win!
Ipredicted what your plan was
going to be from the beginning!
This is Gevanni.
Near, I've checked the notebook.
For the past three days,
he's filled out one page every night
past midnight as he usually does.
The victims match up.
There's no change in
Mikami's behavior.
I understand.
Then let's begin.
It's Near!
He called!
L.
What is it, Near?
I want to meet you.
What?
I must meet you to discuss
the Kira case.
But don't you suspect me
of being Kira?
You shouldn't want to meet me.
Well, there's something that
I must show you personally.
Everything will be resolved
once I do that.
Good. I want you to realize that
you're wrong about me.
Near wants to prove Light is Kira,
and Light wants to kill Near...
The time has finally come...
Let's agree on some rules
regarding our meeting...
Yes. Anything.
First...
All of our investigators
must be there...
In other words, everyone who
is looking for Kira will gather.
I understand. That's fine.
As I said before,
there are a total of four SPK members,
including myself.
Mr. Mogi, who is here,
will accompany us.
Amane will be released
right before we meet.
She will not be told where
we'll be heading.
We shall meet you once you confirm
that Amane has been released.
How about it?
What should we do?
Near, I understand.
We have five investigators,
including myself...
No, Mogi is with you,
so aside from me, there are three.
Very well. ..
Now about our meeting place...
Daikoku Wharf.
An abandoned warehouse...
on the outskirts of
the South East side...
Nicknamed the Yellow Box.
I've already taken
the liberty of buying it.
How about that, Light Yagami?
You should be able to
put your plan into action here.
One more thing.
I want you to bring
the notebook you have at
your headquarters, with you.
Why the notebook?
A simple reason.
There's no one to guard the notebook
if everyone leaves.
I promise you.
I won't try to steal it.
I won't even touch it.
I'll place my faith in you
if Mr. Aizawa can confirm that it's
the notebook from your headquarters.
All right.
But someone other than L
will hold onto it.
Because I believe that L is Kira.
I understand. But I will decide
who holds onto it. Is that all right?
Yes. Then all that's left
is the time and date.
The time and date...
the question is what time.
Mikami kills right after midnight.
In the morning, he'll probably receive
a notice of the people to kill.
Taking his movements
into consideration...
In three days...
On the 28th. How about 1 PM?
One o'clock, huh?
Just as I expected...
Near is calculating
Mikami's movements...
That's fine.
It doesn't matter what time it is.
Then three days from now
at one o'clock.
Yes.
Near.
Light Yagami.
- I know what your plan is!
- I'm going to win!
Sorry, Miss Takada.
I'm a little busy today...
Busy? Does that mean that
you can't stay until morning?
Yeah, sorry.
The police are going to have
their hands full for two to three days.
How unfortunate...
I've already given orders
to Mikami and Takada...
This is the last order
I'll be giving...
JANUARY 281:00 PM
DAIKOKU WHARF WAREHOUSE
It's a rebel!
Protect Miss Takada!
Miss Takada, are you all right?
Yes.
He's getting away! Follow him!
Miss Takada, please
get inside NHN quickly!
Dont! If someone like that
was just here...
It's too dangerous
in or around NHN!
Mel/o!
At any rate, you should
get away from here!
Lady Takada, please get on!
Quickly!
Lady Takada, it's all right.
Get on quickly and
get out of here.
Yes...
Team A, Team B,
follow Lady Takada by car.
The other teams, go after
the car that just sped off!
All right! We've confirmed her safety.
Get Lady Takada
to car number seven.
No! He's taking Lady Takada?!
Damn it!
You idiot! Stop!
What if you hit Lady Takada?!
W-What are you doing?!
One of them is heavily armed...
NHN NEWS
TAKADA KIDNAPPED IN FRONT OF NHN?
- Th-This is really bad . . .
- As reported Led y Tekede and her escort teem- - .
Is it Near again?
Near, you promised that
we'd meet three days from now.
What's the meaning of this?
No, this isn't his style.
It's more like...
It's Near!
So the cars
g0! ahead of me, huh ?
How many escorts
does that Takada have?
Come on!
Since when were the Japanese
allowed to carry such big guns?
I'm an accomplice in
the kidnapping of Miss Takada.
You've probably got
a lot of questions for me...
You won't shoot-!
Idiot. He probably wouldn't
have told us anything anyway.
Death is the only way to
pay for crimes against Kira.
He's...
The person that Yagami warned me
to be most careful of. Mello...
Mihael Keehl...
Take off everything you're wearing
and put it in there.
Huff)'-
I'll give you a blanket.
L, the one who kidnapped Takada...
was not me.
I see... If that's the case, then...
It's Mello.
Yes...
I'll be honest.
The individual I placed
to guard Takada...
has confirmed that Mello was
the one who abducted her.
I'm sorry this happened while
we had an escort with her.
Near... Can't you contact Mello?
No, it's impossible.
I have a method, but...
There is no way that Mello would
respond in this situation.
Let me take off my underwear...
after I wrap the blanket around me.
Fine.
NHN NEWS 7
LADY TAKADA KIDNAPPED
The escort team was forced to
shoot one of the perpetrators.
They are still tracking
Lady Takada's whereabouts
You weren't able to get through
were you, Light?
Yes.
Miss Takada's cell phone is off.
I want to get in contact with
Takada as soon as possible,
but right now, all I can do is wait.
This is the only thing
I can do...
lfl don't do it...
We are still unable to identify
the man who was shot.
Matt... Inever thought
you would be killed...
Forgive me...
- Light!
- Impossible!
Everyone, be quiet.
Yes?
Light... /...
Miss Takada?!
Miss Takada, are you all right?!
The only reason that she'd call me
without notice like this.
means she escaped
from Mello. . .or...
Light, help me. . .!
It's all right. Calm down and
answer my questions.
A-All right.
First, location.
Do you know where you are?
I don't know where I am...
I was put inside a truck.
It was locked from the outside...
We went on the freeway and
I once saw a sign that said
we were heading toward Nagano.
Right now, I'm inside a building...
Miss Takada. ..
you are Kira's spokesperson.
Do you remember telling me
that there might be people
who're after your life?
Yes, I remember.
We talked about what
you would do in that situation.
Do you remember?
I remember...
I did as you said...
I did it...
She did it!
I didn't struggle even when
I was stripped naked...
I did exactly as you said.
I made survival my first priority...
and did it.
Light, I did everything
you told me to do...
Come quickly... Help me...!
Miss Takada...
You know what to do afterwards,
don't you?
Do as many killings as
I can do while I can...
I-| know...
- But Light...
- You can do it, can't you?
I can...
Aizawa, lde, let's go.
- Okay.
- Matsuda, take care of headquarters.
All right.
It's me...
Send me as many names as
you can of those to be punished...
My email is...
Yes, yes, I understand.
The fact that
she's called me like this,
means that. . .
she's killed her kidnappers...
Then the only thing
that's certain is that
she is in a situation where
she can '1' make any m0 ves- - .
Nakajima, I'm going to go to
the scene of the crime for the case.
Okay.
We've discovered the location
by tracing the call.
Head to Karuizawa by freeway.
Karuizawa, huh?
Damn it.
It'll take at least thirty minutes.
Hurry. It's Mello.
We don't know what he'll do.
Yeah...
For God's sake...
Aizawa and Ide are so stupid!
They both got into
the fioht seat Without a thought.
This is just too easy.
What. . . ? Mello. . .!
What's going on?!
Kiyomi Takada, Suicide.
January 26, 2013, 2:32 PM.
Burns to death by setting fire
to everything around her...
including the things she wrote on.
TO BE CONTINUED
This single page Forever depressing
A fleeting tactic in the eyes
Without petition evil against the law
chain it in prison
Poison the notebook fear the lust
Delusion of being deceived
perpetually drooling
Judgement is "crime control" they drive/ed
Who has the Rx for that?
A decriminalized world
A sanctioned word
Taking in heat
Just like "Pirates of Death"
Atone with the game of laws
Billy in despair
Now, it's time for ethics
Now, the unstoppable Eraser Rain
Billy in despair
Now, it's time for ethics
Now, the unstoppable Eraser Rain
The unstoppable Eraser Rain
PREVIEW
It's all going to end...
No, today is just the beginning.
The perfect world of Kira.
Everyone who knows about
the existence of the notebook...
Will die!
NEXT EPISODE: 1.28