Easy easy banzai Easy easy banzai
Easy easy banzai Human
Wanna get them mad? Get them mad?
Get them mad? People
What's up? Full of causes for concern
Crime won't disappear Forever
(play a trick on resentment Who's down?)
What's up? Full of causes for concern
Crime won't disappear Forever
Hey Hey! A hymn to humanity
Love has gone People, are you worried?
Hey Hey! Subservient People! !
WHAT'S UP, PEOPLE?! !
Are you worried?
What seems to be the trouble, Ryuzaki?
What's wrong?
SILENCE
The corner of this page from
this killer notebook is ripped out.
Would someone still die
if their name was written
on the part that has been cut out?
Who knows?
I haven't used it in that way,
so I don't know.
Then do Shinigami only eat apples?
No.
But a Shinigami's organs are devolved...
no, evolved.
So there's no need for us to eat...
Yagami...
You've finally been freed,
but hardly leave the headquarters...
Even if Misa comes to visit,
you only chat with her
for a few minutes.
You're free to go outside and
have a love life, you know.
We still haven't solved the Kira case.
I'm not in the mood for love.
Or, are you trying to say that
I'm a nuisance if I stay here?
No...
Right now, I'm in no position
to be punishing criminals.
Misa, punish them for me.
Misa. ..
Let's make a new world together.
Be. . .careful.
God. . .is watching.
Please hold my hand...
In the dark alley.
Even if I'm alone
and far away...
You'll always. . .
find me...
You tell me...
everything you know.
Even if. . .
I don't remember...
You tell me...
many times.
But what do I do...
once I know everything?
What's going on?
The murders of criminals have
begun again?
There were sixteen
just yesterday.
They were broadcast after
Higuchi died...
That's thorough, isn't it?
I guess that means that Higuchi
wasn't necessarily Kira...
No. We're positive that
Higuchi was the one killing criminals
until we caught him.
Then does that mean that
another Kira has appeared?
Why?!
Damn it...curse Kira...
Kira appears now...
What's going on?
What is going on?
There's only Misa...
This happened as soon as
Misa was freed, didn't it?
Ryuzaki, are you still saying that?
Misa is not involved.
It happened as soon as Higuchi died.
You're right...
Well, if there is another notebook
and someone is using it...
I'll catch him.
The Shinigami said
it didn't know, but...
If someone could kill by writing a name
on a clipping from the notebook...
It's not impossible...
But. . whoever writes
a name in this notebook...
Has to write another name
within thirteen days or die...
Light Yagami and
Misa Amane are alive...
Thirteen days...
This is the only...
Ryuzaki, even if we do catch the person
who was writing in the notebook...
Can we really convict and punish him
as a serial killer?
Well, of course!
He wrote countless names knowing
that people would die.
We should kill him
if we don't want the existence
of the notebook to go public.
Killing him is harsh,
but I bet that's what our superiors
would demand.
If he admits to killing with
the notebook, he'd get the death penalty.
Or at least a life sentence.
Something like that.
What are you thinking,
Light Yagami?
If Misa is caught,
you'll also be...
So that's it!
You bastard!
Light Yagami is sure that
I'll save Misa's life.
In order to save Misa
in this situation
I'll have to write
Ryuzaki's real name in my notebook.
And if I kill Ryuzaki...
It will definitely affect
Misa's lifespan and I'll die as well...
Light Yagami is making
everything go his way...
What are you going to do, Rem?
I know completely that
despite being a Shinigami,
you care deeply about Misa.
Misa's life has been halved.
There's no way you'd abandon her.
Think about Misa's happiness.
What are you doing there, Ryuzaki?
What are you doing there, Ryuzaki?!
What are you doing, Ryuzaki?
Well, I'm not doing
anything in particular, but...
The sound of bells...
Bells...?
Yes.
The bells have been
really noisy today...
I don't hear anything.
Really?
They've been ringing
all day and...
I can't help but feel curious...
Do you suppose it's a church?
A wedding?
Or, perhaps...
What are you talking about, Ryuzaki?
Don't say such silly things.
Let's go back.
I'm sorry.
Everything I say is
complete nonsense, so...
please, don't believe any of it.
That's right, Ryuzaki.
Most of what you say is nonsense.
There would be no end if
I took you seriously all the time.
I know that the best.
Yes, that's right, Light.
But. . .it's true for both of us.
What do you mean?
Have you ever told the truth
at any point since you were born?
What are you talking about, Ryuzaki?
It's true, I lie once in a while.
But. . .how many people live
their entire lives
only telling the truth?
Humans aren't perfect.
Everyone lies.
Even so...
I've been careful not to
tell lies that hurt others.
That's my answer.
I thought you'd say that.
Let's go back. We're drenched.
Yeah.
Well, that was awful!
It's your fault.
You were standing in that rain.
You're right. I'm sorry.
What are you doing, Ryuzaki?
I thought I'd help you...
Since you're enthusiastically
drying yourself off...
You don't have to do that.
I can give you a massage as well.
It's the least I can do to atone.
I'm pretty good at it.
Do as you please.
All right.
Hey...
You'll get used to it.
You're still wet.
I'm sorry.
It's sad...
What?
We'll soon part ways.
Yes?
All right. I'll come immediately.
Let's go, Light.
It seems it went well.
Oh, Ryuzaki!
What is the meaning of this?!
I heard that you got approval
from another country
to use the notebook
for an execution!
Watari... Good job.
Not at all.
I know it's sudden, but let's...
make arrangements to
transport the notebook.
Yes.
Ryuzaki, what's the meaning of this?
It means that I'm going to
try out the notebook for real.
That's pointless!
We don't have to do that at this point!
We already know that the power
of the notebook is real, don't we?
Besides, who's going to
write the name?
Once you write in the notebook
you have to continue writing names
every thirteen days forever!
The one who's going to write
the name
is someone who'll be executed
within thirteen days.
If he's still alive after thirteen days...
we've made a deal
to commute his execution.
But we can't sacrifice people's lives...
Just a little more.
If we just clear this...
the case will be solved.
W-What's this?!
A blackout?!
Watari?
Watari!
Data deletion?
What's the meaning of this?!
I told Watari to erase all information...
in the event that something
happened to him.
If something happened?
Could it be?!
Where's the Shinigami?
Come to think of it, I don't see it...
It's not here!
What's the meaning of this?!
Everyone...
The Shiniga-!
Ryuzaki! What's wrong?!
Hey! Ryuzaki!
What's wrong?!
Get a hold of yourself!
- What happened?!
- What's going on. . .?
Calm down, Light!
We're going to be killed!
Watari, Ryuzaki, we're next!
Damn it!
Where are you, Shinigami?!
Come out!
Light!
You must know something!
Come out!
Let's search as well.
Yes!
Mogi, please take care of him.
Yes.
Everyone, come here.
What is this?
Sand?
What's going on?
Whatever it is... Whatever happened...
I will avenge Ryuzaki...
Solving this case will
be our gift...
to Watari and the other victims...
for all people...
Light...
That's right, Light.
Yeah, but...we're going to be killed.
Isn't that what this means?
Mr. Matsuda, if you're scared of dying,
leave the investigation.
Only people who have chosen to
risk their lives should be here.
Oh...no. That's right, but...
Light, don't talk like Ryuzaki...
Everyone in my way is gone...
I'm the god of the new world.
TO BE CONTINUED
This single page Forever depressing
A fleeting tactic in the eyes
Without petition evil against the law
chain it in prison
Poison the notebook fear the lust
Delusion of being deceived
perpetually drooling
Judgement is "crime control"
they drive/ed
Who has the Rx for that?
A decriminalized world
A sanctioned word
Taking in heat
Just like "Pirates of Death"
Atone with the game of laws
Billy in despair
Now, it's time for ethics
Now, the unstoppable Eraser Rain
Billy in despair
Now, it's time for ethics
Now, the unstoppable Eraser Rain
The unstoppable Eraser Rain
PREVIEW
Ryuzaki, Watari, Rem...
Everyone in my way is gone.
I'm the god of the new world.
NEXT EPISODE: RENEWAL