[theme music plays]
GLARE
That was footage from surveillance cameras
at the station.
The death of one of the FBI agents
is captured on here. [groans]
Let's see the following scenes again.
Raye Penber passing the ticket gate
on his way in,
then him boarding the train. And finally,
the part where he dies on the platform.
[Shuichi Aizawa] Okay.
Let's see…
I think it's next to that.
Oh, here it is.
Um, so based on the records I have here,
Raye Penber comes through
the west entrance
of Shinjuku Station at 3:11 p.m.
Then at 3:13 he boards a train
on the Yamanote Line.
But even if he was following someone
at that time,
I think it's going to be very difficult
for us to draw any real conclusions
from this blurry video.
And then at exactly 4:42 p.m. ...
Oh, thank you very much, Watari.
Um, and at 4:42 p.m.
he exits the train at Tokyo station
and dies on the platform.
It's quite strange, don't you think?
I'm sorry, what do you find strange?
Yeah, what is it?
Did you notice something?
Mmm...
We know that Raye Penber got on the train
and then an hour and a half later
he got off and died on the platform.
But the Yamanote Line only takes an hour
to complete its circuit.
And more importantly,
there's the envelope.
-What do you mean?
-[remote beeps]
[L] He's holding
what looks like an envelope
when he passes through the ticket gate.
[gasps] You're right.
It's there, under his arm.
But in the footage right before his death
it's gone!
I can't believe you actually caught that.
Well, I don't see an envelope
on this list of his personal effects.
[L] Which means it was left in the train.
And if you watch closely
at the very end here...
it seems like he's straining
to look inside the train
before the doors close.
You can see right here.
If that's the case,
do you think it could mean something?
Wouldn't it be interesting
if Kira was on that train?
That's impossible!
I admit I find it hard to believe as well.
There's no reason for Kira
to come to the scene of his own crime
when he can kill from a distance.
Well... maybe he was counting on us
to make that assumption,
and figured he could get away with
such a bold move.
[Ryuk] What's going on with you, Light?
You haven't stopped writing
criminals' names in the Death Note
for four days straight.
So what are you trying to prove?
I don't see the point in writing
these names weeks in advance.
I've never seen the Death Note
used like this.
Consider it insurance.
Suppose the son of
the Detective Superintendent of the NPA
was hospitalized,
if criminals stop dying at the same time
it wouldn't be difficult
to connect the two.
So that's what this is.
Are you sure that I can use any date
as long as it's before the end
of a person's predetermined lifespan?
Well, I can't guarantee it, because
we Shinigami don't normally work that way.
But I suppose any time before the end
of their lifespan should work.
I really can't count on you, can I?
You got that right.
[Watari] Yes?
Yes, would you please hold
for a moment.
Ryuzaki.
It's Ukita at the NPA.
He says he's on the phone with someone
from the tip-line
who has information for us.
Right. Then give Ukita the number
for line five
and ask him to have the informant
call that line instead.
It'll be safer that way.
Mr. Matsuda, it's okay for you
to turn on your cell phone now.
Actually, please turn it on right away.
Uh, sure.
[phone rings]
-[phone beeps]
-Yes, this is Suzuki,
head of Kira's investigation
Public Information division.
Raye Penber's fiancée?
Naomi Misora...
I've heard that name before...
[gasps]
[L] So it's her.
She from the Los Angeles BB murder case.
That's right!
She was working under me.
I guess she must have come to Japan
with her fiancée.
[phone beeps]
Well apparently she's been missing
since the day after her fiancé died.
I'm sure that anyone in her situation
would be pretty depressed.
Was it… suicide?
No, the Naomi Misora I knew
was strong.
Not to mention that she was also
an excellent FBI agent.
If anything, it's more likely
that she'd be trying to catch Kira.
It appears she came to Japan
with Penber.
It's possible she may have found a lead.
[L] If that's the case,
did Kira manage to get to her first?
Everyone, from this point,
I'd like to focus our investigation
on only those people
whom Raye Penber was tailing.
In particular,
he was assigned to two police officers
and those closest to them.
Very well, who are these two individuals
he was investigating?
Deputy Director General Kitamura,
along with…
Detective Superintendent Yagami,
and their families.
At this stage, I'd like to place wiretaps
and surveillance cameras
in both households.
[Light Yagami] I have to make there's
no evidence left on this computer.
just in case someone goes through it.
Now I just have to hide these clippings
from the Death Note in here.
[Ryuk] It seems like you're pretty skilled
with your hands.
I bet you're pretty popular
with the girls, aren't you?
Skill has nothing to do with it.
It's your looks that count.
I'm guessing you're not that popular,
are you?
[Ryuk] Huh?
[Touta Matsuda]
Surveillance cameras? Ryuzaki!
[Aizawa] I don't see how
you could even consider this!
If this got out, we'd have
a civil rights scandal on our hands.
We'd all lose our jobs.
You told me you'd be willing
to risk your lives for this investigation.
But you wouldn't risk your jobs?
Ryuzaki, what are the odds that Kira is
in one of those households?
Maybe ten percent.
No, it's closer to five percent.
Seriously?
-Sorry, but it's not worth the risk.
-[Yagami] No.
Of all the people
we've investigated so far,
not one of them seemed
even the least bit suspicious.
Even if there's only a one percent chance,
we simply can't afford to ignore it.
[Matsuda] Chief!
I don't have to tell you how offended I am
to learn my family is under suspicion.
-Having said that, just go ahead with it.
-[both gasp]
[Yagami] And make sure
you install them everywhere...
I don't want any blind spots in the house,
and that includes the bathroom.
Thank you very much.
That was my intention.
Come on, Chief.
You don't have to agree to this.
Yes, he's right.
Think about your family.
You have a wife
and daughter at home, don't you?
Yes, I'm well aware of that fact.
But there's no point in doing any of this
if we can't be thorough!
Now I suggest you keep quiet.
[both gasp]
-[Matsuda] I'm sorry.
-No, it's okay.
Excuse me.
As a courtesy to the Chief and his family,
only he and I will conduct surveillance
of their home.
Watari, how long will it take to prepare
the wiretaps and cameras we need?
Well, starting tomorrow,
I can set them up at any time
provided we know when
both houses will be empty.
[man] See you later, Light.
Yeah, see you tomorrow.
What? No one's home yet?
I'm home.
-[handle clicks]
-Huh?
Hmm...
[Ryuk] How's it going?
I don't think anyone else is in
the house right now.
Do you wanna play some video games?
Come on, it's been awhile.
Are you listening?
Hey, Light?
[Yagami] I don't believe it.
I never knew he went
to such great lengths.
What could he be hiding in there
that he doesn't want anyone else to see?
For a 17-year-old kid,
I wouldn't say this kind of behavior
is particularly abnormal.
When I was his age,
I did strange things too.
Have you ever talked to you son
about the investigation?
Of course not!
I've never once revealed
classified information to my family.
Besides, I don't get to see them
too often these days,
and usually as soon as I get home
all I can do is sleep.
I understand.
Where exactly are we going?
Light, don’t ignore me
when I'm talking to you
or I'll get mad.
-[Light] Doesn't look ...
-[Ryuk] Hello!
...like these clothes have been bugged.
-Yoo-hoo!
-[Light] I think we're safe.
Listen to me.
There's a very strong possibility
that there are wiretaps,
and maybe even surveillance cameras,
hidden throughout my house.
Really? But that piece of paper
was still in your door, wasn't it?
-That's true, but...
-I left the paper in the door in a way
that it would be obvious
to anyone entering the room.
-The real test is the handle.
-It is?
When that door is closed,
the door handle automatically returns
to a horizontal position
and it won't go any higher than that.
But whenever I close the door,
I adjust it slightly.
Instead of letting it sit horizontally,
I lower it by about five millimeters.
When I get home and try to open the door,
if the handle is all the way up,
I can be fairly certain
that someone was in my room.
But that method alone doesn't tell me
if my door was actually opened.
So I also put a mechanical
pencil lead in place as well.
So what do you do with it?
It goes on the hinge.
After I close the door,
I take the pencil lead
and rest it on the hinges
in such a way that it will break if
the door happens to be opened by anyone.
Normally I take it out myself
when I get back home.
When I got home from school today,
I noticed that the pencil lead was broken.
Now that you mention it,
I do remember that.
First the door handle,
then the lead.
I know someone was in there today.
Maybe it was your mother.
My family wouldn't have noticed
the piece of paper.
What's suspicious is that someone
took the time to put it back in the door.
PSYCHOLOGY
PSYCHOTHERAPY
[woman] Hi there, can I help you?
What's this all about?
Are you buying a book
about wiretaps and surveillance
so you can figure this mess out?
SHOGEN BOOKS
By the way, Ryuk,
what about your apples?
Apples?
Oh! That's right, surveillance cameras.
Once the apple's in my mouth,
no one can see it.
But while I'm holding it,
it looks like it's floating.
[Light] I thought so.
You told me that Shinigami can't die,
so I guess it won't kill you
to stop eating apples for a while.
[grumbles] Don't you think
that's a bit much? Come on.
I never told you this,
but apples are to me
what cigarettes and alcohol are to humans.
Do you see what I'm saying?
I even get withdrawal symptoms.
[Light] Oh yeah?
What kind of symptoms?
My body gets all twisted.
I do handstands. It's not pretty!
-I don't want to see that.
-I know.
Okay, here's the thing.
Unfortunately, I already gave L the hint
that Shinigami love apples,
so I just can't afford
to take the risk.
When did you…
If it's so important for you
to eat apples...
you'll have to find out
where all the cameras are hidden.
If you're lucky,
you might find a blind spot
where you can eat them
without being seen.
All right, let's go!
Yeah! the camera search.
[Ryuk] Sounds so interesting.
Oh, uh... I have to find the cameras.
I can't believe my son is looking at
those magazines.
It's normal for a 17-year-old.
But it seems contrived.
It's too obvious.
The only reason he didn't want anyone
in his room
was because he had these magazines?
That's what he wants us to think.
Hey, that's my son
you're talking about.
Are you honestly telling me
that you suspect him?
I do suspect him.
That's why I placed wiretaps
and surveillance cameras in your house
and the Deputy Director's house.
Huh?
I found a camera in the air conditioner.
[Light] Hm.
So, they really put cameras
in here.
They must have bugged the place
as well.
Even if this is the Kira case,
I didn't think the Japanese police
would ever go this far.
This must be L's idea.
Which means they've narrowed down
their list of suspects.
By now they must have figured out
that it was someone
who Raye Penber was investigating,
or they wouldn't have gone to
all this trouble.
[Ryuk] Huh...
Man, these covers mislead you
all the time.
No...
Given the situation, it's safer if
I just assume I'm their prime suspect,
and the only one being watched.
It'll be okay.
Luckily I prepared for
this kind of situation.
Oh, Light…
Hey, Light!
Come on, dinner's ready.
[man on TV] I love you.
Always.
[sighs]
Hideki Ryuga.
I swear he's perfect.
How come no one in my class
is like that?
Sayu, just eat your dinner.
[Sayu Yagami] I'll eat later!
Hello, Mr. Aizawa? Are the Kitamuras
watching television now?
[Aizawa] Yes.
He's not home, but the other four
are watching while they eat dinner.
It's channel four.
Watari, please contact the broadcasters
and tell them to play our message.
[Watari] Very well.
NKK NEWS FLASH
[Sayu] Huh? What this?
The ICPO?
They're saying that...
"In response to the Kira murders,
Interpol has decided to dispatch a force
of 1500 investigators to Japan.
The investigators were drawn from
the law enforcement agencies
of its member nations.
Fifteen hundred investigators
Woah!
[Light] Chances are they've got cameras
in the living room as well.
Regardless of whether
this news is real or not,
it's obvious they're just trying to evoke
a reaction from me.
L, it's the exact same trick
you used last time.
-The ICPO sure is stupid.
-Huh?
I mean, there's no point
in making this announcement.
If they're going to send
all these people here to investigate
shouldn't they keep it a secret?
Even the FBI agents who were secretly
investigating were killed by Kira.
Why would this be any different?
If you ask me, this is nothing more than
a desperate attempt
to shock Kira, in the hopes that
he'll reveal himself somehow.
Quite frankly, I wouldn't be surprise
if Kira sees right through this.
[chuckles quietly]
Your son is clever, isn't he?
Huh. Well, yes.
[Light] Thanks for dinner, Mom.
[Sayu] Huh?
You're eating a bag of chips?
You just had dinner!
Your looks will go
if you keep that up.
It's a late-night snack for studying.
I think that's it, Light.
I found every camera
they put in the house.
I guess even Shinigami get tired
when they work hard.
Now let me explain where they all are.
It's a little bit complicated,
so listen up.
There's nothing I hate more
than explaining something twice.
[Light] All right, time for me
to hit the books.
[Ryuk] There sure are
a lot of cameras in this room.
I counted 64 in total.
I guess whoever put them here
expected you'd at least find some of them.
[Light] It has to be L.
He had no qualms about putting
a death row inmate in his place
when he declared war on me.
It's pretty clear he doesn't know
any limits.
Ugh. What I want to know is,
how am I going to be able to eat apples?
[Light] Obviously that's impossible now,
isn't it?
Oh, yeah, I guess you can't talk in here.
But we better discuss this
outside tomorrow.
Okay, I think I'm getting
the hang of this now.
[Light] Judging from the number of cameras
he's planted,
he's planning to make a decision
within a short period of time.
Any normal person would slip
under these circumstances,
but it won't be that easy with me, L.
This is the closest you will get!
[Ryuk chuckles]
[Light] I've set things up so that
criminals will continue to die
over the next three weeks.
L is aware by now that Kira can control
the times of death of his victims.
Therefore, to avoid suspicion,
L needs to see criminals
whose names are being broadcast
continue to die while I have no access
to that information.
Oh!
The symptoms are starting.
[Light] I'm going to show you, L!
With Ryuk's information
and my preparations,
I can continue to kill criminals
whose names are broadcast on the news,
while masquerading as
as a typical high school student
studying for his entrance exams.
Just watch me, L.
I'll solve equations with my right hand
and write names with my left.
MURAO TA....
SUSPECT: TAYOSHI MURAO
[Light] I'll take a potato chip...
and eat it!
[L] After dinner,
your son just goes back to studying
without turning on
the TV or his computer.
It's because the entrance exams
are five days away.
[Light] Now, a criminal
who I should have no knowledge of
will die of a heart attack
in forty seconds.
And the witness to my alibi is L himself.
All right, just a little bit longer!
Ryuzaki.
What is it, Watari?
A few minutes ago,
a bank clerk being questioned
on suspicion of embezzlement,
and a purse-snatcher
being held in a detention center
were broadcast on the news...
They both just died of sudden,
inexplicable heart attacks.
It's him again!
While all that was happening at your home,
your wife and daughter
were watching television.
When that was over, they turned the TV off
and didn't watch anything afterwards.
From just past seven thirty
until now, eleven o'clock,
your son's done nothing but study.
Kira needs a name and a face.
Without those, he can't kill.
So I suppose anyone who didn't watch
the news can't be Kira, right?
You said it yourself, that means
my family has been cleared.
It doesn't make sense
that Kira would kill two petty criminals
right after
their identities were broadcast.
[Yagami gasps]
I know it's only the first day
after the cameras were installed,
but the Yagami household seems
almost too innocent to me.
Hmm...
[Light's mom]
Light, are you up yet?
[Light] Yeah, I'm awake.
Today is garbage day, so if you've got
any, bring it down with you, okay?
[Light] What a pain!
[Light's mom]
What are you talking about?
You usually say,
"There's no need to remind me, Mom."
[Light] Yeah, yeah…
[groans]
Another beautiful day.
Well, I can't say for sure
whether you're extremely generous
or just a spoiled brat.
But didn't that mini-LCD TV cost you
400 bucks?
[Light's mom] Good morning.
TO BE CONTINUED
[theme music plays]