[theme music playing]
[imitates car revving]
Near, if you don't mind me asking,
what do you make of all this?
I'm interested to hear
what your thoughts are on this case.
[Near] The current Kira is foolish
and overconfident,
not to mention unusually cooperative
with the task force.
So much so, that I suspect
he's working hand in hand with them.
-You think so?
-That would make the second L and Kira...
one in the same person.
[Rester] What?
-That can't be. Are you serious?
-[Near] Yes, I am.
Having said that, I'll admit that
I'm only seven percent certain.
[Near] Don't worry, Commander Rester,
making assumptions
is part of any investigation.
If we're wrong,
all it'll cost is an apology.
JUSTICE
[child] There have been less crimes lately
in Japan and around the world.
It's because of Kira.
My daddy told me
that if you do something bad,
your name will be written
on the Internet...
-Your name, please.
-...and Kira will kill you.
Come on, I don't have all day.
How am I supposed to file this report
without your name?
Give me a break. Please, not my name!
Leave me alone or I'll put your names
on the Internet!
KIRA, PLEASE KILL...
[tap dripping]
[man on radio] I will proclaim this
right here and now,
to all the people of the Earth,
Kira is true justice!
[jingle playing]
KIRA'S KINGDOM
Good evening. It is my honor
to be appointed by Kira as his spokesman.
This is not a hoax.
It's the absolute truth.
I realize that there will be many people
who might try to have me killed now,
but I am prepared to risk my life
in order to spread Kira's vision.
NEW JAPANESE TASK FORCE HEADQUARTERS
[Aizawa] Kira's Kingdom, huh?
What a horrible title.
[Ide] This is insanity.
Trying to capture Kira
is an unforgivable crime.
-If you happen to know anybody...
-If anybody deserves to be killed by Kira,
it's this guy.
-...a criminal or a regular citizen...
-Oh.
Switch it back to the press conference.
-The president's about to start.
-[audience applauding on TV]
-[camera shutters clicking]
-[Matusda] I wonder what it's about?
All they said was that it was gonna be
some sort of international announcement.
You don't do anything but watch TV,
do you?
Uh, what? [grunts]
Good morning,
I'm gonna try to keep this brief.
-Huh?
-[Light] No way!
[sighs] The United States
will no longer oppose Kira.
-[all gasp]
-[audience yelling indistinctly on TV]
[grunts] Those cowards!
[Light] I've done it! I've even brought
America to its knees.
Huh? What the hell is he talking about?
Have they been threatened or something?
Are you saying that Kira is justice?
[indistinct yelling]
Justice? No, no, I never said that.
But because of Kira, war and conflict
have ceased to exist.
Criminal organizations
are in a state of ruin,
not only in the United States,
but in all free nations.
Anyone who defies Kira head on
will be killed. That is a fact.
We are not acknowledging Kira
as a symbol of justice,
we are simply saying that, as a country,
we will not take any actions against him.
[man 1 on TV] How is that any different?
[man 2 on TV] You're saying
that you accept Kira? Explain yourself!
[man 3 on TV ] And you call yourself
the representative of our country?
I can't believe it. This is America!
How can their government do something
so cowardly like this?
Uh… do you guys mind if I ask
a serious question?
Oh, boy, what is it this time?
Are you telling us you're not
always serious?
Do you guys ever think that maybe
Kira isn't completely evil?
-What?
-What kind of question is that, Matsuda?
I've been thinking about it and part of me
just doesn't believe that he is.
So now you think Kira is justice too?
I don't really know.
But I think that Kira's trying to fight
evil and change the world in his own way.
And well, the world's become a good place
for people who live honest lives,
-so, maybe--
-You're wrong, Matsuda.
People are only afraid
of losing their own lives.
How can you think that's real peace?
I understand that! Believe me,
I know that as well as you.
It's just that I can also understand
the other side.
I can see why all those people
call Kira a savior.
I'm not like you.
[Matsuda] When it comes down it,
I've always been a really weak person.
But I'm also a detective.
I can't accept Kira.
I know it's my duty to catch him.
No, I want to catch him.
It's just that I can't completely
hate him either.
I guess I must be crazy or something, huh?
[sighs] No, you're not crazy.
You're normal.
[all] Huh?
You too, Light?
What are you talking about?
[Light] I'm sure that on some level,
Kira probably knows
-that what he's doing is evil.
-[Ryuk cackles]
But he'll try to change the world
even as a martyr, at the cost of his soul.
That's his brand of justice.
I bet that's what's going
through Kira's mind.
Anyway, we shouldn't be arguing about it.
Good or evil, it's not our call.
All we have to think about
is catching him.
If Kira gets caught,
then that makes him evil.
But if he wins and rules the world,
then I guess he's justice.
Hmm...
[Light] But from now on, the world
will start leaning in favor of Kira.
It's only a matter of time.
Kira will be justice.
[Gevanni]
What's going to happen to us now?
[Near] It looks like we've been disbanded
thanks to that chicken of a president.
No, he's not even a chicken.
He's less than a maggot.
[Near] You've got to be kidding.
There's no way accepting Kira
will lead to anything good.
[shower water splashing]
Huh?
[gasps]
So you're alive?
Near!
Huh?
-What should we do?
-Let him in.
[beeping]
Mello, welcome.
Drop your weapon!
[Mello snarls]
[Near] Everyone, please put away
your guns.
Having a shoot-out here
would achieve nothing.
Sir, with all due respect,
Mello's the one who killed our partners.
[Near] Please don't make me
say it again.
Remember that our primary objective
is still to catch Kira.
Killing Mello right now will do nothing
to benefit our investigation.
Hmm...
Alright.
It seems like things have been going
just as you planned, Near.
[Near] Yes. I take it you've already
heard all about the second L
from Lidner by now?
I've pretty much figured out who Kira is
and it's mostly thanks
-to everything you've done.
-[Mello growling]
[cocking gun] Shut up, Near!
I'm not just a tool for you to use
in order to solve your puzzles, y'know?
Mello, if you really wanna shoot me
then go ahead and do it.
Stop! If you shoot him,
then the rest of us will have no choice
but to shoot you too.
What will it solve if both of you die?
That's just what Kira wants.
[grunts]
You have a good point.
Anyway, I'm only here for one thing.
I came to take back
that photograph you have.
[Near] Of course.
I got it from the orphanage.
There was only one
and no copies have been made.
I've already gone ahead and dealt
with everyone who knows your face,
both inside and outside Wammy's house.
They'll keep quiet.
I can't say a hundred percent for certain,
but it shouldn't be possible
for you to be killed by the notebook.
[Near] Is that the only business
you had with me, Mello?
[sighs] Near…
[bells chiming]
[Mello] Let's get one thing straight.
I have no intention of working together
with you on this.
[Near] Yes, I know.
At the same time, I can't just take
my photo and leave.
That wouldn't be right.
So I'll settle my debt.
[Near] Hmm?
[Mello] The killer notebook...
it belongs to a Shinigami.
Whoever touches it
is able to see a god of death.
That's crazy.
Who the hell would believe
in something like that?
[Near] I would. I believe him completely.
What good would it do for him
to tell an outrageous lie like that?
Even if he had something to gain,
he could at least come up
with a more believable story.
Therefore, these gods of death must exist.
The notebook I obtained had previously
belonged to another Shinigami.
Perhaps even Kira himself.
Also, some of the rules written inside
are actually fake.
That's all I can tell you for now.
-Near?
-Mello?
Which of us is gonna reach Kira first,
I wonder?
The race is on.
[Mello] We're both headed
towards the same destination.
I'll be waiting for you.
[Near scoffs] Right.
[Near] Fake rules...
There's no doubt that the notebook
can cause heart attacks
and control its victims to a degree.
As for burning it or tearing it up,
the notebook still exists
and there's no way to confirm
the rule one way or the other.
That means...
The false rule must be the one
that states a person will die
if he doesn't write a name
within 13 days.
-[Near] Gevanni.
-Huh?
[Near] Please set up a connection to L.
-Yes, sir.
-[keyboard clicking]
-[beeping]
-[Matusda] It's Near.
Yes?
[Near] L, I thought you should know
that we caught Mello.
-[all gasping]
-But he escaped soon afterwards.
[all sighing]
[Near] We were able
to interrogate him for a while.
He didn't really escape, did he?
You let him get away. Am I right?
No, we tried to restrain him
but he was too quick.
Anyway, Mello mentioned
that there was some sort of Shinigami
-attached to the notebook.
-[gasps softly]
[Near] Have you been able to confirm
the existence of such a creature?
Yes. I can tell you for a fact
that Shinigami do exist.
I didn't share that information
with you in the beginning
because I was certain
you would never believe me.
[Near] I would like to ask the Shinigami
a few questions.
Forget it, I'm not up for that.
The thing that's bothering me
the most about this
is the issue of those rules
written in the notebook.
I have reason to believe
that one of them is fake.
-[all] Huh?
-[Light] A fake rule?
[Near] Yes. L, I'd be interested
to hear your thoughts on this.
Out of all the rules,
which do you think is the fake?
-I'd like to know.
-[sighs]
By process of elimination,
the obvious choice
would be the one stating
that the owner of the notebook will die
if they don't write a new name in it
every 13 days.
I don't believe that.
[Near] I thought you might say so.
I've reached the same conclusion.
Hmm. Shinigami, you know the rules
of the notebook well.
Tell us. Are any of them false?
No, they are all real.
[Near] I see. You have a Shinigami
there with you?
Yes.
[Near] Is that so?
I think I'm beginning to get the picture.
In other words, Kira is there in the room
and he's making the Shinigami lie
on his behalf.
[Ryuk] Whoa, this guy's good.
He nailed it.
I don't get what he means.
So what if the Shinigami's lying
and the rule's fake?
It doesn't really change anything,
does it?
[Aizawa] Yes, it does.
It means that Light's incarceration
would be meaningless.
The rule says you die
if you don't continue writing names,
but if that's false, being alive
after 13 days in confinement
wouldn't really prove anything.
But even if that's true,
it doesn't mean he's guilty!
Besides, there's no way
that Light could be Kira.
Before he passed away,
the Deputy Director himself
was able to confirm
that he didn't have a notebook.
[Near] If there's a problem,
I suggest we verify the rule this way.
I will volunteer to write down
Mello's real name in the notebook.
[all gasp]
[Near] Of course, that means he'll die.
If I also die 13 days later,
well, then I guess Kira wins.
Either way, it's a gamble
I'm quite willing to make.
What? So this is just a game to him?
[Near]
Testing and confirming the 13-day rule
can only benefit the Kira investigation.
And other than my possible death,
there would be no drawbacks.
I'm willing to put my life on the line
if it will help us solve the case.
[Light] If I answer him based
on my feelings alone,
it'll only make me look worse to everyone.
Could you please wait for a moment?
We need to discuss your suggestion.
[microphone switch clicks]
Okay. What are your thoughts?
We can say that we must respect
human life and deny this request...
but I can't suggest that.
I'm the one under suspicion.
It's a tough call.
Mello killed the Deputy Director.
If Near is willing, I wouldn't stop him.
I'm against the idea, myself.
I don't believe that Kira's hiding
among us.
We can't use the notebook,
no matter what happens.
We should respect
the Deputy Director's wishes to the end.
I feel the same. I'm opposed to the test.
[Light] Mm.
Near, we've talked it over
and we can't allow you
to use the notebook like that.
[Near] I had a feeling you might say so.
No matter.
Just one last question before I go.
To the members
of the Japanese Task Force...
Was there ever a point
in the investigation
where the second L was suspected
to be Kira,
even if the suspicions were later dropped?
If you've been listening
to our conversation so far
and have any intention of helping
my investigation and taking down Kira,
then call the number
I'm about to give you.
Day or night, I will answer.
The choice is up to you.
[Aizawa] There's no way
that Light could be Kira.
No, it's more like
I don't wanna believe he's Kira.
But if the 13-day rule is fake,
then we really can't say for sure
that he's innocent.
This could change everything.
[cackling]
[Light] Near. I have to kill him!
[phone ringing]
-Yes, hello?
-[automated Kira voice] This is Kira.
Is this a joke?
[Kira] If you want proof,
I can read out a list of people
that I'm going to punish tomorrow.
That way, you can check it
and make your final decision afterwards.
Mr. President, I am very grateful
that you and your country
have sympathized with me, but I'm afraid
even that much isn't enough.
The SPK is still trying to catch me
despite your recent announcement.
I want you to stop them immediately,
and formally disband them.
At the same time, I want you to use
the American police, the CIA, the FBI,
and all other law enforcement
organizations at your disposal
to find out where the SPK members
are currently hiding.
As soon as you've found
their base of operations,
I want you to forward that information
to a third party.
I will give you this contact shortly.
Mr. President, whether you live
a long life or not is up to you.
Don't forget that.
I understand.
[hangs up]
[President groans]
-[man 1] Mr. Demegawa! Please wait!
-[man 2] Why are you going to New York?
[Demegawa] We are going to crush
an organization that dares to defy Kira.
It'll be on live TV.
This is a direct order from Kira,
and it came through the President
of the United States himself.
[all] Huh?
I don't know what's gonna happen
when we get there.
Hell, I don't even know what I'm saying
anymore, and I don't really care!
Sakura TV's ratings are gonna rocket
to 100, no, 120 percent for this special!
[laughs maniacally]
Come on, everyone! The new age
of Kira is about to arrive! [laughs]
[Aizawa] The previous L
was suspicious of Light.
But if Light is Kira, and I just come out
and say we should investigate him again,
I'll probably end up dead just like L,
and that won't solve anything.
The 13-day rule, huh?
-[Ide] Aizawa.
-Huh?
We have a long history. I can tell exactly
what you're thinking about,
and what's bothering you.
Between you and me, you should go ahead
and do what you think is right.
I didn't trust L to begin with.
I never did, to be honest.
I didn't sign up
to join the Kira task force
because Light was running it.
I joined because I wanted
to work with you.
Ide…
[Aizawa] Alright. I'll see if I can
contact Near without letting Light know.
[Ide] Okay.
I'll make sure that no one knows
what you're doing. You can count on me.
[both cough awkwardly]
[Aizawa] Hmm...
Light, I really want to believe
that you're not Kira.
Hmm...
[panting] This is really bad!
Turn on the TV! It's Demegawa.
-[all] Huh?
-[helicopter propeller thrumming]
This is Demegawa, live.
My comrades and I
have finally pinpointed the hideout
of the evil organization
bent on trying to catch
our beloved god, Kira.
We now have the building
completely surrounded!
-[mob yelling]
-[man] Come on out!
[man] Break down the door!
[Demegawa] Right now, our enemies
appear to be hiding within the building.
But they won't be able to hide
from us for long!
[mob yelling]
[Demegawa] Behold the power of the people!
The power of justice!
[Misa] As soon as Near escapes,
I'm gonna write his name in the notebook.
Don't worry, Light. I won't let you down.
[Rester] At this rate, we'll be dragged
outside unless we stop them somehow.
[monitors beeping]
[Near] L…
What's going on, Near?
Could it be that this is some sort of plot
by Mello to finish off the SPK?
No. Surely it couldn't be
that the SPK's security
was so lax that even a normal citizen
could find out where it was located?
[figurine snaps]
[Near] Damn it.
He's lying through his teeth.
[Light chuckling] I win, Near.
TO BE CONTINUED
[theme music playing]