[theme music plays]
DECEMBER 2007
[Mello] What was that? Roger?
What did you just say?
I'm afraid L is dead.
He's dead?
But... but how?
Was it Kira? Did Kira kill him?
Come on, Roger. You've got to tell me.
[Roger] Probably.
But he promised me he'd find Kira
and execute him,
and now you're telling me
that he's been killed?
-[Roger] Mello…
-[clatter]
[Mello] Huh?
[Near] If you can't win the game…
If you can't solve the puzzle…
Then you're just a loser.
[grunts]
So, which of us did L pick?
Me or Near?
He hadn't chosen yet.
And now that he's gone,
I'm afraid he won't be able to.
[Mello] Uh...
Mello.
Listen.
You too, Near.
Can't the two of you work together?
All right. Sounds good.
[Mello] It'll never work, Roger.
We can't do this together.
You know I don't get along with Near.
We've always competed against each other.
Always!
[wind howling outside]
You know what? It's fine.
Huh?
Near should be the one to succeed L.
He is not like me.
He never gets emotional,
he just uses his head,
like it's a game or a puzzle.
And as for me...
I'm leaving this institution.
Wait, Mello!
[Mello] Don't waste your breath.
I'm almost fifteen years old.
[door creaks]
[Mello] It's time I started living
my own life.
MARCH 5, 2012
[Near] A police officer who happened
to be nearby during Higuchi's arrest,
overheard him talking about the notebook,
If you write a person's name in it
with their face in mind,
that person will die.
So that's what you're saying
this notebook of death actually is?
[Near] That's right.
At this point the Japanese police
should have it in their possession.
A YOUNG MAN NAMED NEAR PRESENTS
EVIDENCE ON THE KIRA CASE
WHICH HE'S GATHERED BY HIMSELF
OVER THE LAST THREE YEARS.
HE MEETS WITH THE PRESIDENT,
ACCOMPANIED BY THE DIRECTOR OF THE FBI.
Mr. President, the current L is a fake.
He was created by the Japanese police
to avoid confusion and panic
amongst the various
international police agencies.
The real L is dead.
Director Mason…
This boy...
Who is he?
Sir...
Near is... Well, in a sense
you could call him...
the true successor to L.
THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA
CREATES THEIR OWN INVESTIGATION TEAM
INDEPENDENT OF L TO GO AFTER KIRA.
THE SPK
(SPECIAL PROVISION FOR KIRA)
IS COMPOSED OF HAND-PICKED
FBI AND CIA AGENTS ALONG WITH NEAR.
ABDUCTION
[Yagami] But still, it's impossible for us
to censor everything on the internet.
And we haven't had
any new leads in a while.
But posting names and faces online?
I'm sorry, but if you ask me,
it's the people doing that
who deserve to die.
[Yagami grunts]
But I guess...
that's never gonna happen.
Kira gets a lot of his information
from the internet,
so he's not gonna kill those people.
[giggles] Matsu, you silly,
you've got it all backwards.
[Light] Still, I can imagine
how some people must feel.
To them, the world's become a good place
for people who don't commit any crimes.
Or rather, it's a good place
for innocent people who lead good lives.
[Ryuk cackles]
Look who's talking.
It's more than that.
Soon everyone in the world
will think that way.
Are you all still talking
about that Kira business?
Please, give it a rest
for one afternoon, dear.
-Light, you too.
-[Sayu] I'm home.
-Huh?
-[door opens]
Hey, how's it going? [giggles]
We were just having tea.
Oh, Light, Misa.
-Seems like it's been forever, you two.
-[Matsuda gasps]
Missed you guys.
Aw, we missed you too.
And you must be... Mr. Matsuda, right?
Oh, that's me!
Wow, it's been a long time.
Thank you for always
taking such good care of my father.
[stammering] Geez, Sayu...
You're all grown up...
and pretty.
Last time I saw you, you were this big...
[Misa laughs] Matsu, your face
is going bright red!
It is? I mean... no way!
Well, you can forget it.
I'll never let Sayu marry a cop.
-Huh?
-Yes. That's right.
I'd never want that for my daughter.
-Really? Oh, man.
-[Misa giggles]
I never got the chance to propose,
or even tell her I like her.
You're too cruel to me, Mom and Dad.
-"Mom"?
-"Dad"?
Anyway, I think you'd be
a good catch, Mr. Matsuda.
What?
You really think so, Sayu?
Yep. In fact, I was thinking
if you were a little younger,
I might have considered
going out with you sometime.
[Matsuda cries]
Guess my little sister
is all grown up, isn't she?
[Misa] No kidding.
-She's already way more mature than Matsu.
-[Yagami scoffs]
But of course,
Light hasn't changed one bit.
You're just as wonderful and handsome
as when I first met you.
You've already got
a career and everything.
Make it official.
You should stop living together secretly
and just get married already.
I think that's a great idea.
[cackles]
A heart-warming scene
from the most unfortunate family
in the world.
-[phone ringing]
-Huh?
[phone ringing]
Yes? What is it, Aizawa?
-Huh?
-[Light and Matsuda] Hm?
Yes.
All right. Okay.
We have to go.
Matsuda, Light, come with me.
[Light] A kidnapping?
Involving who?
They got Director Takimura of the NPA.
Not sure who's behind it.
Ah, damn it!
As if we don't have enough
on our plate already with the Kira case.
DEPUTY DIRECTOR
[Yagami] Are you sure about this?
Unfortunately, yeah.
We got the phone call at 6:12.
That was about 45 minutes ago.
In the meantime, we were able to confirm
that the call originated
from the director's cell phone.
Did the kidnappers make any demands
in terms of ransom?
They did.
Huh?
They wanted to trade...
the director for the notebook.
[Light] Who's behind this?
And for what reason?
Do you think it's Kira?
Maybe not. If the existence
of the notebook has been leaked,
there could be any number of people
who'd want it for themselves.
But hang on.
Dad, did you say anything to the director
about the notebook?
We all agreed to keep the information
between the six of us.
So, he didn't know, did he?
I never told the director,
so he couldn't tell the kidnappers
anything.
Someone knows about the Death Note.
And beyond that,
they know
that the Japanese police have it.
Now, they've come to claim it
for themselves.
Notify every bureau
in the police department.
-But only about the kidnapping itself.
-[Aizawa] Got it.
Hmm...
-[phone beeping]
-[gasps]
Has there been a call from the suspects?
[Aizawa] No. There's a visitor here
who wants to meet
with the Director Takimura.
What?
[man] My name is John McEnroe,
I'm an agent with the FBI.
Of course, this is just an alias.
Uh...
As my assignment involves Kira,
it's a necessary precaution.
Kira?
Due to unforeseen circumstances,
the director is unavailable.
If it's acceptable,
you can speak with me instead.
Very well, that's fine.
Pardon me, I'll get straight to the point.
Japanese police have proven themselves
to be unreliable.
[Yagami] Huh?
So, in order to solve the Kira case,
we want you to hand over
the notebook to us.
[gasps]
So the FBI was behind it?
Where did you take the director?
-[McEnroe] What are you talking about?
-[Yagami] Don't act like you don't know!
This is a serious criminal offense!
[McEnroe] What would the FBI gain
by capturing the director
of the Japanese NPA?
What the hell is going on?
By the sound of things,
it seems that the director
of the Japanese police force
-has been kidnapped by someone.
-[Rester groans]
Specifically, someone
who wants the notebook.
All right, Commander Rester.
Hmm?
Pass on this message to our agent.
Suggest to the Japanese police
that we'd like to assist them
in rescuing the director
and apprehending the culprits.
We'll take the notebook
once we have the opportunity.
Roger that.
[Rester] Attention! This is headquarters.
We have new orders for you.
[footsteps echoing]
[metal door creaking]
[director groans]
Has he decided to say anything yet?
He told us the Japanese police
had begun to wimp out on Kira,
Looks like right now
the only ones officially working for L
are Soichiro Yagami, Kanzo Mogi,
and Touta Matsuda.
Isn't that right?
Yeah.
There was also Ukita,
but he was killed by Kira.
Right. And as a top cop
somehow you didn't know
that this notebook even existed,
or that you had it.
[laughs]
Japanese cops must be a joke.
Of all the investigators
on the task force,
Deputy Director Yagami
would be the highest ranking, right?
[Takimura] Ye-- Yeah.
[scoffs]
My theory is that
there are two notebooks out there.
One of them is in Kira's possession,
the other is with the NPA.
We're gonna take both of them.
Huh?
Don't worry.
As long as we do what Mello says,
there will be no mistakes.
It's been a year and a half
since he joined us
and in that entire time
he's never been wrong about anything.
Yeah, but that's what's so weird.
If he was able to bring us
the head of a mafia boss
that even Kira himself couldn't kill,
why the hell would he even
need the notebook to begin with?
[Mello] It's not just the notebook
I'm after.
I want to eliminate my competition.
[cracks]
I will be the best!
I don't care what it takes.
I will beat Near by any means necessary.
[panting]
[man chuckles] Yeah, that's right.
-[laughter]
-[Pedro] B-- Boss!
Shut up!
Can't you see that I'm busy.
I’m sorry.
But Eddie and I were
talking for a minute and...
Looks like Takimura hung himself
with his tie somehow.
What's wrong with you?
Just great!
What are we supposed to do
with a dead hostage?
-No, this'll be just fine.
-Huh?
If Kira is responsible for this,
we know he can't touch us
since he doesn't know our names or faces.
That's why he went after Takimura instead.
That means Kira is someone
who knows about the kidnapping.
That should make things
rather... interesting.
[Glen] So, what are we gonna do, Mello?
I'll tell you what are we gonna do.
We're gonna kidnap
Soichiro Yagami's daughter,
Sayu Yagami
[Mogi] We still haven't been able
to find any leads
on either Director Takimura
or the kidnappers
Things are getting pretty weird
I mean, they should've contacted us
by now with further demands
but still nothing.
We know one thing.
I found out the real name
of the FBI agent John McEnroe.
According to his personnel file
he is actually called Larry Conners.
[Light] Well, that's good to know.
He's also a genuine agent.
His background and credentials check out.
On top of that,
the director of the FBI has offered
to help us rescue Director Takimura.
I'm pretty sure
we'll be able to trust them.
But the director should
already by dead by now.
Why haven't the kidnappers
said anything?
Are they gonna give up on the deal
just because they lost
their bargaining chip?
I didn't think our opponents
would be such pushovers!
Remember, Dad, and the rest of you too,
we're gonna have to be
extremely careful.
The director might not have known
about the notebook,
but he does know
who was originally working with L.
It's possible the kidnappers
-might come after us.
-[Misa] Hey, Light!
[men] Huh?
I'll be a good girl
and go to bed by myself, okay?
[Light] Yeah, good night.
Good night, everyone!
-Guess I'll hang out around here.
-[gasps]
It just occurred to me.
We're not the only ones in danger here.
-Our families are at risk.
-[phone ringing]
[Yagami] A call
from the director's cell phone.
It must be the kidnappers!
-Quick, Aizawa!
-Got it! Tracing!
This is Yagami.
[Mello] Look. About trading the director
in exchange for the notebook,
the deal's been cancelled.
Takimura is dead.
-[all] Huh?
-[Yagami] You bastards! What did you do?
[Mello] It's only canceled, though,
regarding the director.
The new deal is this:
the notebook for Sayu Yagami.
[gasping]
See, as you're the deputy director
of the Japanese police,
it would be stupid to ask you
not to call the cops.
But you had better handle this
on your own, without backup.
If I see the police making
any big movements
in the next little while,
I'll kill your daughter.
That's right, just as easily
as we killed the director.
I'll send you a photo of Takimura's corpse
to prove I mean business.
Take a good look.
-I'll contact you tomorrow.
-[call ends]
Huh? Wait!
Damn! They got me.
They used the director's death
as an opportunity to get to Sayu.
[cackles]
Looks like things
are getting interesting again.
Sir, I...
I...
-can't believe they'd go this far.
-Damn them!
YAGAMI
-[phone ringing]
-[Sachiko] Yes, yes, coming.
Darling, you usually never call
from your work phone.
Is something the matter?
Huh? Sayu?
I don't know.
Well, now that you mention it,
she is late getting home.
Sayu…
[phone buzzing]
BIG BROTHER
Dad, are you okay?
I've just realized something.
I think it was Kira
who killed the director,
not the kidnappers.
[men] Huh?
He probably did it because he doesn't want
the notebook to fall into the wrong hands.
Kira claims to be justice.
He wouldn't want the notebook
used by someone evil.
If he killed the director,
then it's reasonable to assume
he has ways of obtaining information
from within the police force.
That means we should be the ones
who investigate this.
We leave the police out of it.
Otherwise...
Kira will find out about it
and probably kill the hostage.
Right. And we can't take that chance.
[cackles]
[Rester] Near...
we've just received a report
that the director
of the Japanese Police Agency
has been killed.
-[Near] I see. By whom?
-"By whom?"
Uh... The kidnappers, of course. Who else?
It would be interesting
-if it turned out to be Kira.
-Huh?
[Near] That's a very good point.
The police won't be
trading their notebook
if the hostage is dead,
so it protects Kira's interests.
And if it is in fact Kira,
I can narrow down
our list of suspects significantly.
Huh?
By the way, Commander Rester…
Have you been able
to determine his whereabouts yet?
Not yet.
We're able to confirm that he
left the institution four years ago.
But nothing beyond that.
-Very well. That clinches it.
-What?
[Near] Mello, you never change.
You always overlook
the most important things
because you let your emotions
get the better of you.
Or perhaps you're not even
involved in this case.
How could you leave your photo
behind at the orphanage?
[phone ringing]
This is Yagami.
[Mello] Your daughter has finally arrived.
It's about time.
What you mean?
[Mello] You already have a pretty
good idea of where we are, don't you?
Hmm...
[Mello] We'll make the exchange here.
Come to LA by yourself in two days,
and of course,
bring the notebook with you.
[Yagami] I won't make the trade
unless I'm sure my daughter is safe.
I want to talk to her right now!
[Mello] How about this?
I'll send you another photo.
That should satisfy you.
-[call ends]
-[murmurs nervously]
[both murmur nervously]
[phone beeps]
[whimpers] Oh! Sayu!
Hey, Chief, we've narrowed the call down
to Fifth Street in LA.
[Light] I just checked out the show
that was playing in the background
And it's being broadcast right now
on a local LA station.
They must've shown us that
so we'd know the photo is recent.
Oh, thank goodness.
At least we know she's still alive.
That's reassuring.
Hmm.
I'm taking the notebook to Los Angeles.
It's my decision, both as deputy director
of the Japanese Police Force
and as Sayu Yagami's father!
I'll take full responsibility
for the consequences.
That's my final word.
Wait, Dad. Before we do anything,
we have to come up with a plan.
He's right, Chief. We can't rush in.
But I have to be in LA in two days.
We don't have time.
So what you're telling me
is that Kira killed Takimura,
not the kidnappers?
I'm simply putting it forward
as a possibility.
If it does turn out to be true,
then it means Kira must be
getting his information
from the Japanese police.
Hmm.
-[phone ringing]
-[grunts]
-[phone beeps]
-Yes?
-[Light in distorted voice] This is L.
-Huh?
I don't believe it.
It's L.
I've already heard what investigator
John McEnroe, or rather Larry Conners,
had to say to Deputy Director Yagami
in regards to the notebook
in the Kira case.
Will you help us
with the investigation
into NPA director Takimura's murder?
I see. Well...
Pass me the phone.
-[rattling over phone]
-Huh?
I'm pleased to meet you at last,
L number two.
[grunts]
"Number two?"
-What do you mean by that?
-[men] Huh?
Who is this?
There's really no point
in trying to hide it.
We are a new organization
known as the SPK,
or "Special Provision for Kira".
It was established
to find and capture Kira
without the help of L.
[in distorted voice]
Furthermore, seven of our top members
already know of L's death.
[Light] They do?
Where'd they hear that?
Who the hell told them?
As for myself,
I'm at the center of the SPK.
You can address me...
as N.
[Light] N?
Who is this guy?
Is he joking?
But…
[chains rattling]
...this strange feeling, what is it?
TO BE CONTINUED
[theme music plays]