Within the spreading darkness
I pledged a vow to the revolution
I can't let anybody interrupt it
I'm going to change
The future that
the forbidden fruit foretells...
I'm going to change
The dream into reality
The ending
That everybody wants
Within the spreading darkness
I pledged our vow to the revolution
I can't let anybody interrupt it
Someday I'll show you
A bright and ideal
World
ASSAULT
Next, we have
the Naomi Misora case...
Should we go ahead and
open a criminal investigation?
We should investigate it
separately from the Kira case.
We should avoid using photographs
and only use police sketches.
But she's already been
missing for four months.
She's probably dead already...
If she's dead, it's odd that
her body hasn't turned up yet.
If it does turn up,
we might be able to find a clue.
Ryuzaki. Turn on Sakura TV.
Something terrible is happening.
In other words, we are being
held hostage by Kira.
MESSAGE FROM KIRA
4 VIDEOS
We also feel it's our duty as journalists
to give you this report.
Please understand this is not a hoax...
...and that we are not broadcasting
these tapes purely for sensationalism
"Held hostage by Kira"?
What is this?
Four days ago, our program director
was sent these four tapas.
Without a doubt,
they were sent by Kira.
Our ratings could go up sixty,
no, seventy percent...
MESSAGE FROM KIRA
4 VIDEOS
As predicted, they died of heart attacks.
If this is true, it really is something
that only Kira could do.
MESSAGE FROM KIRA
4 VIDEOS
It foretells another death
to prove that he is Kira,
and also contains a message
to people all over the World.
Well, it's probably just another
fake documentary, right?
It couldn't be. Who would make
such a vicious fake?
Please watch.
I am Kira.
If this video was aired on April 18,
at exactly 5:59 PM,
the time now is 5:59:47... 48... 49...
Please change the channel
to Taiyo TV.
The anchor, Mr. Kazuhiko Hibima will die
of a heart attack at exactly six o'clock.
Change it!
It can't be!
How could he?!
Change the channel back.
- Bring another set in here...
- Mr. H/b/ma continued f0 refer...
- no, two sets.
- to Kira as evil on air.
- Yes.
- This was his punishment.
There shall be another victim.
My next target is NHN TV commentator,
Mr. Seiji Kumaizumi.
He has continued to condemn me.
He is scheduled to appear live...
R-Ryuzaki-!
Change it Channel 24!
Change it back.
I trust you now believe
that I'm Kira.
Kira said that he was going to send
a message to the people of the world...
Something terrible will happen if
we don't stop this broadcast!
Get Sakura TV on the line!
It's no good.
My friend who works there
has his cell phone off.
All lines at the station
are all busy!
Damn it!
Mr. Ukita!
I'm going to the station to
stop this at the source!
Please listen to me carefully.
I don't want to kill the innocent.
I hate evil and love justice.
I consider the police as allies
and not my enemy.
Damn you, Kira...
My goal A9 f0 create a World
vwfhouz' e v17.
If everyone cooperates,
this will be simple.
If you do not try to capture me,
the innocent will not die.
Damn!
Even if you don't agree with me...
refrain from publicizing your views in
the media or in public. And you will be spared.
Also please be patient.
I will create a better world
for everyone.
I will change this tainted world
into a new one...
inhabited by only good,
kindhearted people.
Imagine it. Together the police
of the world and I will create...
Sachiko.
Dear, this will affect your health.
Please rest.
Sachiko. I am the head of
the Kira task force.
Damn it! It's locked!
This is the police! Open up!
You... Idiot!
- Hello?! Damn it, I'm not getting through!
- We interrupt fh/ls program
to bring you live footage from
the front of the Sakura TV studio.
Mr. A-Aizawa!
It seems
someone has collapsed!
We're currently right
in front of Sakura TV studios!
U-Ukita! Damn it...
It's Kira, isn't it?!
Mr. Aizawa.
Where do you think you're going?
Where Ukita is, of course!
That wouldn't be good.
Please think about this calmly.
Are you telling to just sit
here and watch TV?!
If this is Kira's doing, you'll just meet
the same fate if you go there.
Kira shouldn't be able
to kill without a name!
So how could this happen!
Our aliases and fake police IDs
are pointless!
This could mean Kira already
knows our names!
That may be so.
If that is the case, it would be
a lot easier to kill off
all those who are investigating him
before making a move...
I deduced that he needed
a face and a name to kill, but...
from what I just saw,
it's not entirely impossible
that he may only need a face to kill...
All I can say is that Kira is
within that television station...
or is in a place where he can
watch who enters the building.
If Kira is in that area,
isn't that more of a reason to go?!
He may have only placed
surveillance cameras in the area.
If we go there unprepared,
we'll just be killed.
You said that you were risking
your life to catch Kira, didn't you?!
Risking my life
and doing something
that'll easily get me killed are
completely different things.
What?
Please bear with it.
Mr. Ukita was killed.
But if something were to happen
to you as well...
I want the police to tell me
Whether or n02' the y will help me
create a new World.
Please make an announcement
on the six o'clock news in four days.
I have prepared a video...
for whichever answer
you choose.
What the hell is going on?
Hey! What do you think
you're doing?!
Where's the studio
they're airing the Kira videos?
This just in!
A vehicle has just crashed
into the Sakura TV studios!
That's one way to get into the building
without being seen.
But who would...
This is the police!
Stop this program!
W-What's going on?!
Stop the Kira tape right now!
W-Wait a second,
Detective!
If we interrupt it
we'll be killed by Kira...
Shut up! You do that,
and you won't be killed right now!
What do you think
you're doing?!
Are you out of your mind?!
All of this is happening because
you're treating Kira like a celebrity.
Don't you think
it serves you right?
Give me all of the copies
of your tapes!
And don't try anything!
L-| got it!
I'll give them to you!
So please stop waving
that gun around!
You've got a crazy look
in your eyes!
Police cars have finally...
arrived in front of
Sakura TV studios!
We're not alone in this.
There are still police who are
willing to stand up against Kira.
Mr. Aizawa.
You know Deputy Director Kitamura's
cell phone number, don't you?
Aizawa, I told you not to call me...
This is L.
I want you to do
something for me.
Watch the news broadcast.
You'll see the officers driven to act on
their own, to bring Kira to justice.
If you don't take control of them
as their superior,
We 'll ha ve a tragedy
on our hands.
But we are not supposed to
get involved in this case...
Two of the police officers
who rushed forward have collapsed!
SAKU RA TV
We're going to move
away from this spot!
I understand, L.
Advise me on how
I should lead them.
It's from
Detective Superintendent Yagami.
Call him back...
And give the phone to me.
Quickly, get me Ryuzaki!
It's me. Mr. Yagami, so that was
you in that police van.
Yes... I just
couldn't take it anymore...
I've confiscated all the tapes.
I'll bring them to you.
How are you doing?
I'm more than fine. I've never
felt more alive in my life.
So what should I do?
I think going out from
the front would be dangerous.
But maybe I'll be all right
in that van...
Wait just a moment.
Deputy Director Kitamura,
Chief Yagami is the one
who crashed into the building.
Are you prepared?
As you requested.
Mr. Yagami. ..
Wait five minutes...
then just exit
through the front entrance.
Just exit through
the front entrance?
Listen up!
Do not leave any gaps!
Do not show yourselves!
Kira is not in
the television station.
He's outside!
Thank you.
I'll drive myself.
I understand.
Listen up!
There is a good chance that
Kira is in the area!
Be sure not to show yourselves
while you're searching!
The police will reject Kira's offer!
They plan on fighting!
I-I will gather up the courage
to say this...
This is right!
This is the right thing to do!
This is the right stance that
a country under rule of law should take!
My name is Koki Tanakabara.
I am NHN's Golden News anchor,
Koki Tanakabara!
Chief!
Chief Yagami!
Ryuzaki. .. I'm sorry for acting
on my own.
It seems I got too emotional...
Not at all.
The tapes and envelopes
that Kira sent, are all in here.
Thank you very much.
Please allow me to rest
for a moment...
Mr. Yagami...
Your efforts will not be in vain.
The postmark is from Osaka.
But Kira can control his victims
before they die.
He could have it delivered from
Osaka without going there himself...
Mr. Aizawa.
Could you take this to the lab?
I have a lot of contacts in the lab.
I'll be sure to check
this out thoroughly.
Please do.
I shall check the contents
of the duplicate tapes.
Ryuzaki, what's on them?
They're very interesting videos.
COPY 2
COPY 3
and cooperated with Kira,
tape number three was to be aired.
And if the answer was no,
number four was to be aired.
COPY 4
COPY 3
Tape three details the conditions
for cooperation.
Basically,
to broadcast more criminals.
Especially those who had hurt people...
Or criminals who had abused
those weaker than they are.
Regardless of how severe
their crimes were.
And Kira would play the judge
in all of this.
Furthermore, as proof that
the police are cooperating...
he said that he wanted
the top brass from the NPA and L
to appear on TV and announce
that they will cooperate with him.
In other words, get the top brass
and me, to show our faces
so that if we do anything suspicious,
he can kill us.
So, what if we had answered no?
Basically the same thing,
just expressed in a different manner.
Mr. Yagami, the answer is no,
of course.
Please give Sakura TV permission
to air the fourth video.
I think it is unfortunate...
that your answer is no.
The police have answered...
that they still wish
to fight me.
So I will first take the life of
the Director-General of the NPA.
Or, Imay take the life of the L
who is leading the investigation.
The Director-General or L.
Who will be sacrificed...
for the loss of a peaceful world?
Please make your decision in four days.
As I thought,
god is really on my side...
Only this time, it's not god
but a Shinigami, a God of Death.
So it seems.
Another Shinigami has come
to the human world.
And another Shinigami's Death Note...
has fallen into the hands of
someone who endorses Kira.
SAKU RA TV
This guy probably also
has the Shinigami-eyes.
So this Kira's killing abilities
are far more powerful than mine.
If I leave things
the way they are,
I might be eliminated
within the next four days.
But...
I can't forgive the impostor
for dragging
down Kira's image
with these dirty tactics.
If the impostor slips up
and is caught,
the existence of the Death Note
could be discovered... That would be bad.
I can't let them run wild
for too long.
My priority is to cooperate
with the investigation...
and to figure out L's moves and
the fake Kira's moves.
Ryuzaki, it's as you thought.
Leaders of several countries
have talked and
they want the real L
to appear on TV.
That would be the most right
and reasonable choice.
Well, we still have three days,
so let's think of a measure
to prevent all that.
It would annoy me...
if I'm killed by someone who's
jumped on Kira's bandwagon.
What are you talking about Ryuzaki?
There is a high possibility
that fh/ls Kira is a fake.
No, we should call him
the Second Kira.
The Second Kira?!
W-Why do you think
there's a second Kira?
Please explain!
First of all, there are
the predicted victims.
They were used to convince
the TV station employees that he's Kira.
Those two victims
were only featured
in women's magazines and
on daytime talk shows.
The real Kira has no need to prove
himself with such insignificant people.
But in the Second Kira's view...
he couldn't use a criminal that
the real Kira might kill
before his prediction.
Hmm... Ryuzaki...
What are the chances that
there is a second Kira?
This time it's more than
a 70% chance.
I don't like the way he does things.
It's not like Kira.
"Not like Kira"?
Kira has always avoided
innocent victims,
aside from those who have
tried to catch him.
If we catch one Kira,
I think we'll get a hint as to
how we can catch the other.
Mr. Yagami.
May I ask your son to
cooperate in this investigation?
Does that mean he's
no longer a suspect?
No. I can't say that he's been cleared,
but I could use his reasoning abilities.
So that's what it means.
If my son wants to cooperate with you,
I have no reason to stop you.
Thank you. But...
please keep it a secret that
this current Kira might be a fake.
Please make it seem as if
we're pursuing the same Kira.
Hey, Misa...
I gave you the Death Note...
so why don't you use
it more for yourself?
I am using it for myself.
Because I believe in what Kira is doing.
I want to know what kind
of person Kira is.
I want to meet and talk to him.
I sent those videos to
the television station just for that.
I made sure
Kira would take notice.
I bet that got Kira's attention.
I'm sure of it.
This is a dangerous game.
You might be killed.
Do you understand?
It's all right. I'm sure that Kira
is kind to those with pure hearts.
But if it comes down to it...
I'm stronger because
I have the eyes!
TO BE CONTINUED
I dreamed a dream
that no one could see,
I threw away everything
that I didn't need
I'm holding these feelings
That I can't give up in my heart
Even if my feet fall victim
to the shackles of sacrifice
In between reality and my ideal
I can't hold back
the flooding impulses
Because I have a strong desire
To accomplish
[deceit] [fear] [vanity] [melancholy]
I'm not weak enough to believe
Any of these negative perceptions
I'm a trickster
who doesn't know solitude
PREVIEW
I need to find out
about the Fake Kira
before anyone else on
the Task Force does.
What kind of person are you,
Fake Kira?!
NEXT EPISODE: LOVE