[theme song playing]
TACTICS
[car engine idling]
DECEMBER 20, 11:50 A.M.
-[Raye Penber] You there?
-Yeah?
Listen carefully, I came to Japan
as a part of a secret investigation,
so the local police can't find out that…
Um… That I'm…
I understand.
I promise, I won't tell anyone
that I met you.
And of course, that includes my father.
[Penber] Well then… Please excuse me.
[Light] It's just as I thought.
Anyway, I don't want the police to know
that I've come into contact
with an FBI agent either.
If my father ever found out,
there's no doubt he'd let L know.
It's obvious that he doesn't suspect me.
And as for the police…
I'm sure they'll treat this
as just another unfortunate accident.
[door opens]
Hey, welcome back.
[Penber sighs] What a day.
Raye, what's the matter?
Something happened, didn't it?
I've never heard you sigh like that.
Yeah.
The bus I was on
got hijacked, if you can believe it.
A bus-jacking?
Some junkie robbed a bank
two days ago
and I guess he wanted to try
taking on a bus today.
I didn't think this kind of thing
happened here.
So, you were already riding the bus
when the hijacker got on?
[Penber] Yeah.
And in the end, the guy freaked out,
jumped off the bus and got hit by a car.
[Naomi] Did he die?
Yeah. Probably.
I couldn't really stick around
to see what happened to him.
-[Naomi] You know… [sighs]
-[Penber] Hmm?
It's a little hard to believe
that that was all a coincidence,
don't you think?
[Penber] What do you mean?
[Naomi] Think about it.
You got on that bus because
you were investigating someone, right?
And now you're telling me
that this criminal is most likely dead.
-Doesn’t that suggest that you--
-[Penber] That's enough.
Look. darling, you and I know you used
to be one of the best agents in the FBI.
But now you're my fiancée, Naomi.
We talked about this.
You're not an agent anymore,
so just leave it alone.
But…
You wouldn't get involved
with the Kira case.
And you wouldn't do anything dangerous.
That's what you promised
when we decided
you'd come with me,
so I could meet your parents in Japan.
You do remember that, don't you?
Yeah, I guess you're right.
It's just force of habit.
Sorry about that.
[Penber] No… I should be sorry.
Let's forget about it.
Anyway, once we have a few kids
running around,
you'll probably be so busy
you'll forget you were ever an agent.
Your mind will be occupied
with better things too.
[gasps]
More importantly,
tell me how I can convince your dad
I'm worthy of his daughter.
Kira doesn't scare me
half as much as he does.
[Naomi chuckles]
[Ryuk] Oh, let me guess.
You're about to write down
the name of that agent, aren't you?
-The one from the bus.
-Not yet.
I'm gonna wait one week
before writing his name.
If he dies right after meeting me,
I'll only draw attention to myself.
I'll write his name in here
once I've given him time to investigate
more people with ties to the police.
It'll be less obvious that way.
In the meantime,
I think I'll use some of these inmates
I've been keeping alive
to play around with L a little more.
[beeping]
-[Watari] L.
-[L] Hmm?
Another victim.
This one left
what appears to be a suicide note.
[L] Please, send it to me.
[computer beeps]
"Gods of Death."
"L, do you know?"
"Gods of Death"?
Is he trying to tell us
that Gods of Death exist?
Listen, Watari.
Tell the police to monitor
prison populations closely
for the next few days.
Kira may use other suicide notes
to communicate with us.
[Watari] Understood.
DECEMBER 27, 3:00 P.M.
[Ryuk] This place is crawling with humans.
Are you gonna do it here?
Let's just say
you're about to see the results
of all the research and experiments
I've been doing over the last few days.
[Ryuk] "Experiments"?
Yeah.
I've been using known criminals
who live in this part of town
to test out different killing methods
and I've learned a lot
about the Death Note.
ACCIDENTAL DEATH, DECEMBER 26, 8:30 PM
DIES AFTER GETTING HIT BY A CAR
For example, if I write a cause of death
and the circumstances leading up to it,
I can add a name afterwards
and it'll still happen.
SHO HANEKURODA
[Ryuk] Oh… even I didn't know that one.
He's here.
Right on time.
Mr. Raye Penber.
Turn around and you're dead.
-I am Kira.
-[gasps]
That's right. Don't turn around
or put your hands in your pockets.
I won't hesitate to kill you here.
[Penber] It-- It couldn't be…
This voice…
I've heard it somewhere.
But first, I'm gonna prove to you
that I am Kira.
Do you see the man
working over there at the coffee shop?
That's right. The one sweeping the floor.
I'm gonna kill him just for you.
But-- But… how?
Don't do it!
[gasping, grunting]
[gasps]
I'm afraid I had no choice
but to kill him.
I figured if I didn't kill
at least one person,
you wouldn't believe me.
Although that man has been repeatedly
charged with sexual assault,
he's managed to avoid conviction
every time due to lack of evidence.
He was a menace to society.
He got what he deserved.
I can only assume
that L has already informed you of this.
I can't kill someone who I haven't seen.
I have to know their face.
Which means, of course,
I can easily kill all these people
right now, if I wanted to.
Go ahead and choose someone
if you want.
[Penber] D-- Don't do it. I believe you.
You're Kira.
I'm sure you care more
about your loved ones
than any of these people here.
Imagine how you'd feel
if one of them was killed
just because you refused to cooperate.
I think you should consider them
the real hostages at the moment.
How do you know about her?
[chuckles]
You seem surprised.
I've been investigating you.
And if you don't do exactly as I say,
she will die.
And so will the rest of your family.
Including you.
And that's a promise.
I-- I understand.
Just tell me what you need me to do.
I see you've got your laptop with you.
I want the files containing the identities
of all the FBI agents who came to Japan.
[Penber] I do have my laptop with me.
It's the one I use for work.
But I don't have the files
you're looking for.
[Light] All right.
Then take this envelope.
-[Penber] Huh?
-[envelope rustles]
First, take the transceiver
out of the envelope
and put the earpiece in
and await my instructions.
[Penber] A transceiver.
This thing looks like a toy.
But there'll be no record
of this transmission anywhere.
And it allows us to converse
from a close distance, even underground.
He really thought this through.
[Light] All right.
Now get on the Yamanote Line.
Inner or outer route.
It doesn't matter
which direction you take.
SHIBUYA - SHINAGAWA
15:10
I will be close by at all times,
which means I'll be watching
your every move.
When you get on the train,
pick a spot in front of you
and don't take your eyes of it.
If I see you looking around,
I will kill you.
Once you've boarded, I want you
to take the seat closest to the doors.
If it's occupied, wait until it's free.
[train horn blares]
Now, I'm going to ask you something.
If I have even the slightest suspicion
that you're not being honest,
your girlfriend is as good as dead.
How many FBI agents
are currently in Japan?
Speak quietly into the transceiver
and don't make it obvious.
I believe it's four teams.
Three agents per team
for a total of 12.
[Light] Okay. Now, take the papers
out of the envelope.
Huh?
[Penber] What… is this?
Of those 12 agents you mentioned,
I want you to write down
the name of your superior,
the one who is heading up
this investigation,
in the space at the very top of the page.
[Penber] What is the meaning of this?
What is he after?
Let's face it,
he hasn't really left me any choice.
Besides, it's not like he can kill them
using just their names.
Next, take out your laptop and turn it on.
Any minute now your boss
is going to send you
a message with a file attachment.
It contains the names and photos
of all the FBI agents
currently active in Japan.
[Penber] But-- This… This is…
[Light] Now, one by one
you’re going to look at each photo,
and then write that agent's name
in the space provided.
You're going to do this for each agent.
[Penber] It doesn't make sense.
If he's got the names already
why use me?
What's he planning to do with them?
[Light] Good. Looks like you're done.
Now, put the transceiver
and all the papers
back into the original envelope
and place them on the rack
directly above your head.
After that,
you're going to stay in your seat
and ride the train
for at least another 30 minutes.
When you are absolutely certain
that nobody will notice
you leaving without the envelope,
you can get off of the train.
[Penber] I know that voice.
Why on earth can't I remember
who it belongs to?
Kira… who are you?
[gasps]
[loud heartbeat]
[grunting]
[gasping, groaning]
[train doors hiss]
[groans]
Light… Yagami…
Farewell, Raye Penber.
Raye Penber wrote all of those names
on pages taken from the Death Note.
Ironic.
Without even realizing it,
he was actually signing a death warrant
for all of his colleagues.
As for Penber's boss…
he died of a heart attack
after sending all of his agents a file.
And the other 11 investigators…
[chuckles lightly]
…they all died of heart attacks
after receiving the same file.
[Watari] L… You have a call
from the Director of the FBI.
[FBI Director] It's me.
I've got a report
in front of me right now stating
that all of our agents in Japan
are dead.
All 12 died of heart attacks.
I can only assume
that Kira is behind this.
Look, I'm sorry, but…
It's already decided.
We're calling off our investigation.
[beeping]
[Watari] I have Chief Yagami on the line.
[Yagami] L, I've just got off the phone
with the Director of the FBI.
According to him,
it seems that you arranged for the FBI
to come to Japan
and investigate everyone here
associated with the task force.
[L] Yes, I did.
[Yagami] So, how do you explain this?
Are we now suspects
in our own investigation?
[L] I felt that it was necessary
to uncover Kira's identity.
[Yagami] I cannot accept that.
I find it unbelievable
that you would spy on us,
the very people working with you
on this case.
Hear that?
Well, I knew all along
we couldn't trust that guy.
More importantly,
Kira killed those FBI agents, didn't he?
It's obvious he'll kill anyone
who gets in his way.
Whether they are criminals or not.
So much for his sense of justice.
He's a murderer.
[beeping]
[Watari] We have another victim.
A note was found at the scene.
L, do you know?
Gods of Death…
Huh?
[Light] …love apples.
Damn you, Kira!
[crying]
He's dead.
Raye's dead.
No, he was…
He was murdered by Kira.
[Sayu] Um, so… what's
with the family meeting, Dad?
I figured you're going
to find out sooner or later.
So, I might as well tell you now.
I don't want you to be alarmed.
I'm sure you've heard
of this Kira investigation.
Well, I am currently in charge of it.
What? Are you serious?
That's totally awesome, Dad.
You're the best cop ever.
[Yagami] That's not quite the point
I'm trying to make.
Oh?
You see, the truth is…
the FBI sent 12 of their agents to Japan
to assist us in finding Kira.
And all of them… died yesterday.
-Does that mean they were killed by Kira?
-What?!
What I'm saying is
there's a chance that Kira
will actually try to kill
anyone who comes after him.
His crimes are ruthless
and more frightening
than anything we've seen.
Many detectives have already quit.
Dad, you should quit too!
I don't want you to die!
What if he gets you?
[Sachiko] That's right.
Your life is so much more important
than some job.
I can't.
I could never forgive myself
if I walked away from this.
I will not sit back and let evil triumph.
But, Dad, you…
Please, dear…
I think it's honorable of you, Dad.
I'm proud to be able
to call you my father.
And if anything should ever happen to you,
I'm going to find Kira
and make sure he gets executed.
[door closes]
[Yagami] We now know
that Kira doesn't just target criminals.
He'll kill anyone who opposes him.
It's quite possible
that we may all be killed by Kira.
Think of your own lives,
your families, and all the others
you'd be leaving behind.
If anyone wants
to leave this investigation,
now is the time.
You won't be demoted
if you choose not to stay.
You have my word.
But if you're not absolutely sure
then we don't need you.
You have to be willing
to fight against him,
even if that means
making the ultimate sacrifice.
That is all.
[officer 1] So… what are you gonna do?
[officer 2] I'm not sure.
[driver] Oh, yeah. That' him, all right.
There's no doubt about it.
I remember him
because he told us to get down.
But I don't really remember
any of the other passengers.
[Naomi] I see.
Well, thanks for talking with me, anyway.
I appreciate it.
It's a bit of a long shot.
But if what I'm thinking is right…
Kira could have been
one of the passengers on the bus that day.
And if that is the case,
then I know that he is close enough
to use this bus route.
SERIAL MURDER
SPECIAL INVESTIGATIONS HQ
Five men, huh?
Well, six including myself.
Still, I'm grateful to see
that there's as many as five of you
willing to risk your lives to face evil.
[L] The fact that you've chosen to stay
means you have a strong sense of justice.
-I trust all of you.
-Huh?
Hol-- Hold on a second.
L just said
that he's decided to trust us now.
But honestly, what reason
do we have to trust him?
Look, L, all of us have agreed
to put our lives at risk
to bring Kira to justice.
So, I hope you understand
what this means.
We're really sticking our necks out here.
[Aizawa] But you never have to
show your face, do you?
You just give the orders.
I don't see how you can expect us
to work alongside you
under those conditions.
L.
If all of us are going to work together
on this investigation,
and if you truly meant what you said
about trusting the six of us,
could you come here,
so we can all meet in person?
[L] The thought had
already crossed my mind.
After all, I did say
that I trusted all of you.
[gasping]
Please, keep what is about to happen
a secret between the eight of us.
I would like to meet the six of you
whom I trust as soon as possible.
Before that, I want you all to go
outside of the police building
and decide once more
if you trust me or not.
NATIONAL POLICE AGENCY AND
NATIONAL PUBLIC SAFETY COMMISSION
[Ukita] Why is he seeking our help now?
There's only six of us.
He solved all of these difficult cases
by himself in the past.
So, what makes this one so different?
They way L's been
conducting things so far,
odds are he's gonna send a stand-in
or a proxy of some kind to meet us,
instead of coming himself.
It's not like we'd ever know.
A proxy, huh?
Well, it is possible.
[Matsuda] I believe L.
I think we can trust him.
And besides,
I don't really see how we can
solve this case without his help.
I agree.
From the beginning
he's been very upfront about the fact
that he'd need the help of the police
on this case.
Perhaps we should think of it like…
he's been waiting for this to happen
all along.
Why would he do something like that?
There were a number of people
on the task force
who distrusted L
before this investigation began.
And once we got started,
we had detectives
resigning left and right.
Following that
classified information was leaked.
So, I'm not surprised
that he didn't trust us.
In other words, he was waiting
for the task force to get narrowed down
to only those investigators
he could trust.
And to do that,
he needed to weed out anyone
who wasn't totally committed.
[Yagami] Hmm…
[grunts]
If we're working with that guy,
I'm leaving the task force.
You don't have to worry.
I won't try to follow you,
I'm not interested in finding L.
Well, I think we can trust L,
so I'd be willing to cooperate with him
on this investigation.
Count me in.
[L] I am staying in a suite
at the Teito Hotel at the moment.
But I'll be switching hotels
every few days
from this point on.
I want you to think of these hotel rooms
as the de facto
headquarters of this investigation.
[elevator dings]
[L] If this arrangement
is acceptable to all of you,
then split into two groups
and stagger your arrival,
so you come 30 minutes apart.
Please, arrange it
so you're all here at midnight.
Kira…
it seems we're getting
closer to each other in equal steps.
It's only a matter of time
before we collide.
So be it.
I'm ready to show my face.
I'll make my first public appearance as L.
If you ever manage to find out
about these secret meetings,
I'm sure you'd feel compelled to move in.
That's what I'm counting on.
[Light] I've been quite active
over these last few days.
Think carefully.
Was there anything I missed?
What comes next?
There are endless possibilities.
The real battle
is only just beginning now.
[L] It's unlocked.
Please, let yourselves in.
[Yagami] Hmm.
TO BE CONTINUED
[music playing]