[theme music playing]
EXECUTION
[Rem] You will continue to kill criminals
whose names are broadcast.
Outside of that, you're free
to use the Death Note however you wish.
That's the only condition.
If everything happens
as Light Yagami planned,
this should help to save Misa.
Do as I say, and you'll get what you want.
In the end, it works out well
for both of us.
I suppose, for someone in your position,
you'd call this good business.
50 DAYS IN PRISON
[L] Mr. Yagami, are you all right?
There's no reason for you
to keep doing this to yourself.
[Yagami] It's been over a month since Kira
started killing criminals again.
And as far as I'm concerned,
that's all the proof I need
to be sure that my son isn't Kira.
So, then all that's left
is for you to be sure.
One way or another,
when I get out of here
it will be with my son.
Wow. The Chief can be pretty stubborn.
Light, how are you feeling right now?
Uh. I'm okay.
Ryuzaki,
I know that in the time
I've been in prison
no new criminals have died,
however, that suggests to me
that Kira must be someone
who is intimately familiar
with my situation.
-And if that's the case--
-No, Light.
The reason criminals have stopped dying
is because you are Kira.
No! I'm not Kira.
How many times do I have to say it?
[L] If Light were Kira,
he'd know that I was bluffing.
So, why is he getting so upset?
He honestly seems clueless.
This is just cruel.
I don't care if he is a suspect.
Light still has a right to know
that criminals are being killed again.
-[L in distorted voice] Amane.
-[Misa] Yes?
[L] Are you okay?
You seem tired.
[Misa] Is that supposed to be funny?
How are you expecting me to look
after being tied up and questioned
for this many days?
[L] Hm, that's true.
Please, just let me go.
I want to see Light.
Please.
Light...
back me.
Uh... I'm not sure how much more of this
the three of them can take.
Ryuzaki, you have no reason
to keep Light locked up anymore.
Do the right thing and let him go.
Then we can get the Chief out too.
Criminals are still being killed,
even though Misa and Light haven't had
access to any of that information.
We know that much already.
So, what are you waiting for?
Not true.
All we really know at this point
is that Amane
harbors an unnaturally strong
devotion for Light Yagami.
Ryuzaki.
I'm sorry, but with all due respect,
from where I'm standing,
it's starting to look like
you're only doing this
because you don't want to admit
that you were wrong about Light.
Yes, I figured you'd say that.
Okay, fine.
But we do know
that Kira killed Lind L. Tailor
and those FBI agents, right?
As Light, said, if Kira could kill
while under surveillance
and without access to information,
there would've been no need.
If they didn't pose a threat to him,
then why would he bother killing them?
Kira doesn't kill without good reason.
I've heard you say so yourself
on more than one occasion.
Oh, I see.
If he was able to kill
under these circumstances,
then he wouldn't have been
concerned about those FBI agents
in the first place.
[Aizawa] It's already been 50 days.
There's no point to this anymore.
Ryuzaki, it's time
to start looking for the real Kira.
Yes, I understand.
[L] Mr. Yagami.
Yes. What is it?
Would you be willing
to come to headquarters just once?
I'd like to discuss my thoughts with you
but it must be done in person.
However, above all else,
I need to talk to you as Light's father.
All right. I'll come.
[dramatic music playing]
[inaudible dialogue]
THREE DAYS LATER
Honestly, all this time
I never pictured you
as an old man, Mr. Stalker.
I'm not your stalker.
-I'm a detective with the NPA.
-What?
Wait. I remember now!
You told me I was being arrested
for being the Second Kira.
You mean, that was for real?
No, you're a stalker.
There's no way the police
would blindfold me and tie me up
all fetishy like that.
Anyways, it's kind of weird that you have
my hands and feet all tied up,
even though you're planning to let me go.
Please, just keep quiet.
-Light!
-[Light] Misa?
Oh, I've missed you so much, Light.
Dad, tell me, what's all this about?
He's your dad?
Oh, my God.
I totally called your dad a stalker,
and said he was old
and all kinds of other rude stuff.
Pleased to meet you. My name's Misa Amane.
I'm Light's girlfriend...
They're all yours, Chief.
Let's go. Get in the car.
I was starting to think
I'd never get out of there.
But it feels good to finally be cleared.
[Yagami] No.
I'm afraid you two are being taken...
to your execution.
I wanted to be the one
to escort you to the execution site.
It was secretly built
in an underground facility,
not far from here.
-Execution?
-What?
-Is this a joke?
-What the hell are you talking about?
[Yagami] L is convinced
that you are Kira, Light,
and that Misa Amane is the Second Kira.
He is convinced that the only way
we can prevent the murders,
is to execute the two of you.
I don't understand.
The killings have already stopped.
[Yagami] No, they never stopped.
They never...
That's not what he told me.
So, he was lying?
L was trying to get
a confession out of you, Light.
He would have said anything.
But at this point that's not the problem.
It's political now.
You see, L's suggestion that the killings
would stop if you two were eliminated,
was unanimously accepted
by top officials in the UN
and the Japanese government.
They want Kira to disappear.
No trial, no publicity.
But that's completely insane!
Please, Dad. I'm not Kira!
He's right. What kind of a father
are you anyway?
This is your own son
you're talking about!
L made this decision, not me.
And his word is absolute.
Over the years,
he's tackled the most difficult cases,
solving all of them.
He's never been wrong.
You trust L
more than you trust me, your own son?
L went so far as to stake his life
on this theory.
If the killings don't stop,
then he too will be executed.
Huh?
L said that?
What could he be thinking?
I know that given the material evidence
this might seem
like the only logical solution.
But... he is making a mistake!
How could L come to this conclusion?
-[heartbeat]
-Something's is not right here.
It's just...
It's not like L at all.
The L I know
would rely on hard evidence.
He has to have the truth.
Is he really trying to end it like this?
All right. We're almost there.
[tires screeching]
[Light and Misa groan]
[cawing]
Where are we right now?
Why did you bring us out
to the middle of nowhere?
-What is this?
-Wait a sec!
I bet he brought us out here to let us go.
This will do.
Looks like there's nobody around
to see us out here.
I decided it would be better for us
if I brought you here,
instead of the execution site.
Listen to me.
I'm going to kill you here
and then kill myself.
[gasping]
What? What are you talking about, Dad?
-You can't! That's crazy!
-How can you say that!
You'd kill your only son for L?
If you want to die so bad
why don't you kill yourself?
If you do this,
you're no different than Kira.
I'm nothing like Kira.
I'm bound by my responsibilities
as a parent and as chief of the NPA.
Dad, come on. She's right!
Think about it. If we die here,
the truth will never be revealed!
-Please, Dad. You have to let us escape!
-[Yagami] It's too late.
Either way, you'll be executed.
At least with this,
I'll be the one to do it.
[pants, whimpers]
Please, stop, Dad! I'm not Kira!
If I die here, Kira wins!
Can't you see?
Amane, I'm going to die here with my son.
But I have no reason to kill you.
Do you understand what I'm saying?
It's only a matter of time
before the police locate this car.
Then they'll transport you
to the original site
and execute you there.
[whimpers]
Light, my son...
from one murderer to another,
I'll see you in Hell.
No, Dad!
No! Stop it!
[gunshot]
Light, my son...
from one murderer to another,
I'll see you in Hell.
No, Dad!
[gunshot]
[birds cawing]
[Light and Misa panting]
You... used a blank?
[sighs] Thank goodness.
"Thank goodness"?
What's going on? I don't understand.
Please, forgive me, you two.
I know that was hard on you.
But it was the only way
I could get you out of prison.
-You must understand.
-Oh.
I only agreed to do this because
I believe in your innocence, Light.
Were you watching, Ryuzaki?
I did exactly as you said,
and as you can see, I'm still alive.
[L] Yes, it was
a convincing performance.
If Amane were the Second Kira,
who only needs to see a person's face
to kill them,
there is no doubt
she would have killed you
before you had the chance
to fire your weapon.
Also, if Light was in fact Kira,
the Kira I know wouldn't hesitate
to kill even his own father
to save himself.
With Light in particular,
I cannot rule out the possibility
that he may have seen
through our act at some point.
However, as we agreed,
I will end their confinement immediately.
And as we discussed,
Amane will remain under surveillance
until Kira is apprehended.
Although she insists the tapes we found
were just occult videos,
the physical evidence we have,
plus her confession,
suggest otherwise.
Hey! No fair! You still suspect me?
If I were you, I wouldn't complain.
You get to go back to your normal life.
If you're innocent, the surveillance
shouldn't be a threat to you.
Think of it as a complimentary
police protection.
Oh, I get it.
Since I'm not the Second Kira,
it'll be kind of like having
my very own private bodyguards.
[L] As for your part
in this agreement, Light...
you and I will be together 24/7.
And that's how we'll remain
until we've brought Kira to justice.
Fine by me.
We will catch Kira.
Together.
[L] Yes. I look forward
to working with you.
[Light] Are you sure
this is necessary, Ryuzaki?
This is as difficult for me
as it is for you.
So, is this what you meant by being
together 24 hours a day with him?
Looking at you,
I never would have guessed.
Are you on that side of the fence,
Ryuzaki?
I told you I'm not doing this
because I want to. Okay?
But Light belongs to me.
I don’t wanna share him with you.
If you're with him 24/7,
then how are we supposed
to go on dates together?
Oh, you can still go on dates.
But it will have to be the three of us.
No way! Are you telling me
we have to kiss in front of you and stuff?
I'm not telling you to do anything.
But, yes, I suppose I would be watching.
-[Misa] That's so gross!
-[Yagami growls quietly]
[Misa] You really are a pervert,
aren't you?
[L] Light, please,
make Misa stop talking now.
Listen, Misa, that's enough.
The police have already established
that it was you who sent those tapes.
So, you're lucky
to even be here right now.
They have every right
to keep you in prison.
How can you even say that, Light?
In case you forgot, I'm your girlfriend.
Don't you trust you own soulmate?
Uh... What do you mean, "soulmate"?
You're the one who said you fell in love
with me at first sight, Misa.
So, why did you kiss me
if you didn't have feelings for me?
You took advantage of me!
[squealing] Stupid! Stupid! Stupid!
About this love at first sight.
It happened in Aoyama on May 22,
didn't it?
So what?
Why did you choose that day
to go to Aoyama?
And do you remember what you wore?
It's like I told you.
I just happened to go there.
I don't know why.
I don't remember how I felt
and I don't even know what I was wearing.
Anyway, since when do I need a reason
to hang out in Aoyama, huh?
And somehow
when you came back from Aoyama,
you knew that you were in love
with some guy
-and that his name was Light.
-Yes.
And yet, you yourself have no idea
how you came to know his name.
Yeah. So what?
Tell me, what if Light was Kira?
-How would it make you feel?
-Huh?
How would I feel
if Light was Kira?
That's right.
That would be wonderful!
I mean, I've always been grateful to Kira
for punishing the man
who murdered my parents.
So, if I found out that Light
was actually Kira,
that would be like a bonus for me.
If anything, it would make me
love him even more.
Even though it's, like,
practically impossible
to love him more than I already do!
It's Kira, though.
You'd love him even more for that?
I mean, wouldn't you be afraid?
What if he tried to kill you?
You're talking about Light being Kira?
He wouldn't be scary at all.
I'm a supporter of Kira,
so if I found out
my Light was actually him,
I'd think of how I could be helpful.
[quiet growling]
[L] That's very generous of you,
but I am pretty sure
Kira doesn't need your help.
Well, Misa, based on
what you've just told me,
there can be no mistake
that you are the Second Kira.
But you've made it so painfully obvious,
that I don't really wanna believe it.
Whatever. It's not believable
because I'm not the Second Kira. Okay?
Anyway, for the time being,
you'll remain under surveillance.
When you do go out, if needed,
you'll be able to contact us
using this room's extension.
For the most part,
your life will return to normal.
But from now on, for all private
and work-related affairs,
Mr. Matsuda will be accompanying you
as your new manager,
-Matsui...
-Matsui here.
[L] Your agency's been paid to
keep quiet and the police don't know.
Don't blow his cover.
This old guy is my manager?
Oh! You can't be serious.
Come on, what's wrong with me, Misa-Misa?
-Is it the tie? Cause I can--
-[growls]
Would you cut it out with all this dating,
kissing and Misa-Misa talk already?
This is the Kira investigation!
Stop messing around!
Sorry about that, Aizawa.
No, it's all right.
I just figured out what the problem is.
Misa Amane, it's time for you
to go to your room.
[Misa] Why?
-Out you go!
-Don't--
Hey, Light! Let's go on a date,
even if it is the three of us!
[growls]
So, Light, are you serious about her?
No way. Like I told you earlier,
it's completely one-sided.
Then could you at least
pretend to be serious,
for the sake of the investigation?
There are two things
I know about Amane for sure.
One, that she is involved in this.
And two...
that she is in love with you.
You-- You want me
to become intimate with her
to gather information
about the Second Kira?
Yes. I think you could do it
without arousing her suspicions.
And Amane would definitely be
a valuable source of information for us.
Not to mention, this is the main reason
why I agreed to release the two of you.
Ryuzaki.
As much as I wanna help you,
and as important as
the Kira case is to me,
I can't manipulate a woman's feelings
like that.
Hmm...
[Light] Please, try to understand,
to me, exploiting another
person's feelings for personal gain
is unforgivable,
and I won't allow myself
to stoop that low.
[L] There's something wrong
with this picture.
It's as if he is a different person now.
Is it possible this is an act?
If this is genuine,
it not only implies
that Amane was being controlled by Kira,
but Light Yagami too.
Huh?
What's wrong, Ryuzaki?
[L] N-- Nothing.
I suppose you're right, after all.
However, considering Misa will have
a lot of contact with the public,
it would be helpful if you could
make sure she doesn't leak information.
By the way,
do you think we could come up
with some kind of alternative
to this system of moving
from hotel to hotel every few days?
[L] Yes. In fact, I had
that very same thought some time ago.
And so...
I arranged for a facility to be built.
Construction started right after my first
meeting with Mr. Yagami and the others.
It should be finished in a few days.
-Mm. Where is it... Here it is.
-[gasps]
[L] Twenty-three floors above ground
and two below.
Although it’s impossible
to see it from the outside,
there are two helicopters
hidden on the roof.
[Light] What? That's amazing.
[L] Ideally, I want all of us
to spend as much time here as possible,
If the investigation team grows,
we can accommodate up to 60 people.
Misa shouldn't have any complaints,
since she will have her own floor.
This is truly impressive.
-To go to such lengths...
-Hold on a second.
Where did you find the finances
to build this thing?
As you can see,
it is my intention to solve this case,
no matter what it takes.
That's how it is.
I'm sorry, but how is that an answer.
[Light] No, he's right.
The mass killings are bad enough already.
But personally, I will never forgive Kira
for putting my dad and I through this.
I wanna solve this,
no matter what it takes.
If you're serious about that,
you should try to get close to Misa
and find about the Second--
I can't. That goes against my principles.
Right. You said that.
-What a shame.
-[Aizawa chuckles]
[Yagami] Huh?
Um... nothing. I'm just feeling
really motivated right now, Chief.
Ryuzaki, Chief Yagami, Light.
Let's get out of here
and bring Kira to justice.
[Yagami] Hmm.
Excuse me, I couldn't help
but notice you missed my name.
[man] Well, this looks like all of us.
Let's get started, shall we?
We're all here to further the growth
of the Yotsuba group.
by reducing competition.
So, the question is...
who is going to die?
I'm not thrilled that we
have to do this every single week.
This may be irrelevant,
but I have to wonder what prompted Kira
to start killing business people
in addition to the usual criminals
and such?
Come on now, haven't you figured
this out yet, Takahashi?
Hm?
This is the most advantageous
course of action for Kira.
Advantageous?
He's basically started
a killing service, Higuchi.
You have a lot to say
considering how stupid you are.
I'd hate to see you get killed
because of it.
Despite the fact
that we are all relatively young,
all of us are now frontrunners
to become Yotsuba's next CEO.
Not to mention,
our salaries have virtually eclipsed
those of the others
employees in the company.
It's unlikely he would choose
to back a particular company.
No matter how you look at it,
one of the people in this room
has to be Kira.
TAKESHI OOI - EIICHI TAKAHASHI
MASAHIKO KIDA - KYOSUKE HIGUCHI
So, back to business.
Does anyone have a proposal?
Who should we have Kira
eliminate this week, gentlemen?
Humans beings are truly...
disgusting creatures.
TO BE CONTINUED