Within the spreading darkness
I pledged a vow to the revolution
I can't let anybody interrupt it
I'm going to change
The future that
the forbidden fruit foretells...
I'm going to change
The dream into reality
The ending
That everybody wants
Within the spreading darkness
I pledged our vow to the revolution
I can't let anybody interrupt it
Someday I'll show you
The bright and ideal
World
Because you're
my very first friend...
- Misa.
- Yes?
Could you ask Rem to kill L?
Rem...
I want Light to love me.
Light and I will be grateful.
That would be my happiness.
Fine. I'll kill L for you.
I will die,
this easily?
WAGER
So when should I kill him?
If you take me to wherever he is,
I can kill him immediately.
It should be done
as soon as possible.
Tomorrow if you can.
But it's still too soon to
make a decision now...
I'll give you an answer after
I think of a way to kill him tonight.
All right.
No matter what,
don't kill him until I say so, got it.
No matter what! Got it?
All right, I promise...
Only in regard to L.
Misa, give me
your cell phone number.
It's about time!
Give me yours too, Light!
No, I can't give you mine.
Why not?! We're lovers!
I told you,
I'm under police surveillance.
The police now can listen in
on phone conversations.
In that case, here.
I'll give you one of
my own cell phones.
I just ended up with three after
getting them for different jobs...
That's a good idea.
Using your phone would
probably be all right.
All right!
I'll call you every day.
I'll also send you a lot of texts!
No, I'll be keeping it off.
I'll be the only one
making calls,
and I'll only tell you what
you need to know.
What? No way...
When are you going to call?
Probably tomorrow...
I'll call once even if I decide
not to execute L.
What? Tomorrow?
It doesn't sound like something
a boyfriend would call about,
but we can talk
about love afterwards.
Well Misa,
go home for today.
What? Why? It's only 7:00.
The time for love
has just begun, hasn't it?
We can go get dinner,
look at the night sky,
and after that, the main event...
Misa.
Got it?
Go home for today.
Yes...
Also, when you're talking
outside with Rem,
whisper and make sure that
no one's around.
That's what Ryuk and I do.
Yes...
Thanks for having me over...
Misa, come again tomorrow!
That kiss was so sudden,
it surprised me.
I need to keep
Misa deeply in love with me.
Oh?
Besides that, I need to decide
if I should kill L tomorrow or not.
I hasn't made himself public yet.
So if Ryuga dies...
I have to be prepared to become
an even greater suspect...
I see.
I thought you were hesitating
because he said that
you were his friend.
Friend? I was just playing along.
From the beginning, I've said
that if it's friendship he wants,
then I'll give it.
Ryuga is Light Yagami's friend,
on the surface... But L is Kira's enemy.
Yes, L is my enemy...
Since Ryuga's revealed that he's L,
I must kill him...
If L dies in an accident,
almost nobody will suspect me...
Even if they do,
there's no evidence.
I can only imagine
what will happen after L dies.
This is all a wager now.
Tomorrow will be L's...
no, Ryuzaki/Ryuga's final day.
Hair.
Snack crumbs.
Mr. Yagami.
If I die within the next few days,
your son is Kira.
Another hair.
What did you just say?!
Yeah. What are you
talking about?!
I'll make sure that you
have ready access to Watari,
I'm counting on you...
Ryuzaki. . .!
You said he was almost entirely cleared,
but I want the truth.
How likely is it that he's-?!
Even I don't know how I truly feel.
This has never happened before...
If Kira and the Second Kira
are working together...
I'm in big trouble.
So I might not be analyzing
the situation calmly...
I might be considering him a suspect
just because there's nobody else...
Despite that...
If I'm killed now,
please assume that your son is Kira.
I have no choice
but to make a surprise attack.
It can't be helped.
This is all a wager now.
That's not true.
I'm just good at
dealing with things...
What's wrong?
Oh, Yagami.
Hello.
Miss Takada,
I'd like to talk to him for moment.
Could we continue this later?
What? All right.
Was that okay?
More importantly,
didn't you say that you were afraid
to appear in front of people?
Are you all right out here?
I realized that as long
as you're not Kira, it's okay.
You're the only one on
the outside who knows I'm L...
So, I've told everyone at headquarters
that if I die in the next few days...
to assume that you're Kira.
Damn him...
You told me that
you've been lonely
because I've been taking
breaks from school,
so I came out for a change of pace.
As long as you don't die,
college is a fun place.
Yeah. When you're not here,
it's so boring
because there's no one who can
match my level of conversation.
So that explains why
you're with the "brilliant" Takada.
Well, something like that.
Should I really kill him today?
No. . .As soon as I
decided to kill him,
he suddenly appears, as if to
distract me from my resolution...
to prevent me from killing him...
This is exactly what he wants!
Shall we have some cake
in the cafeteria?
Sure... My next lecture was cancelled.
That's good.
I wonder if they have shortcake?
Well... who knows.
Light! There you are!
I came because I had
a photo shoot nearby!
Misa! You idiot!
Is this a friend of yours?
He's so unique and cool...
No... I've won!
Misa can see Ryuga's real name!
I'm Light's girlfriend, Misa Amane.
Pleased to meet you.
I'm Hideki Ryuga.
Huh? Hideki Ryuga?
Yeah, he has the same first name
and last name as that idol.
Isn't that funny?
Buzj ifis cfifferenz' from
the name I'm seeing...
Ryuga, coming outside like this
was a big mistake!
Why's he laughing?
Does this mean he noticed?
But if he's guessed that
she's the Second Kira,
there's no way
he would be laughing...
Yagami...
I'm jealous.
I've been a huge fan of yours
since the August issue of "Eighteen."
What? Really? I'm so happy...
Hey, that girl.
Isn't she Misa-Misa?!
It's true. It's Misa-Misa!
- Misa-Misa?!
- The real one?!
I should have guessed
that I'd be discovered
if there were
a lot of young people around.
I look forward to
seeing you every month.
Keep up the good work.
Yeah. Thank you.
I'll do my best...
What's going on?
Hey! Who touched my butt?!
How disgraceful!
I won't forgive anyone who would
take advantage of this situation.
I'll find the culprit.
Ryuga! You're so funny!
- I want to touch her, too.
- Stupid!
At any rate, I want to ask Misa what
L's name is as soon as possible,
but these people are in the way.
Misa!
It's time!
Are you planning on
being late again?!
Oh, sorry, Yoshi...
- Let's g0!
- Oh, yeah!
Good...
Once Misa's out of here,
I just have to give her a call
and ask her for L's name.
See you after work, Light...
Now then, shall we go, Yagami?
Yeah...
Sorry, could you go on ahead?
I need to go to the restroom.
I see. See you there...
It's over...
It's been fun... L.
I'm glad that I could discover
your name and kill you myself.
It's been fun L.
I'm glad that I could discover
your name and kill you myself.
Yes, hello?
What do you mean, "Hello"?
Oh, this cell phone must have
been dropped
by someone in
that commotion earlier.
Bastard. . .he must have...
back then...
Hello?
Yeah... That's Misa's cell phone, so...
I'll give it back to her.
I see. I understand.
Ryuga probably thinks he's won,
but Misa has another phone.
If I call that one...
Oh, this time...
it's my cell phone.
Yes?
Yes. I see. We did it.
I understand.
This may come as good and
bad news to you, but...
Misa Amane has just been
taken into custody
under suspicion
of being the Second Kira.
When in the world
did he find out about Misa?!
I never thought he'd
catch her this quickly...
There were hairs and fibers,
among other things,
attached to the masking tape
sealing the tapes the Second Kira sent.
We discovered many matching samples
of evidence in her room.
There will probably be a riot if
we charge her with being the Second Kira,
so we're telling the public that
she's voluntarily coming with us
because her manager is
suspected of drug possession.
The truth will probably
never go public...
I was careless...
That video. I should have
destroyed all the evidence...
In the end,
Ryuga chose to protect himself
by being with me instead of hiding.
He confronted
the heart of the matter...
This wager. . .is my...
M)”...
No!
Not yet...
The challenge is just beginning, L...
Watari, has she said anything?
No, she hasn't said anything yet.
Get me a visual of her.
Are you sure?
Yes, quickly.
R-Ryuzaki!
What's the meaning of this?!
I've apprehended her
as the Second Kira.
This, at the very least,
is necessary.
Indeed, there was enough evidence
in Amane's room...
to mark her as
the Second Kira, but...
Yes. There's no mistake.
Now all we have to do is
make her tell us how she kills...
Whether she knows Kira,
and if she knows who he is.
Watari. Take the proper precautions,
but do whatever needs to be done,
I don't care what,
to get her to confess.
Yes.
Also, Mr. Yagami...
I'm probably going to
call Light in...
as a prime suspect.
Please be prepared for that.
Ryuzaki, Amane's talking.
Give me visuals...and sound quickly!
Finally after three days, huh?!
I can't take it any more...
/(I'll me-
Kill me... Hurry up and kill me!
I guess it was too much
for a young girl...
She must be at her limit...
Misa Amane, can you hear me?
I can hear you...
Please kill me now...
Is this because you admit
to being the Second Kira?
No! I don't know anything
about the Second Kira!
I can't take this anymore. . .!
I'd rather die...
Just hurry up and kill me!
You should be able to
kill me immediately, right?!
Misa. . .do you mean-?
Yes, kill me.
You want me to kill you?
Yes... Kill me...
I can't take it anymore... Kill me...
If I kill you, I'll kill Light Yagami.
This all happened because of him.
No! No...
Kill me...
Misa. .. You want so badly...
to die for h/nv?
That's it! If you won't kill me...!
This is not good, Watari...
Don't let her bite her tongue!
Could it be that these are
just actions
controlled by Kira before death?
Oh Rem.
What's this all of a sudden?
Light Yagami...
I offered to help Misa escape,
but she refused.
She probably thought it would
get you in trouble
since the police think that
she has special powers...
And when she was
at her wit's end,
she started asking me to kill her.
This is all because
she wants you to love her.
No matter how much she asked,
I couldn't kill her...
I couldn't bear watching her...
There was only one way
to save her from that suffering.
Forfeiting ownership
of the Death Note.
That's right.
If she forfeits ownership
of the Death Note,
all memories related to
the Death Note will disappear.
All memories of murders
she committed with her notebook,
and the fact that you are Kira,
will disappear.
Misa will not reveal your secret.
Also, Misa will no longer
be able to see Ryuk or me.
SEVERAL HOURS EARLIER
You will forget
everything about Shinigami.
It's all right. The human
you love is Light Yagami.
Those emotions will remain.
So Misa, forfeit ownership
of the notebook
and leave everything to Light Yagami.
Misa no longer owns the Death Note.
You did well, Rem...
I was beginning to think
that was the only way.
If her memories of
the Death Note are erased,
then it's not impossible
to get Misa released.
Light Yagami, I proposed this
to Misa
because I knew this is the method
you would have desired the most.
If you don't save Misa, I'll kill you.
I understand, Rem.
I think I have a good idea
of what L is going to do next.
I have a plan.
This is good bye, Ryuk.
What?
TO BE CONTINUED
I dreamed a dream
that no one could see,
I threw away everything
that I didn't need
I'm holding these feelings
That I can't give up in my heart
Even if my feet fall victim
to the shackles of sacrifice
In between reality and my ideal
I can't hold back
the flooding impulses
Because I have a strong desire
To accomplish
[deceit] [fear] [vanity] [melancholy]
I'm not weak enough to believe
Any of these negative perceptions
I'm a trickster
who doesn't know solitude
PREVIEW
Yeah... I know I probably look
pretty bad in here...
but this pride...
I'll just have to...
get rid of it!
NEXT EPISODE: DECISION