[theme music playing]
-[Soichiro] What?
-[man groaning]
I don't believe this.
Another 23 victims yesterday?
Are these confirmed?
[L] As soon as we began to suspect
that Kira might be a student,
the pacing of the killings changed,
as if to contradict that theory.
This can only mean that Kira has access
to police information.
[Light] When L discovers that I'm somehow
getting confidential information,
he'll be obligated to start investigating
the police to find the source of the leak.
You're being followed by another human.
He's watching you right now.
[Light] That's a problem.
I'll have to get rid of him
as soon as possible.
Because through a Shinigami's eyes,
a human's name can be seen
above their head.
Not only that.
We see their lifespan as well.
LIGHT YAGAMI
However, if a Shinigami drops
his Death Note and a human picks it up,
he can grant that human
the eyes of a Shinigami.
The price for having a Shinigami's eyes...
is half of that person's
remaining lifespan.
That's all it is.
So, what'll it be, Light? Is it a deal?
PURSUIT
Has anyone seen Ryuk around lately.
Maybe he was serious
about losing his Death Note.
It was probably picked up by some human
before he could get to it.
No way. Then he'd be stuck there
till the end of that human's life
or until the Death Note is destroyed.
That could take a while.
Yeah, I can't picture
Ryuk doing something so boring.
But you know what? I actually heard
he was carrying two Death Notes.
[Shinigami] Seriously?
Why would he need two?
Beats me. I'll never understand that guy.
[Light] So, the price for receiving
the eyes of a Shinigami
is no more than half
of my remaining lifespan?
That's it, right?
Yes.
Well then, do we have a deal or not?
Ryuk.
This deal is out of the question.
Huh?
[dog barking in the distance]
[Light] Let's get this straight.
My plan is to create an ideal new world
free from evil and all criminals,
and I intend to reign as a god
in that world for a very long time.
[Light] I might consider the deal
if it lengthened my life,
but not if I die sooner.
I figured you of all people
should know I wouldn't take this deal.
Yeah. I still felt I should tell you
that the deal existed, just in case.
Anyway, I've done my part.
I don't need you complaining
I didn't tell you this earlier on.
[Light] This is what you call
"telling me early on"?
Don't you think you're a little late?
I don't see why you couldn't have
told me this when we met.
Or better yet,
you could've simply included it
in the instructions for the Death Note.
Uh, good point.
He's not the slightest bit daunted
by the fact that I'm a Shinigami.
He doesn't suck up to me, and he seems
to have no problem giving me a hard time.
-[Light] Well?
-Huh?
You sure there's nothing else
you want to tell me "ahead of time,"
Shinigami?
No, nothing else.
Uh, probably.
-Really? That's too bad.
-What do ya mean?
You know, Ryuk, I might've seriously
considered the deal
if you'd offered me wings instead of eyes.
Just the idea of flying around
freely in the sky sounds very god-like.
After all, it's been mankind's dream
since antiquity to be able to fly.
You'd stand out if you sprouted wings
and flew around.
Not to mention the police would have
no trouble finding you.
I was only joking.
Anyway, if I keep bargaining for eyes
and wings and whatever else,
next thing you know I'm going to end up
becoming a real Shinigami.
Though who knows?
I bet that could be pretty interesting.
I wouldn't worry.
Even without the eyes and the wings,
you're already a worthy Shinigami.
[Ryuk] The Shinigami Realm
is slowly rotting.
We lead meaningless and empty lives.
And the only reason
we still take human lives
is because we're afraid to die ourselves.
The truth of the matter is, we no longer
even know why we exist.
In fact, I doubt there's any reason
for our existence at all.
What I'm saying is, compared to that,
you're becoming
a much more impressive Shinigami.
I don't know about that.
From what you're telling me,
it sounds like I'm doing
a lot more work than they are, but...
I don't want to be compared
to a Shinigami.
I'm a human using this Death Note
to make the world a better place
for other humans.
[Light] But I wouldn't necessarily say
that the Shinigami realm
is meaningless to humans either.
-Huh? Why do you say that?
-Well, just think about it.
Whenever a Shinigami like you
comes to the Human World
once every hundred, no,
more like every thousand years,
the Human World changes dramatically.
The existence of the Shinigami Realm
is extremely significant.
[Ryuk] Really?
[Light] You told me just now
that the Shinigami realm
is slowly rotting, right?
Well, when you return from this world,
why not use what you've learned here
to try and change it for the better?
Well, Light, I'm not sure
why I never noticed this until now
but you're quite the positive thinker.
[scoffs] Yeah, of course I am.
That's why I'm using the Death Note
to create a better world.
You have to be a positive thinker
to even attempt something like this.
[gasps]
[Light] That's it!
I got it!
Got what? What's this about?
I think I just figured out
how to find the name of the guy
who was following me today.
How are you gonna do that?
[Light] I'm gonna use the rules
of the Death Note to my advantage.
I already know that if I write down
a cause of death,
I've got six minutes and forty seconds
to record the conditions
and exact time of death.
First, I need to know
exactly how far I can go
in terms of specifying
the details of death.
This should be interesting.
THE FOLLOWING MORNING
[phone ringing]
Yeah, it's me.
Another six inmates
were found dead last night?
All were heart attacks?
It's him.
-What?
-Huh?
Bizarre behavior before they died?
Could you be more specific?
What do you mean?
So they didn't just die
from heart attacks.
No, what I'm saying
is they all died of heart attacks,
but it wasn't quite that simple.
Before one of them died,
he drew a pentagram on the wall
of his cell using his own blood.
Another left a letter, but it doesn't seem
to be a will or anything meaningful.
And as for the third victim,
he escaped from his cell
and ran all the way to the staff bathrooms
before he died.
[beeping]
[L] What is it, Watari?
Three more heart attack victims,
but the circumstances of their deaths
are different from what we've seen so far.
What do you mean by "different"?
I'm sending you a copy of a letter
as well as pictures taken at the scene.
Okay.
[L] It sounds like he was afraid
that Kira would find him.
It's believable that our victim
might have been genuinely afraid
and wrote this...
but we know Kira can control
the time of death.
What if he can also determine the actions
in the moments leading up to death?
In which case...
[L] Chief!
Huh?
[L] We can't release details
of these men's deaths to the media.
As far as they're concerned,
these are just heart attacks.
I have reason to believe that Kira
was performing some kind of test
using these criminals.
And if that's the case,
we'd only be giving him the results
of this information if we go public.
[Soichiro] Right, I understand.
So now he's experimenting on his victims?
Horrible.
He's playing with people's lives,
as if all this was just a game.
It's unforgivable.
[L] If Kira is really using criminals
as test subjects...
what is he trying to achieve?
[clicking]
Look at this, Ryuk.
I think we're in luck.
The results of yesterday's little "test"
have already been downloaded
onto my dad's computer.
KEITO NAWARAMI: KIDNAPPING, MURDER
These results are just as I expected.
The Death Note will work
for what I have in mind.
What do you mean by that?
One of them escaped
and ran into the bathroom
I had specified in the Death Note.
Another one drew the same symbol I'd
drawn in the Death Note before he died.
TAMIKI: HEART ATTACK
ESCAPES FROM CELL. DIED 6:00 P.M.
A third wrote the same letter I had
written in the Death Note. Word for word.
LORD HAVE MERCY
I'LL BE HANGED OR KILLED BY KIRA.
All three did exactly
what I intended them to do.
[Light] For the other three inmates,
I purposely wrote conditions
that were virtually impossible.
Huh?
YUZO FURA: DIES IN FRONT OF
THE EIFFEL TOWER TODAY AT 6:00 P.M.
With the first one, I wrote that he'd die
in front of the Eiffel Tower in one hour.
However, everyone knows it's physically
impossible to go from a prison in Japan
to Paris, France in only one hour.
Since this couldn't happen, he simply died
of a heart attack in prison.
The next was supposed to draw
an exact picture of L's face
on the prison wall.
KABEOKA: HEART ATTACK
DRAWS EXACT IMAGE OF L'S FACE
This also didn't happen. You can't draw
someone you've never seen, right?
[Ryuk] Makes sense.
SHINSHIRO YAMAMAE: HEART ATTACK
With the last one,
I tried something slightly different.
I specified that he'd write
a note that read,
"I know that L is suspicious
of the Japanese police."
To be honest,
I actually expected this one to work,
but it didn't end up happening.
Which means, it's impossible
to make someone write
what they don't already know.
Or at the very least,
it has to be the kind of thing
they could come up with on their own.
Basically, even the Death Note
can't do the impossible.
But, as long as it's within
the realistic limits
of what that person might do,
I can control them as much as I want
before they die.
That's very clever.
But what's all this leading to?
What's the point?
These latest victims will no doubt
keep L and the police guessing.
Even as we speak,
he's probably trying to decipher
all the clues I left for him.
Especially that little note.
That absolutely meaningless dying message.
[L] If Kira used those criminals
to conduct an experiment of some sort,
it means he's about to start something.
If he moves now, there's a good chance
the FBI will notice someone
acting suspiciously.
But perhaps he has a different goal
in mind altogether.
Could the pentagram and this letter
be some kind of message?
[gasps] Is this it?
L, DO YOU KNOW?
Alright. Time for the real thing.
The real thing?
Yesterday on the news,
they said this drug addict
tried to rob a bank but was unsuccessful.
WANTED CRIMINAL
KIICHIRO OSOREDA
He attacked a few people and then
ran away empty-handed. I'll use him.
It's kinda last minute,
but I'm sure I can find someone.
[Light] I got a few people in mind.
A few people? For what?
You'll see. Believe it or not,
I'm actually a rather popular guy, Ryuk.
[phone ringing]
[phone continues ringing]
Hello?
Uh huh, Light? Morning.
[indistinct chatter]
[Light] He's still following me.
Perfect.
This whole thing would just be
a waste of time if he wasn't tailing me.
[bus engine chugging]
Huh?
Light!
-A date?
-Yeah.
-[giggles]
-It's a date no matter how you look at it.
And I'm sure even my stalker
will see it that way.
But this isn't just a date, is it?
You said that you'd figured out a way
to find your stalker's name.
So, tell me, what do you plan on doing?
Huh? Come on. Didn't you see
what I wrote in the Death Note?
I explained it in great detail.
No. Doing that would take
all the fun out of it.
In that case, just be patient
and watch what happens.
-Sorry, did I keep you waiting?
-No, not at all!
Anyway, I haven't been
to Space Land since junior high!
I'm so excited!
And the best part is
I have you all to myself.
Uh, yeah.
[man] During the week, he goes to school
and cram school at night.
Dates on his day off.
A normal kid. Just a hardworking senior
in high school.
[man] Chief Yagami's son, Light Yagami.
No cause for suspicion.
[bus door hissing open]
At any rate, I'll be done
with my surveillance today.
And that'll be it.
[Yuri] I don't get it, Light.
Didn't you say you weren't going out
until entrance exams were over?
That was before I scored number one
on the national practice exams.
Ooo, you're such a nerd!
[Yuri giggles]
EMERGENCY EXIT
[bus approaching]
[door hissing open]
[Light] It's him! He's here.
Seven passengers excluding him,
no one's in the way.
Everything should go smoothly.
-[gun clicking]
-[driver exclaims]
Stay in your seats unless you wanna die!
[people exclaiming]
A bus-jacking? You gotta be kidding me.
Everybody, shut up!
If anybody moves,
I'm putting a bullet in their head.
Alright, driver, you listen to me.
I know you've got the number
for Space Land's office on you.
-Call them!
-Okay.
[driver] This-- This is Sasaki,
calling from bus 174.
Tell them what's going on,
and no tricks either!
My bus has been hijacked
and he's holding a gun to my head!
[Osoreda] Gimme that!
You heard what he said. Now you listen up!
Have a female staff member bring
all of Space Land's cash from yesterday.
I know it's there. Have her meet us
two bus stops from the park.
And don't make me wait!
If you mess with me at all
or try to get the police involved,
I swear I'll kill
every one of these passengers.
[grunts]
[Yuri whimpering]
[Light] Yuri, don't be scared.
As soon as he turns around,
I'm gonna grab the gun out of his hand.
Don't be stupid. That's risky.
If it comes to that, I'll take care of it.
It's okay. We don't have
to pass notes back and forth.
As long as we keep it down,
he won't be able to hear our voices
over the sound of the engine.
Do you have any proof
that you're not his accomplice?
Why should we trust you?
-Accomplice?
-Yes, I've read about this before.
The first hijacker comes in
like he's working alone.
Meanwhile, a second one
pretends to be a hostage
and stays in the very back,
just in case something goes wrong.
What's the matter?
You-- You really think he is one?
[man] I've-- I've no choice.
I'm sure Light Yagami isn't Kira.
If he was, he could just kill this guy
with a heart attack.
Here's proof. Take a look.
[Light] FBI?
I see. L needed an outsider,
so he got the FBI to investigate
anyone connected to the Japanese police.
His name is… Raye Penber.
[Light] I trust you.
And I guess for the time being
I won't bother asking
what an FBI agent is doing on the bus
in the first place.
-Do you have a gun?
-[Raye] Yeah, I've got one.
[Light] So if it comes down to it,
I can rely on you, right?
[Raye] Yes.
[Osoreda] Shut the hell up, you old hag!
You want me to shoot you right now?
[Raye] That's right!
This guy, his face was all over
the local news just a few days ago.
Some junkie who tried to rob a bank
and ended up killing three people
before he got away.
He's extremely dangerous.
[Light] We're safe. He won't shoot us.
In fact, he's not going to do anything.
Don't move, you little punk!
What the hell is that?
Smart-ass. You guys were planning
something back here, weren't ya?
Damn it. If he sees that note from before,
he'll find out that Light was planning
to jump on him and take his gun away.
MINAMI PARK BUS STOP, 11:27
SPACE LAND BUS STOP
[Osoreda] Plans for a date, huh?
Stupid kid.
Gotcha.
Huh? [gasps]
Who the hell are you?
You in the very back!
What do you think you're doing?
Don't mess with me!
How long have you been hiding back there?
What's this? You're talking to me?
So you mean you can actually
see me right now?
[exclaims] Stay there, you!
You keep away from me, you freak!
This isn't good. He's hallucinating!
Everyone, get down!
[all screaming]
Oh, I get it.
That little note that Light
accidentally dropped
was actually torn from the pages
of the Death Note itself.
Since he tricked this guy
into touching the paper,
he's the only other one on the bus
who can see me.
That's so smart.
Get away!
[Osoreda yelling]
Sorry, pal.
I'm a Shinigami, so I'm afraid
your bullets aren't gonna kill me.
[screaming]
[screaming and gunshots]
-[Osoreda continues screaming]
-[gun clicking]
[whimpering]
[Ryuk] Anyone who touches
the Death Note can see me.
I have to stay till the Death Note
is finished or I see you die.
Whichever comes first.
And a Shinigami can't die from being shot.
I've said all these things
at one time or another.
Well, he is the top-ranked student
in the country.
Guess I shouldn't be surprised.
He even used this hijacking
as a way to get the guy following him
to willingly give up his name.
Stop the bus! Let me off!
[brakes screeching]
SPACE LAND
[panting]
[tires screeching]
[Light] Eleven forty-five on the dot.
Everything went just as I planned.
[Light] "Kiichiro Osoreda.
Accidental death.
Boards the 11:31 Space Land-bound bus
near the eastern entrance to the park,
holding a loaded gun
and attempts to hijack the bus.
He sees a horrific phantom
and empties his gun trying to kill it.
Terrified, he flees the bus.
Immediately afterwards, at 11:45,
he dies when struck by a car."
[Light] The Death Note never fails.
You will be next, Raye Penber.
TO BE CONTINUED