Within the spreading darkness
I pledged a vow to the revolution
I can't let anybody interrupt it
I'm going to change
The future that
the forbidden fruit foretells...
I'm going to change
The dream into reality
The ending
That everybody wants
Within the spreading darkness
I pledged our vow to the revolution
I can't let anybody interrupt it
Someday I'll show you
A bright and ideal
World
I can't believe my diligent son
is looking at a magazine like that!
Light, it's time for dinner...
I'll solve equations
with my right hand...
And write names with my left.
Grab a potato chip. . .And eat it!
The witness to my alibi is L himself.
ENCOUNTER
Are you sure, Ryuk?
Yeah. You definitely aren't being followed.
G-Give it to me quickly.
My withdrawal symptoms are...
You're not saying that
just because you want an apple, are you?
Hey, hey!
I flew around, above you a bunch...
up to a radius of a hundred-meters.
I'm sure.
But there was the news report
about Interpol dispatching 1,500 investigators...
You know they were bluffing.
You said it yourself.
If it were real, they would sneak in
and investigate secretly.
All right, Ryuk.
I'll buy you an apple.
All right!
Thank you very much.
Light! Hurry! Hurry!
You know, the way you go around treating
Shinigami...
You had me search for cameras...
And made me give up
eating apples in the house.
Eat the core too...
In the end, I'll write your name
into my Death Note and kill ya!
Are you in a position to laugh?
That's right. There's just one thing left
to top everything off.
Ryuzaki...
Yes?
About the purse-snatcher and embezzler's
heart attacks two days ago...
That happened before my family
had any knowledge of it.
Have they been cleared?
I suppose you're right...
Even though Kira can control
the time of death,
I don't think that there's any way
he could set up his victims without
watching that broadcast-!
Your son has come home again.
So, you're gonna ignore me and act like
you're studying again, huh?
I already have an idea of
where all the cameras are.
But I was only able to kill
a purse-snatcher and an embezzler
with the potato-chip trick...
SUSPECT: TAYOSHI MURAO
They ended up being minor criminals
compared to those I've killed until now.
- Next on the news- - -
- Are you going to watch I V?
I killed criminals whose names
and faces were broadcast
when I didn't have access
to TV or the Internet.
But there still is a chance
that I'll be suspected because
only minor criminals die
when I don't have any information...
- ...an investigation has been opened...
- In other words...
If I also kill minor criminals
being broadcast when I watch TV...
I won't call attention to myself.
Also, when Igo out...
regardless of the severity
of the crime...
I should remember the names
of criminals broadcast...
And kill them at random times...
with the piece of the Death Note
I left in my wallet.
Now, my countermeasures against
the surveillance cameras are perfect.
During these past few days...
I have checked the tapes
and video footage many times.
I've come to a conclusion.
Of the people in the Kitamura and Yagami families,
suspicious activity was observed in...
...l'1O 0H8.
I shall remove the cameras
and wiretaps.
So, in the end the culprit
wasn't here, huh?
Don't lower your guard!
We're going to narrow down
our possibilities once more.
Please don't misunderstand...
I just meant that there wasn't
anyone suspicious
from what I could see
from our footage.
Even if Kira is among them,
he wouldn't give himself away.
No.
It means that he was killing criminals
as usual, without showing it.
So are you saying one of them
might be Kira?
As I said...
There's a five-percent probability.
Kira was still killing people even while
the surveillance cameras were in place...
I don't know how he does it...
But even if he's able to kill
just by imagining it...
...any normal human being would exhibit
a change in their facial expressions
or behaviors while
committing the murders...
"Kira is not among them,"
is what most people would conclude.
But... If one of them is Kira...
His psychological state
has already reached god-like levels.
Judging sinners without
any change in expression.
I want to believe that Kira
doesn't really exist...
that this really is divine judgment.
But, to think that a god would
need a person's face and name to kill is ridiculous.
This isn't divine judgment.
I129 the actions of a child/Sh killer
who thinks he is a god.
That's all.
The mass murderer known
as Kira definitely exists.
And I will catch him.
But I don't think that Kira will
expose himself
even if I keep
these cameras in place...
What should I do?
It would be best to get him to
tell me himself that he's Kira,
and have him
show me how he kills...
But there's no way I can...
Hey, Light. All the cameras
have been removed!
All of them, all of them!
Hey Light, are you listening?
Hey, Light.
Oh, I get it.
The wiretaps might still be here.
I'm no longer a suspect.
It went exactly the way I'd planned.
But I will probably continue
to pursue Kira.
And if he's still working
with the Japanese police...
My father will be among
those being used.
If that's the case...
I'll use my father to find
out L's identity so I can...
eliminate him...
If I just get rid ofL...
Kira will be one step closer
to becoming the god of the new world.
Light, hurry up.
Do your best!
Good luck, Light!
Really, you're making such
a big fuss over this.
I'll be going now.
It sure feels good, now that we know
that there aren't any wiretaps.
Well, it's nice to know
that one cause of stress
is gone before my test.
2007 TEST CENTER FOR UNIVERSITY ADMISSIONS
TO-OH UNIVERSITY TEST
You there! The test will start
in ten minutes! Hurry up!
I was planning on going in
three minutes before the test
because I didn't want to wait around
in the classroom...
I sure got here early.
Talk about confident...
You may begin.
You there... Number 162...
Sit in your seat properly!
There's been
a lot of Shinigami...
looking real hard into
the human world lately.
What's going on?
It seems that Ryuk has turned
into some human's pet.
W-What in the world is he thinking?
Really. He's a disgrace to
all Shinigami.
No, I'm talking about the human
who's keeping him.
Ryuk's probably not a very cute pet.
Well, yeah.
So, what kind of human's keeping him?
Is it a woman? A man?
Who knows?
Guess I'll go take a peek as well...
Good grief!
2007 TO-OH UNIVERSITY
ENTRANCE CEREMONY
So you're a college student
now, huh, Light?
I'm kind of...filled with emotion.
Now for our freshman address.
Our freshman representative,
Light Yagami.
Yes.
Oh, wow.
And other freshman representative,
Hideki Ryuga.
Oh! Yeah...
Hideki Ryuga, the pop idol?!
Couldn't be... There's no way
he's smart enough to enter To-oh.
Ah... You're right. He doesn't even
look anything like him.
I heard I was going to be giving
the address with someone else, but...
I never thought
it was going to be him.
He's the guy who was sitting weird
behind me on the first day of the Exams.
He completely stood out...
from everyone else.
Life springs renewed
in the breath of Spring...
The person who scored highest on
the test is supposed to do this, right?
That just means that there were
two top scorers this year...
I heard they both
scored 100% in all subjects.
Seriously?!
I guess there really are
people like that.
I definitely like the guy on the right!
What-?! Kyoko, you're weird!
Most people would choose
the one on the left.
But those two sure are different...
Yeah...
One looks like a brilliant genius
from a sheltered family.
The other...
Life springs renewed
in the breath of Spring...
Seems wild. ..
Or at least very weird...
Is that what people
would call a genius?
He's doing the address...
for the To-oh entrance ceremony
dressed like that.
He is either not taking this seriously
or an idiot.
Thank you very much...
Hideki Ryuga.
Yagami...
You are the son of Soichiro Yagami,
Detective Superintendent of the NPA.
You have a sense of justice
which rivals that of
your respect for your father.
What is with this guy?
You aim to become an NPA official...
and have helped the police to
solve several cases in the past.
You're now showing great interest
in the Kira case.
I have faith in your sense of
justice and abilities,
and if you swear not to tell anyone,
I'll tell you something very important
concerning the Kira case.
What is this all of a sudden?
Should I just ignore him?
But what is this important information
concerning the Kira case?
I won't tell anyone. What is it?
I'm L.
I-It couldn't be!
What is he talking about?!
There's no way that
I would say that he's L.
I thought he was weird,
but is he actually insane?
T-This isn't good.
Don't be shocked.
If he really is L...
I have to act naturally,
like how
Soichiro Yagami's son, Light would act.
If you truly are who you say you are,
I respect and admire you.
Thank you...
I revealed myself
because I think that
you can be of help in solving
the Kira case.
Light Yagami...
The probability that you are Kira
is just under five percent.
But out of everyone we were watching,
I sensed something from you.
You're too perfect.
And if you're Kira, there's nothing that
could pressure you more than this.
If this guy's really L,
he's something else.
Indeed. . .if he really is L.
No, even if he isn't L...
I...
I can't do anything to him!
If what he's saying is true,
he's probably already shown
his face to my father.
If he dies as soon as he reveals
himself to me,
then it would immediately
cast suspicion onto me.
And he's using an obvious
alias like "Hideki Ryuga. "
If his name really
isn't Hideki Ryuga
and I try to kill him by writing
his name in the Death Note...
HIDEKI RYUGA
Ryuga, the pop star's face will pop up
in my head whether! want it to or not...
and he may die instead...
But he won't die and
he'll infer that I'm Kira.
Is he really L-?
And does he suspect that I'm Kira?
I don't know how much he knows,
but I'm sure he suspects me.
There's no other reason for him to
tell Soichiro Yagami's son that he's L.
Does this mean that
he's still focusing on
the people that
Raye Penber was investigating?
But why would L approach
me directly-?
Not now...
It's better to keep my mind blank.
I need to look calm.
He's definitely watching me to
see if I'm rattled or not...
2007 TO-OH UNIVERSITY
ENTRANCE CEREMONY
Light, that was a fun
college entrance ceremony.
Yagami.
Hey, Light... He's calling you.
It was nice to meet you...
No, the pleasure was all mine...
What an amazing car...
A limousine?
Well, I'll see you around campus.
Oh, yeah.
Where is that rich kid from?
And he's even at the top of the class?
What a jerk.
Welcome home,
To-oh University student!
Damn it! He got me!
He "got you". . .?
Damn it, L... I've never been
so humiliated in my life!
Hey, why don't you just do
the Shinigami eye deal with me
and just kill him?
What good would that
do if this is a trap?!
If he's not really L, then that would
be just like telling L that I'm Kira!
S-Sorry...
Shinigami killing people and
humans killing people
aren't the same thing.
I want to kill him,
no matter what it takes,
but if I do,
it'll be traced back to me...
The Death Note can only kill
a person whose name I write in it...
I cannot control someone
to kill someone else.
The Death Note is
a pain in the ass!
Light is usually calm,
but he's fuming now...
He's pretty annoyed.
At first, I thought that when
I found out his name,
I'd have him get in
an accident or commit suicide.
But it's no good unless
I know a hundred percent that he's L.
No. Even if I do know it's him,
it may be too late.
No matter what the cause of death,
if L dies, I'll cast suspicion on me...
I underestimated him...
I never thought that I would
come up to me and say, "I'm L!"
He just has to tell all
the suspects that he is L.
Even if he's his double...
This is a solid defense as well as
an attack against Kira.
He beat me...
It was a good move...
Ryuga will continue to play dumb and
probably continue to approach me
and manipulate me at the university...
This is great...
There's nothing to worry about.
This proves that they don't have
anything on me...
It's a contest between L and me.
It's a game of wits!
On the surface, we'll be
friendly acquaintances on campus.
In reality, we'll be investigating each other,
"Are you L?" or "Are you Kira?"
This will be fun, Ryuga.
If it's friendship you want from me,
I'll gladly accept.
I'll make you trust me...
And once I've pulled everything
out of you, I will kill you...
with my own hands!
TO BE CONTINUED
I dreamed a dream
that no one could see,
I threw away everything
that I didn't need
I'm holding these feelings
That I can't give up in my heart
Even if my feet fall victim
to the shackles of sacrifice
In between reality and my ideal
I can't hold back
the flooding impulses
Because I have a strong desire
To accomplish
[deceit] [fear] [vanity] [melancholy]
I'm not weak enough to believe
Any of these negative perceptions
I'm a trickster
who doesn't know solitude
PREVIEW
Hideki Ryuga, L...
There's no way that he could
profile me with this tennis game.
He has some other goal in mind.
But even if it is tennis,
I will win!
NEXT EPISODE: DOUBT