[theme music playing]
[rattling]
[door thuds]
[Light] How many seconds has it been
since you wrote down the first name?
Thirty-five, 36, 37,
thirty-eight, 39...
Well, Near, looks like I win.
[Mikami] Forty!
NEW WORLD
[both shuddering]
[Matsuda] Huh?
We're still alive.
It's been over a minute
and we haven't died!
Didn't I already tell you all
that no one was gonna die?
[Mikami stammering] But why?
Why won't they die?
[shuddering breathing]
[Mikami] God!
I did everything you told me!
Rester, Gevanni, take him now!
[Mikami yelling frantically]
Gevanni, the notebook, please.
If you didn't believe me earlier,
then see for yourselves.
KANZO MOGI TOUTA MATSUDA
HIDEKI IDE SHUICHI AIZAWA
I can confirm that the first four names
are definitely the real names
of the SPK members.
The second four are the names
of your team.
The only name that hasn't
been written down...
is Light Yagami.
[snarling]
[Near] If that weren't enough,
Mikami also addressed you as "God,"
and said he did what you asked him to.
It's settled.
[Light breathes shakily]
It's a trap! This whole thing is a setup!
This is all part of Near's plan
to frame me!
Isn't it a little odd that no one died
after having their name
written in the notebook?
This proves it's a trap!
[Matsuda gasps]
[whimpering]
I believe I already told you
that no one would die
-because I modified the notebook.
-[Light gasps]
No! You-- [panting]
[huffs] That can't be!
This is a setup. I don't know this guy!
[begins sobbing]
Light, it's too late to deny it.
You know Near has won.
Just a moment ago, you were saying,
"It looks like I win."
How much more of a confession
do we need?
[Matsuda] Light...
Why?
[gasps] Stop it!
[yelling in panic]
[panting]
Light Yagami. L. Kira.
It's over. You've lost the game.
Just a moment ago,
you proclaimed your victory,
expecting us all to die.
And to tell the truth,
you might've actually won.
And I would've lost.
We ended up doing exactly
what you expected us to,
and altered the fake notebook
in Mikami's possession.
However, when I said before
that we had modified the notebook,
I was in fact referring
to the real notebook as well as the fake.
[gasps]
We only switched part
of the fake notebook.
But as for the real one,
we replaced the entire thing.
This notebook here
is actually the real one.
[gasps] No! Impossible!
[Near] We used the same kind
of pen that Mikami used,
copied his handwriting perfectly,
and made both the inside
and the outside of our fake
look exactly like the original.
Gevanni was able to do it
in a single night.
Of course, since I had touched
the real notebook before coming,
I've been able to see the Shinigami
as well.
-Ah...
-[Aizawa] Huh?
It's a pleasure to meet you,
Mr. Shinigami. I'm Near.
[cackles] Nice to meet you too.
My name is Ryuk.
[Light] He can talk to Ryuk.
He can see him, so that means...
it must be true.
[Near] Some of the edges
of this notebook's pages are torn.
Tell me, if someone's name was written
on a ripped off piece of paper,
would they still die?
Oh, yeah. Of course they would.
[Near] I thought so.
I bet you were able to use that
to your advantage.
I wonder how many times you deceived us
with this, and how many people you killed.
Light Yagami, you are Kira.
[Light] This has gotta be a trick.
Or could it be that Mikami's betrayed me
somehow?
-[Near] You're mistaken.
-[gasps]
This was all thanks to Mello.
I believe if I explain this much,
you'll begin to understand.
[Light] What? Mello?
Please take a look at this page
of the notebook.
[gasps]
KIYOMI TAKADA SUICIDE
BURNS TO DEATH
[Light] Takada's name is in the notebook!
[panting] I was the one who killed her,
but her death was written there
just one minute later.
JANUARY 26 2:33 PM
Does that mean Mikami
did the same thing I did?
God! You told me you couldn't move freely.
I had to make sure Takada
was taken care of!
Wasn't that my duty to you?
[Light] You idiot!
I gave you strict orders not to make
any unnecessary movements until today!
It's all true.
On the 26th,
right after Takada's kidnapping
was broadcast on the news,
Mikami went to the bank.
I've been trailing him.
I knew he went to the bank
everyone month on the 25th.
So, it was odd for someone so methodical
to go to the bank twice in two days.
I followed Mikami to the bank as he headed
for the safe deposit boxes.
It was only at this time
that he seemed concerned
whether someone was following him or not.
I got into his safe deposit box.
Inside was the real notebook.
Sure enough, Takada's name had already
been written inside it.
[Near] Do you understand now,
Light Yagami?
You didn't realize
that Mikami made a move on his own
and wrote Takada's name in his notebook
because you had already killed her
using a notebook clipping yourself.
This was the event that made me consider
the possibility of a fake notebook.
We were able to stop you
thanks to the efforts of one person.
It was Mello who did it all.
[Lidner] Mello probably knew
what was going to happen all along.
[Mello] It can be resolved by having
a name written in the notebook?
That's right.
[Mello] Well then, if I don't do it...
I bet Mello knew in his heart
that working by ourselves, neither of us
would be able to attain our goal.
and surpass our mentor, L.
But together...
together, we can stand with L.
Together, we can surpass L!
And now, acting as one,
we face the Kira who defeated L,
and with solid evidence,
beat him at his own game!
Let's see you try and talk your way
out of this one... if you can.
[Light laughs softly]
[laughing intensifies]
[laughing maniacally]
[Light] That's right...
I am Kira.
That's right. I am Kira.
And what can you do?
Kill me right here?
Hear this. I'm not only Kira.
But I'm also...
God of the new world!
Kira has become law in the world
we now live.
He's the one who's maintaining order.
I have become Justice.
The only hope for mankind.
[snickers] Kill me?
Is that really the right thing to do?
Since Kira's appearance six years ago,
wars have stopped
and global crime rates have been
reduced by over 70 percent.
But, it's not enough.
This world is still rotten!
With too many rotten people.
Somebody has to do this!
When I first got that notebook,
all those years ago,
I knew I had to do it.
No, I was the only one who could!
I understood that killing people
was a crime...
[glass shattering]
There was no other way!
The world had to be fixed!
A purpose given to me!
Only I could do it.
Who else could have done it?
And come this far?
Would they have kept going?
The only one...
who can create a new world... is me.
No. You're just a murderer, Light Yagami.
And this notebook is the deadliest
weapon of mass murder
in the history of mankind.
You yielded to the power
of the Shinigami and the notebook.
And you have confused yourself
with a god.
In the end, you're nothing more
than a crazy serial killer.
That's all you are.
Nothing more and nothing less.
[Light] Useless fools.
As if they could ever understand.
[Light] Near.
Here's some food for thought.
That notebook you have,
and the one that Aizawa brought
from the Japanese Task Force Headquarters.
Are they both real?
[Near] What is he up to?
Is he bluffing?
[Light] At the moment, only I know
where the real notebook is.
If you truly wanna defeat Kira,
as well as test the notebook
that Aizawa's carrying...
I guess you're gonna have to write down
either my name or Mikami's.
It's the only way to see if it's real...
or fake!
He's hidden a piece of the notebook!
[Light yells]
Matsuda!
[growling]
Matsuda, you idiot!
Who the hell do you think
you're shooting at?
Don't screw with me!
What was it all for, then?
What about your dad?
What the hell did he die for?
[wheezing] My dad?
[laughs] You mean Soichiro Yagami?
That's right, Matsuda!
In this world, all those earnest people
like him who fight for justice,
they always lose. You want a world where
people like that are made to be fools?
I know you understand, so kill the others!
Shoot them!
You led your own father to his death.
And now he's gone, you call him a fool?
-His blood!
-[Matsuda yells]
[gunshots]
-I'll kill him!
-[Light gasping for air]
I'll kill him! He has to die!
[gunshot echoing]
[Matsuda whimpering]
[Light grunting]
[Light] Damn you.
What the hell is this?
Mikami! What are you waiting for?
Write down their names!
Write them down! Kill them now!
[Mikami breathing shakily]
[Mogi] It's finally over, isn't it Near?
[Near] Yes.
[wheezing]
Where are you Misa?
Where's Takada? [sobs]
[wheezing] Someone...
[sobbing] What do I do now?
[Mikami screaming]
Mikami!
[Aikawa] Quick. Stop the bleeding!
[Gevanni] It's already too late.
He'll be dead in a few seconds.
Wait, Light!
[gasps]
He's getting away! Light!
-[Near] Mr. Aizawa!
-Huh?
It's unlikely he has any more pieces
of the notebook.
And with those wounds,
he's not going to go far.
He'll stop running soon,
even if we leave him alone.
Huh. Near, I'm not gonna follow
your orders.
Huh?
Very well, then. I'll leave it up to you.
[Light breathing shakily]
[Light begins sobbing]
[panting]
[Ryuk] Well, Light,
it looks like you've lost.
Remember how, in the beginning,
when we first met,
I told you that I'd be the one
writing your name in my notebook?
That is part of the agreement
between a Shinigami who brings a notebook
to the human world...
and the first human who picks it up.
If they put you in prison,
who knows when you'd die?
And I don't wanna lie around waiting.
So, it's all over.
You'll die here.
It was good while it lasted.
We eased each other's boredom
for quite a while.
Well, Light, it's been interesting.
LIGHT YAGAMI
[soft piano music playing]