[theme music plays]
[Near] The current Kira is foolish
and overconfident,
not to mention unusually cooperative
with the Task Force.
In fact, I suspect he's working
hand in hand with them.
-You think so?
-That would make the second L and Kira...
one and the same person.
-[monitor beeping]
-[Near] To the members
of the Japanese Task Force...
Was there ever a point
in the investigation
where the second L
was suspected to be Kira,
even if the suspicion was later dropped?
[Light] Near... I have to kill him!
[panting] This is really bad!
Turn on the TV! It's Demegawa.
This is Demegawa, live.
My comrades and I have finally pinpointed
the hideout of the evil organization
bent on trying to catch
-our beloved god, Kira.
-[mob yelling]
We now have the building
completely surrounded!
TRANSFER
[tires screeching]
[jingle playing on TV]
[Demegawa] Fellow Kira supporters,
I urge you, do not rush the building
all at once.
The traitors may attempt to blend in
with the crowd to escape.
I am Kira's loyal servant and spokesman.
You must listen to me!
Find them, move them from the building,
and bring them in front of the cameras!
-They'll be a sacrifice to Kira!
-[glass cracking]
[mob yelling]
You can't hide from me. I'll find you.
Near, you've got no choice.
You better evacuate.
You've got some nerve to say that,
being Kira.
What? Are you still going on
about that nonsense?
Think about it.
With all the anti-Kira groups around,
why is it we're being targeted,
and right after I start suspecting you?
Pretty convenient, if you ask me.
[Light] Near, with all due respect,
you're wrong.
You're jumping to conclusions.
[Near] Members of the Task Force,
please listen to me.
Kira is likely amongst you.
Even as we speak, he is in that room.
I'm simply asking you
to think about this carefully.
[Aizawa sighs]
[Aizawa] "Light is Kira."
This is all sounding way too familiar.
The original L also thought
that Light had to be Kira.
[mob yelling]
The first wave of 20 people
will break the door and get inside!
-Second wave, stand by!
-[man grunting]
Out of the way, idiot!
We're the first wave!
What? Like hell! We're going first!
-Near, we have to evacuate immediately.
-[glass shattering]
[Near] Really, what pathetic people.
I'm not surprised
that there are ordinary people
who support what Kira's trying to do.
I'm talking about honest citizens,
who believe in their hearts
that by punishing evil doers,
Kira will actually make this world
a better place to live.
But as for this crowd outside,
they're a completely different breed.
They are truly despicable and stupid.
This is just a diversion for them.
They're all selfish.
I-- I know that, but it still leaves us
with the immediate problem.
[Near] We'll use L's legacy
and the anti-Kira protestors we hired.
Yes, but we only have one shot
with that plan.
I'm aware of that, but I can't imagine
a better time to do it.
Besides, it should be interesting.
[mob yelling]
Huh? It's...
-It's money!
-[mob yelling and laughing]
Money? It's so much!
[Matsuda] What? Whoa.
That's a lot. Amazing!
Man, I wish I were over there right now.
Matsuda!
[laughs] Humans are so interesting.
Of course you can use money to get apples,
so I can kind of understand.
-[man 1] I grabbed it first, you bastard!
-[man 2] Out of the way!
[Light] Damn it! He's planning to use
all this chaos to escape into the crowd.
Even so, he can't escape
from Demegawa's cameras.
Over there, pilot! Go to the floor
where all the money's coming from!
Jeez! What are you doing, Demegawa?
Don't you know that you can't
buy love and peace with money?
[Light snarls]
A literal downpour of money
is causing mayhem in Lower Manhattan.
-[reporter] The police have arrived.
-[Light gasps] The police?
[reporter]
They're a welcome sight in the midst
of what can only be called
a full-scale riot.
[Light] This is bad. At this rate...
[Near] Let's go.
This is our window of opportunity.
We can leave via the front exit.
It makes sense that the police would have
to mobilize for a riot like this.
[Light] Damn! Near was prepared
for this situation.
He's planning to come out
along with the rest of them,
and if I tell Aizawa and the others
to keep an eye on the police,
it'll only make me look
that much more suspicious.
[reporter] The police are coming out
of the building. They've secured the area.
[Light] Where is he?
He's gotta be in there somewhere!
But where?
[gasps]
Damn it.
[sirens wailing]
[indistinct police radio chatter]
[groans] How much money
do you think was there?
-Bet it was a lot.
-[Ide] Matsuda, knock it off!
[Matsuda] I bet it was around ten million
dollars or something.
[Ryuk] Ooh, what's that in apples?
-[monitor beeping]
-[gasps]
-Near!
-Already?
-[Near] This is Near.
-[groans]
We've reestablished a secure connection,
so I thought I should give you a call
to let you know.
[Light] You're safe. That's a relief.
To all of you on the Task Force...
I'm sure that by now, some of you
are starting to suspect
that Kira may be one of you.
Given the timing of today's attack
on our headquarters,
I don't think anyone could blame you
for having doubts.
If you don't suspect the second L
of being Kira by now,
you're in the wrong line of work.
The number I gave you
the day before has been reconnected.
Please feel free to call anytime you like.
-Well then, I'll be waiting for your call.
-[Aizawa sighs]
[chuckles]
Those were some strong words.
This guy's pretty sure of himself.
I've been thinking, and if any of you want
to cooperate with Near, please go ahead.
I'm not particularly satisfied
with the way things are going either.
Ideally, we should cooperate with the SPK.
Maybe this will clear the air a little.
[Matsuda] Still, it kind of feels
like Near's against us, doesn't it?
[Aizawa sighs] When I think
about Deputy Director Yagami,
I don't wanna suspect Light,
even a little bit, but… [sighs]
-[Yumi] Dad?
-Huh?
Welcome back. I didn't know
you were gonna be home tonight.
Oh, yeah. What are you still doing awake?
I've got a couple of exams coming up.
I see. Well, don't push yourself
too hard, okay?
-'Kay. You too, Dad.
-[chuckles]
Hmm...
[ice cubes clinking]
[Light] I wouldn't be surprised
if one of the others contacted Near.
It's inevitable.
The problem is what comes after that.
If I'm too late to act,
something might happen
that I won't be able to take back.
I've got no choice but to do it.
[beeping]
[squeals] An emergency order
from Light! Yay!
[chuckles]
Hmm, file number three.
Huh? [gasps]
No way...
[phone ringing]
[Near] Yes, this is Near.
[Aizawa] I'm with the Japanese Task Force.
My name is Aizawa.
[bird chirping]
[Misa] So, the time has finally come.
If I do this, my safety is guaranteed,
and I can finally just be a normal wife.
This is what Light wants for me!
He wants me to be happy,
just as a woman should be.
Thank you, Light.
[Near] I see. That's very interesting.
You're saying there were two suspects
in the Kira investigation
that the previous L detained
for more than 50 days,
and they were cleared
based on the 13-day rule, correct?
[Aizawa] Yes, but of course,
that alone doesn't prove they were Kira.
[Near] And L was willing to release them
because of that?
[Aizawa] No. L had Deputy Director Yagami,
the chief detective at the time,
put on an act.
He was instructed to tell the suspects
that they had both been found guilty
of being Kira and the second Kira,
and that they were going to be executed.
Then, on the way,
the Deputy Director pulled over
and pointed a gun at the suspects.
He said that he would first kill Kira,
then himself.
[Near] Huh.
[Aizawa] The idea was
that if he were Kira,
the suspect would've killed the chief
right then and there.
[Near] Kira is quite impressive.
He must have used his detainment
to demonstrate his innocence.
Well done.
Out of curiosity, did the suspect
volunteer to be detained
-as part of the investigation?
-Hmm...
Come to think of it,
Light did volunteer to be imprisoned.
[Near] If he did, then I'd say
that settles the matter, wouldn't you?
So, who was it?
Who were those two suspects?
Hmm. I can't tell you that much.
I'm willing to cooperate,
but I'm still a member
of the Japanese Task Force,
working under L.
[Near] I understand.
Thank you very much.
Your information's been quite valuable.
Especially the part about Shinigami's eyes
that enable you to see
other people's names.
-It was very helpful. Goodbye.
-[hangs up]
[sighs]
[Rester] Will that be enough, Near?
Shouldn't you have pressed
for a little more information?
I think that all things considered,
his level of cooperation is fine for now.
And besides, I discovered something
very important.
The person suspected of being Kira
is Deputy Director Yagami's son.
Hmm?
[Near] It's the only possible explanation.
Why else would the Deputy Director say
he would kill Kira and then himself?
Therefore, that means the second L,
and the person I think is Kira
can only be one man...
Light Yagami.
-[Aizawa] Light.
-Yes?
There's something you should know.
I phoned Near and talked to him.
[Matsuda gasps]
[Light] Don't worry about it.
After all, I was the one
who recommended it.
So, what did the two of you
end up discussing?
[stammers] No, on second thought,
I probably shouldn't ask.
I guess it's not appropriate for me to ask
those kinds of questions if I'm a suspect.
[Aizawa] Hmm...
Don't get me wrong.
I wanna believe that you aren't Kira.
But I've gotta be certain.
I'm sorry to have to do this again,
but I wanna put you under surveillance
until we catch Kira.
I'm afraid that goes for Misa Amane
as well.
I'm gonna search your place right now.
There's a possibility that Amane
might have a notebook.
[Matsuda] Hang on a second, Aizawa!
[Light] No, go right ahead.
Look at it this way,
at least you can prove to everyone
that I'm not sneaking around
and contacting Misa in private, right?
-[keyboard clicking]
-[Matsuda grunts]
[door closes]
Huh? Mogi?
I'm coming with you.
I wanna make sure too.
[Aizawa] Hmm...
It would be best for everyone
if Light wasn't Kira,
but if Amane has any evidence on her
that connects her with Kira, then...
[Aizawa sighs]
[doorbell rings]
[both gasp]
[Misa] Mochi! Monchichi!
Long time no see, you two!
Light hasn't been home at all lately,
so I've been super bored.
[Aizawa groans] Well, there's no way
she's got the notebook hidden
on her dressed like that.
We're just investigating a tip
that there were explosives
planted in L's house.
We think it's a prank,
but we'd like to check the rooms
just in case.
[Misa gasps] What? How about Light?
Is he okay? I have to call him.
No. You can't call him right now.
How come?
[Aizawa] Don't worry. Light's safe
but he's really busy right now.
He has some other things he has to do
so he's handed the investigation
over to us for the time being.
Oh, I get it. Light loves me like crazy,
so he doesn't want me to call him
'cause that'll only make him worry
about me.
[Light] Search as much
as you like, Aizawa.
You won't find the notebook.
[Misa yawns]
Mm, I wouldn't like all this suspicion
to ruin the atmosphere around here.
This isn't a social club.
I think Aizawa and Mogi should do
as they see fit.
Hmm. [sighs]
It's time for Kira's Kingdom.
[jingle playing on TV]
KIRA'S KINGDOM
[Demegawa] Greetings to all
my fellow Kira worshippers.
I am Demegawa, the voice of our god, Kira.
Behold! This is the new Kira's Kingdom,
which shares its name with this program.
Its construction is going smoothly
but will depend on the generous support...
ARCHITECT'S CONCEPT
...of our loyal viewers.
Once it has been completed,
let us welcome our god here!
Whoa, talk about bad taste.
[sighs]
[grunts] Hey, so is everything okay?
Oh, yeah. Seems like it was just a prank.
-Oh.
-But just in case,
one of us is gonna stay and keep watch
over you for the next few days.
Really? Oh, that would be great.
Mogi, why don't you go back
to headquarters?
I'll stay on guard here.
Huh? I'm with Monchichi instead of Mochi?
Hmm? What's wrong? Don't you trust me?
No, you're just not Monchichi
without your old haircut.
You're not cute anymore.
-[Mogi chuckles]
-[Aizawa grumbles] Mogi!
Yes, sir, my apologies.
All right, you stay.
[rock music playing]
We are now accepting donations,
starting at the million Yen mark
towards the completion of Kira's Kingdom!
So, if you truly support Kira...
[Matsuda] This sounds like a con.
[Ide] Yep. Just another scam
at this point.
It doesn't even seem like Kira's style.
[Light] Demegawa...
He's just acting on his own now.
If he keeps doing this, he'll end up
pushing people away from Kira.
I don't need him anymore.
But I can't do much at the moment.
[Matsuda] Hey, welcome back, Aizawa.
[Aizawa] We didn't find a notebook
in Light or Misa's room.
-But still...
-[Light] I understand.
You're more than welcome to keep watch
over Misa and I until you're satisfied.
[Demegawa] Next on the program,
it's time for me to introduce
the new leaders I have chosen
for Kira's Kingdom!
The first gentleman is...
[Mikami] Delete.
[splutters and groans]
[all gasp]
[stammering] We will unite with Kira
and work with him!
[Mikami] Delete.
[man groaning]
-[Mikami] Delete!
-[man yells]
[Mikami] Delete!
[Demegawa panting]
[gasps] Save me!
And delete.
-[heart pumping]
-[Demegawa yells]
SAKURA TV
PLEASE STAND BY
[Aizawa gasps] What the hell is this?
Why would Kira kill his own supporters?
[Matsuda] Do you think it's because
they're going overboard with this?
That might be a possibility.
But this is horrible.
[Aizawa] What's going on?
There was no chance
for either Misa Amane or Light
to use the notebook to kill Demegawa.
[Light] Mikami...
I can definitely use him!
It seems I was right
to choose him for this.
He understands Kira's beliefs
and ideals perfectly.
And he knows what Kira wants
and doesn't want.
Thanks to that, he takes action
without needing my orders.
I had Misa relinquish ownership
of the Death Note.
Before she lost all her memories
of the notebook,
she sent it to someone else,
along with some special instructions.
Now she won't be able to answer
any questions about it.
She's just an ordinary woman.
The main problem was selecting
the next owner.
I saw him trying to speak to Kira
through the television broadcasts.
It was clear he worshipped Kira...
KIRA'S KINGDOM VIEWER SURVEY
DO YOU WANT TO PARTICIPATE
IN THE NEXT SHOW? YES
...from the bottom of his heart.
He would understand that he was chosen
simply by receiving
and accepting the notebook.
SEX: MALE
BIRTHDATE: JUNE 7, 1982, AGE: 27
OCCUPATION: PROSECUTOR
There was no mistake in my selection.
NAME: TERU MIKAMI, YEAR OF BIRTH: 1982
RESIDENCE: KYOTO PREFECTURE
Teru Mikami, he's more than worthy
of becoming the hand of Kira.
[Mikami] Shinigami, thank you
for coming to me.
Now, I'll be able to punish evildoers
with death.
WHAT IS KIRA TO YOU?
[Mikami chuckles] God.
TO BE CONTINUED
[theme music plays]