Within the spreading darkness
I pledged a vow to the revolution
I can't let anybody interrupt it
I'm going to change
The future that
the forbidden fruit foretells...
I'm going to change
The dream into reality
The ending
That everybody wants
Within the spreading darkness
I pledged our vow to the revolution
I can't let anybody interrupt it
Someday I'll show you
A bright and ideal
World
TACTICS
DECEMBER 20, 11:50AM
Hey...
Yes?
I'm actually here in Japan on
a secret investigation.
If the Japanese police were to...
I understand.
I won't tell anyone that I met you.
Including my father...
Please excuse me...
It's just as I thought.
I also don't want the police
to know
that I've come into contact
with an FBI agent.
If my father ever found out,
he'd tell L.
Raye doesn't suspect me at all...
The police will deal with
what happened just now
as a regular accident.
Welcome back.
Good to be back.
What's the matter?
Why the big sigh?
Raye... What happened?
I got mixed up in a bus jacking.
A "bus-jacking"?
A man who robbed a bank
two days ago tried to hijack a bus.
Japan has become a scary place.
Does that mean you were
also riding on that bus?
Yeah.
In the end, the suspect jumped
out of the bus and was hit by a car.
Did the suspect die?
Yeah. Probably...
I didn't have any time to
watch what happened.
Raye...
Do you really think
that was an accident?
What do you mean?
Well, you were on that bus
because you were investigating
someone, weren't you?
The criminal probably died...
Doesn't that mean...
Hey, you were indeed once
a brilliant FBI agent.
But now you're my fiancée.
You're no longer an agent.
Don't say anything about
the Kira case.
Don't get involved or take risks.
That's what we agreed on
when I brought you with me here
so we could meet your parents.
I understand, Raye.
It's just a force of habit.
Sorry.
No, I'm sorry.
Don't worry about it.
Once we have a family,
you'll be so busy that
you'll forget that you were an agent.
You won't have time
for that habit to come out.
Instead, help me think of something that
will make that father of yours like me more.
Oh...
Are you going to write down
the name of the agent now?
No. I'm going to write his name
a week from today.
If he dies right after I meet him,
I'll look suspicious.
It would be better to do it
once they've investigated
more people involved with the police.
For now, I'll use some
more inmates to toy with L.
L.
There is another dying
message left by a victim.
Please send an image to me.
Gods of Death...
"L, do you know? Gods of Death."
Does he want to say
that Gods of Death exist?
Watari.
Tell the police to keep
watch on the prison.
There may be someone else
who will leave a message.
I understand.
DECEMBER 27, 3:00PM
There sure are a lot of humans...
Are you going to do it here?
I'll show you what I've learned
from all of the experiments and research
I've done in the past few days...
"Experiments"?
Yes.
I've been testing different killing
methods on the criminals in this area...
ACCIDENTAL DEATH DECEMBER 26, 8:30PM
DIES AFTER GETTING HIT BY A CAR.
First, I write the cause of death
and the circumstances in the Death Note...
Then, when I write a name
in afterwards, it becomes true.
SHO HANEKURODA
That's something even I didn't know...
He's here...
Right on time...
Mr. Raye Penber.
I'll kill you if you turn around.
I am Kira.
If you turn around or
put your hand in your pocket,
I Will kill you.
I-It couldn't be...
But this voice...
I've heard it somewhere...
I shall first prove to
you that I am Kira.
I'll kill the man
with the glasses...
working at the coffee shop
you are looking at.
T-That's impossible!
Don't do it!
I had no choice.
I thought that if I didn't kill
at least one person,
you wouldn't believe me.
That man has been repeatedly
accused of sexual assault,
but the police have never convicted
him due to lack of evidence.
He was a menace and
deserved to be punished.
You may already have
heard from L,
that I cannot kill someone
unless I know his face.
I could kill everyone you see here.
If you have any requests,
I'll do it.
D-Don't do it.
I believe that you're Kira...
Of course, you care more about
your loved ones more
than the people here, don't you?
Consider them hostages.
Y-You know about her?!
That's right.
I've been studying you.
I will kill everyone,
including your family if
you don't do exactly as I say.
You included, of course.
L-| understand.
What do you want me to do?
You have a computer
with you, don't you?
Is there a file on the agents
who've come to Japan?
My laptop is for work. I always
carry it around with me.
But those files aren't in it.
Then take this envelope.
First, take out the transceiver
and put on the earphone.
A transceiver...
It's almost like a toy...
But this won't leave
a transmission record anywhere
and we can converse at
close distances even underground.
He's thought this out.
Please take the Yamanote Line.
It doesn't matter if you take
the inner circle or outer circle.
SHIBUYA - SHINAGAWA
Even while you're on the train,
keep your eyes fon/vard...
...focused on one spot.
Don't forget, I can kill at any time.
Once you're on the train,
sit in the corner closest t0 the door.
If it's taken, wait until it's free.
First, I must tell you something.
If your answer differs significantly
from what I expect,
I will kill your girlfriend.
Of the FBI agents who have
come to Japan,
how many are there and
how are they organized?
Please answer
into the transceiver.
I've heard it's f-four teams...
a total of twelve people...
Next, take out what's in the envelope.
What. . .is this?
Of those investigators...
Write the name of the agent
who is directly in charge of you all...
in the space at the top.
What is the meaning of this?
What is he planning?
But I have to do as he says.
He shouldn't be able to kill
with just names alone...
Next, open your laptop.
You should be receiving
a file from your superior soon.
A file of all the names and faces
of the FBI agents who came to Japan.
T-This is... What's going on?
Now, like you just did,
take a good look at each agent's face as
you write their names on the envelope.
I don't understand.
What is Kira trying to do?
What is he doing?
It seems like you're done.
Now put the transceiver and
envelope with the names on it
back into their original envelope
and put them on the rack.
Now put your hands on your lap
and continue riding the train
without making any movements for
about thirty minutes.
When you are sure that
nobody has noticed
that you have forgotten the envelope...
get off of the train.
Why? Why can't I remember
that voice?
Kira...
Who are you?
Light... Yagami...
Farewell, Raye Penber.
Raye Penber wrote those names
on pages taken from the Death Note.
He unwittingly killed
all of his colleagues.
Penber's superior died after sending him
the file on all of the agents.
HEART ATTACK AFTER SENDING THE FILES ON THE FBI
AGENTS VVHO CAME TC) JAPAN TC) INVESTIGATE KIRA.
The rest of the agents all died
of heart attacks
after the file was received.
L... We have a call
from the Director of the FBI.
It's me...
I've just got word
from Japan that
all of our agents have died.
They all died of heart attacks.
I can only think that
Kira killed them.
L, I'm very sorry, but...
The FBI will call off
our investigation in Japan.
It's from Chief Yagami.
L, I've just spoken with
the FBI Director.
According to him,
you were investigating everyone here
involved with the task force.
Yes.
What is the meaning of this?
Are you saying that you suspect us?
I decided that it was necessary
to learn Kira's identity.
I cannot condone this.
I cannot believe
that you would spy...
on your colleagues...
We can't trust L...
Besides, Kira killed
those FBI agents, right?
Even if they're not criminals,
he'll kill anyone who
stands in his way!
Kira's really just a murderer!
L. Another victim has
left a message.
L, do you know? Gods of Death...
love apples...
Damn you, Kira!
Raye's. . .dead...
No, he was killed by Kira...
What? A family meeting?
Even if I kept it secret,
you'd find out sooner or later.
So I'm going to tell you now.
I am currently in charge of
conducting the Kira investigation.
No way!
Dad, you really are amazing.
That isn't what I wanted to say.
Yesterday...
twelve FBI agents,
sent to Japan to find Kira, died.
Does that mean that
they were killed by Kira?
What?!
It means Kira might kill anyone
who tries to apprehend him...
It's a cold
and ruthless crime
more fearsome than anything
we've encountered before.
Many of my officers have quit.
Dad, you should quit too!
I don't want you to die!
She's right. You should place
your life before your job.
No. I will not remove myself
from this case.
I will not yield to evil.
Dad...
Dear...
Dad, that's admirable.
I'm proud of you.
If anything ever happens to you,
I'll see that
Kira gets executed.
Kira will probably kill all who
oppose him,
even if they're not criminals.
We may all be killed by Kira...
Think of your lives,
your families, and friends.
If anyone wants to be removed
from this investigation, please resign.
If you resign,
you will not be demoted.
I promise you.
I want those with the confidence
to stay on the case to fight Kira,
even if going after him means
sacrificing everything.
That is all.
Hey...
What are you going to do?
Yeah...
Yeah, right, that's him.
I remember him because
he said, "Get down."
But I don't really remember
the other passengers...
I see.
I understand.
Thank you very much.
If what I'm thinking is correct,
Kira could have been
among those passengers...
If that's so, I can find Kira
along the path this bus takes.
SERIAL MURDER
SPECIAL INVESTIGATIONS HQ
Only five people, huh?
Six including myself.
No, I should say as many as five
of you are willing to risk your lives.
I trust all of you who have
a strong sense of justice.
W-Wait just a moment.
I says he trusts us, but...
We don't trust L.
L, we have decided to
risk our lives to catch Kira.
You should know what
we mean by that.
But you never show your face
and just order us around...
We cannot work with
someone like that!
L.
If you want to work with us
and want to catch Kira...
Would it be possible for
you to come here?
Earlier, I said that I trust you all.
PLEASE KEEP WHAT IS ABOUT TO HAPPEN
A SECRET BETWEEN THE EIGHT OF US.
I WOULD LIKE TO MEET THE SIX OF YOU,
WHOM I TRUST AS SOON AS POSSIBLE
BEFORE THAT, I WANT YOU ALL TO GO
OUTSIDE OF THE POLICE BUILDING
AND DECIDE ONCE MORE
IF YOU TRUST ME OR NOT.
NATIONAL POLICE AGENCY AND
NATIONAL PUBLIC SAFETY COMMISSION
Why does he suddenly
want to work with just the six of us?
If he's solved numerous difficult
cases by himself,
he should do the same
this time, too.
And judging by the way that L
has been conducting the investigation,
he'll probably send a double
to meet us.
A double, huh? It's possible...
I-| trust L.
I also think we need L's help
in this case.
Me too...
I said from the beginning that...
he needed the police's help
in this case.
Perhaps you could
think of it like this.
I was waiting
for this to happen.
For what to happen?
There were people
in the investigation
who distrusted L
from the beginning.
Then we had detectives
continuously resign...
and confidential information
was leaked.
You can't run an investigation
unless you trust your partners.
In other words, L was waiting
for the task force
to get down to the people he can trust
and who will face evil
without fear.
Yes.
I'll resign rather than
join up with L.
Don't worry.
I won't trail you and
try to find L.
I trust L and will try
to cooperate with him.
Me too...
I am currently in a room
at the 719/70 Hotel.
I shall be switching hotels from
now on every few days.
From now on, I want you to
think of these rooms as...
the de facto HQ of
the investigation.
If you can agree to these terms...
I want you t0 split into two groups,
with a 30-minute interval between you,
and come here by...
twelve o'clock midnight.
Kira, we're even in how far we've
closed the distance between us.
Fine.
I'll show myself to others as L
for the first time.
If you manage to find out
about this, you'll definitely move in closer.
Bring it on.
I did a lot these past few days.
Think.
Was there something that I missed?
And. . .what is my next move?
L, the real battle starts now.
Please come in.
TO BE CONTINUED
I dreamed a dream
that no one could see,
I threw away everything
that I didn't need
I'm holding these feelings
That I can't give up in my heart
Even if my feet fall victim
to the shackles of sacrifice
In between reality and my ideal
I can't hold back
the flooding impulses
Because I have a strong desire
To accomplish
[deceit] [fear] [vanity] [melancholy]
I'm not weak enough to believe
Any of these negative perceptions
I'm a trickster
who doesn't know solitude
PREVIEW
if this woman had told the police
all this before she told me...
This Shinigami may not be on my side,
but it looks like another god is.
NEXT EPISODE: UNRAVELING